So in the last lecture, we set up our project and we add bootstrap to it,
now I want to get started adding the components we laid out here.
Here's your challenge,
try doing this on your own,
now with that I don't mean filling these component templates with life, for now each component may
simply hold some dummy text so that we can see that it's there,
I mean create the components and try to create a clever folder structure in your app folder. Not every
component should have a folder on the root level,
you should also nest them by feature maybe and try to create at least one component manually by hand,
not using the CLI.
I'll give you a chance to pause the video and then I will show you my approach,
chances are that we deviate in our solution
but that's a good practice for you,
so definitely go ahead and try creating these components without any content for init for now on your
own.
So were you successful?
Let's see how I would solve this, how I would approach this.
We got two main areas, recipes in the shopping-list and we get this header component.
Now I will create the header component manually.
So for this, we can already start the discussions, should we create a header folder in the app folder
where we store this component or should we create a component in the app folder itself?
Now I will create a header folder but placing the component directly in the app folder would also not be wrong
since it is really only used by our app component.
So here, I will create this new folder named header and in there, I'll add my header.component.ts
file.
Now as you learned, a component is simply just a TypeScript class, so
let's name it HeaderComponent here and right now, that would not be recognized as a component by
Angular,
instead here we have to add the @component decorator and later, I'm going to use the autoimport feature
of my IDE.
For now I'll import it manually, we have to import component between curly braces from @angular/core,
that's important.
Now with that, we need to pass a Javascript object to this decorator to configure this component,
specifically we need to add a template and I'll put this in external file, so templateUrl in this
case and a selector so that we can use this component. So the selector here is app-header because I want
to ensure that I have a unique selector and that I don't overwrite an existing HTML element for example
and header would be an existing element.
The templateUrl, here I want to point to the header.component.html file
and as you've probably recognized, this file doesn't exist.
So I can quickly create this by creating a new file in the same folder, in the header folder, here
header.component.html is the full file name and in this HTML file here,
I simply want to output the header for now,
I'm going to add some content soon.
So that's my header component and I can already include this in my app component,
maybe above the container because in the container, I later only want to contain my content component
I will say, so here I'll add the app-header, just like this.
So with that, we added it here,
now let's see if we can see it
and I just see loading... which always is an indicator that there has been an error.
So check the Javascript console in your developer tools to see the error and the error is pretty clear,
app-header is not a known element.
This is a common gotcha which is why I wanted to show it.
Why is it not known?
We added it here and we set up selector here, right?
Well remember, you have to register all the features you're going to use in the app module
and since we didn't use the CLI to create this component, it wasn't added there automatically.
So we have to add it manually to our declarations array
and that means we also have to add the import.
So we should import header component from and now pointing to the header folder and then in there,
the header.component file without the file extension.
So that now unlocks the header component in our app and if we save this, now we see the header.
Now that's not pretty,
we're going to change this soon but we can see that it is working.
Now, let's move on to adding all the other components with the CLI for now.
So we had a couple of components we wanted to add and I will use the ng generate command or just ng g as
a shortcut and then we want to generate a component
or just c as a shortcut and the first component I want to add is the recipes component for this recipes
feature area.
I'll add spec false to prevent the creation of a testing file which I don't need.
So with that, we get a new folder in our app folder, the recipes folder which holds our recipes component,
that is great.
Now this will be our overall recipes feature component and that actually is a component
I didn't sketch out here,
here we only have recipe-list item in detail.
Now you could also just work with these
but I want to create a set up where I have a list on the left let's say
and if I click an item, the detail component is displayed on the right,
so I will need an overall component holding both.
Now that is an optional set up,
you can also go with another one where the detail is somehow embedded into the list component,
I chose to create this overall component.
Now besides that, I will go ahead and create the other components though,
so besides recipes,
I will also now create the recipe-list component as laid out on the slides.
Now here, I don't want to create the recipe-list on the or inside the app folder though, which is the default
behavior by the CLI if
I now would hit enter, instead
that should go inside the recipes folder because that is where all the recipe related components should
go.
We can easily tell the CLI to create this component in a subfolder by basically passing a path here,
so instead of just saying recipe-list, we can say recipes/recipe-list and since you already have
the recipes folder, this will create the recipes-list folder inside of the recipes folder,
that is what I meant with structuring the folders by feature. Now with the recipe-list added, I also
want to add the recipe detail here because the recipe detail should be displayed next to the list in
my set up here, so I will add it to the recipes folder too,
so that now we also have the recipe detail folder here
and we also need the component for a single recipe-item, right,
so recipe-item.
However I don't want to add that to the recipes folder, that should go inside the recipe-list folder
because it's in the recipe-list where I want to also have that item,
so I'll point to the recipe-list subfolder here and now hit enter.
And now we get the component inside the recipe-list because again the recipe-item is just one item in
this list of recipes.
Now again, it's only one possible folder structure,
you could remove the recipes component and put the recipe-list component as the main recipe feature
component and add details somewhere in this component
then, I chose to have this set up here though.
Now let's move on to the shopping-list.
Well for this, I'll of course run ng g c again to generate a new component and I name it shopping-list,
I'll also add spec false here to prevent the creation of this testing file and this will give
me a shopping-list folder in my main app folder,
so next to recipes and header. Inside the shopping-list,
there's only one other component I want to create and that's the shopping-list edit component which
will allow us to add new ingredients or edit existing ones, that should now go into the shopping-list
component,
so just like before with recipes, I'll simply change this to shopping-list/shopping-edit and this
will now add it inside of this component.
So now we get all the components we need for now or at least I think we need for now,
of course feel free to choose a different set up but with all these components added and since you use
the CLI, they were also added automatically to app module.
If you did create them manually, make sure to add them here too.
So with all that created and added to app module, we can now use them.
So let's start using them in the next lecture and let's also start filling them with some life there.