In the last lecture we learned about local references.
Now there is also another way of getting access to local references or to any element actually directly
from within our typescript code.
Right now we're passing the reference here when we serve and we call a method and that works fine.
But sometimes you want to get access before we call the method and there is a nice old decorator we
can use in typescript to get this access.
Let's do the same 40 server content so we're able to quickly duplicate that input and comment outa old
solution using two way binding and the new solution will not use to where binding but instead this will
now also have a local reference these server content input maybe.
Now in the cockpit component I will also comment out the old new server content here and I will add
a new property which I'll name server content input now server content input like this is just a property
but we can add at view child in front of it.
This decorator with parentheses and we need to import view child from at angular core.
Now view child like this won't work.
We need to pass an argument here and this argument actually is.
Lecture or off to element how we want to select the element and select or now not like a CSX selector.
But for example we can simply pass as a string the name of a local reference so server content input
could now be passed as a string.
If you don't want to pass a string but want to select a component you could simply pass to component
type here.
So in the cockpit we don't use any other components but in the app component we could pass cockpit component
so to type like this not like a string to get access to the first occurrence of this cockpit component
in the app component.
But here I'll switch this back to getting access to the local reference which probably is the use case
you will see the most often.
And with that we now get access to our server content input.
Now what does this actually hold.
Then let's quickly comment out this codes that it doesn't break and let's log this server content input
so our property here which is kind of set through view child.
So with this if at all to comment this out down here so that we can run our app and if I now safe this
and we go back to our application and I enter something here and I click ad server we see that this
is of type element ref.
So unlike the local reference we pass directly from the template why the method which was the element
itself.
This is of type element ref so we can set this type here.
Element ref a reference to that element element ref needs to be imported from at the angular core it's
the angular type.
So this element ref however has a useful property we can use and that steam native element property
we can use server content loops.
This server content input here and then native element to get access to the underlying element which
now has a value because this will now be the input element.
Now we can do the same of course for the on app blueprint method.
And with this we get direct access to elements in our Dom in our template through at view child.
And you should see that this now works again if we Andrews am content here and collect the buttons works
perfectly.
Now without two way binding but with local references past two methods or local references fetched through
view child.
Now one important thing to watch out for is you should not change the element fruit is because of course
you could use our server content input the native element and then set value to something right.
You can't do this.
And if we actually do this like this and I click ads or a blueprint you see something was now added
here.
I strongly recommend not doing this.
You should not access to DRM like this angler offers you a better way of accessing the Dom and you will
learn about this in the directives section.
Generally you should use the other tools like string interpolation and property binding if you want
to output something in the DOM and not directly mess with any element.
You can get even though if you have gotten them through angular.