Before concluding this module one more thing related to our hooks here.
We learned about at Vue child which we can use here in the cockpit to get access to element from our
while Dom from our template.
Let's do the same here in the server element component HDMI follow where we have all these lifecycle
hooks.
Let's say I want to get access to this heading.
So I would simply place a local reference named heading on it therefore I'll add a new ad view child
property.
Make sure to import view child from angular core.
And with that added here all stored is in the header property which is of type element for F as we learned
which also needs to be imported from angular core.
And I want to select the heading local reference with a chest placed on this day of year.
So with that we get access to it and now we would expect that we can't use stairs before we reached
after view in it.
So let's try it and energy on in it.
Let me actually console log this
header and there the native element.
And now let's access something which is definitely a whale on a div and that is the text content if
we do this and I save this.
Let's view the console.
If I reload the application here you see this empty line here.
This is where I would have expected text content can make this even clearer by outputting text content
and then while rendering the text content if there were any there is no text content in here as you
can see an empty space.
If I copy the exact same code and placed as an after view in it here.
So after the view should have initialized now you will see that here when it's called the second time
after viewing it we see test server.
So that is the difference between Wilder points of time where these hooks run after view and it gives
you access to the Template elements.
You can then access them and use their values and so on before does Hook has been reached.
You can't do that you can't check the value of some element in your dorm because it hasn't been rendered
yet.