In the last lecture we learned that we have view child and how we can access it in our life cycle hooks
that there is one ever nice little addition in app component where we add our content which we then
project into our server element.
Let's say we also want to place a local reference on this paragraph.
So the content paragraph maybe.
But now we want to use that in our server element component which is where this content will end up
in the end.
Now in the app component which is where we currently placed us in the template we could use at The View
child because it's in the template of the app component even though it will be kind of passed on to
the server element component later.
Since we know that it will be there it would be nice if we could also access it from the server element
component.
But at the view child won't work because it's not part of the view.
It's part of the content which is why we also have separate hooks your content in it and view in it.
Great thing is we don't only have at view child.
We also have at content child which also needs to be imported from ad angular core.
There's not also allows us to pass a selector so the reference name content paragraph would be the selector
we chose here in the app component HDMI file and then just like with ET view child we get we can store
this in some property which will be of type element ref like this and now we can use it and just like
with view ref we of course can't access to value or anything before we reached content in it.
So that's something I just wanted to add at content child to get access to content which is stored in
another component but then passed on via energy content.
Now let me locked is and I will log it here and on in it to demonstrate that this is not there.
Here I will simply output text content of paragraph
whoops paragraph and access this paragraph native element text content and then I will copy this to
offer content in it.
Now once I save this reload the application you see that the first time we call it it's empty here after
on in it but there after an energy after content in it or after this has been called once this hook
has been called we see just a tests now it was initialized.
That is the missing piece.
Understanding how we can get access to elements in our dorm and how we can work with these lifecycle
hooks.