So were you successful, let's hold it together.
Let's start with the first task creating these components.
I'll use DCI for this.
So with energy GC, I'll trade my game control component with SPAC Falls to not get this testing file.
And then I will repeat this for my art component and then might even component here.
So just like that with dad, we should have free folders with new folders here and now, let's start
in the game control.
I'll keep this relatively simple here.
I will add two buttons where I say start game and also give to some bootstrap classes.
Button, button.
Let's make it button success to have a green button.
And then here I will say.
POS game on the second button, maybe let's make this off type button alert to make it a red button.
But the danger would be the right class, so if Dad, we have the two buttons in game control in component,
these were of course added to app module automatically since we used to seelie these components.
So an app component, I can now add them.
So I will simply do this here in a new div with a new with the real class here and then call X as well
as the width here.
I will add app game control.
Let's have a look at our running application and service already running.
That looks all right.
That is the behavior.
I want the console so that we could see any potential errors.
But that of course looks all right now.
When starting the game, we should emit an event.
So Indy game control component.
First of all, I need to add a click listener to start game and I will start or I will execute on start
game any method name you like here, of course.
And it will added to my component typescript code.
So you're in on start game.
I now want to set this interval and I will stored in property so that I can later access it and clear
it.
So I'll simply name it interval here.
And here and on start game, I will set this interval equal to set interval, as I said, a method supported
by native JavaScript.
And here I want to emit an event every thousand milliseconds, which would be one second.
And then the function here is a six arrow function again.
You could use a normal function, but then you would have to bind this to get the correct reference
to this.
So here I will use a S6 Arrow function.
This is the function which gets executed on each tick.
The function doesn't have any arguments, but here I want to emit an event.
Now this event needs to be created.
So at the top of this file, I'll add another property and I'll simply name interval fired any name
you like.
This will be a new oops new event emitter.
And keep in mind, event emitter needs to be imported from at angular core like that.
Now, this event emitter will in the end only hold a number as a values or why will set the generic
type here of this value of this generic type two number?
Don't forget the parentheses to instantiate this event so that you really get an instance of this object.
And with that, I can now call this interval fired and here emit and I want to emit, well, incrementing
number.
So maybe there are a couple of ways of implementing this.
I will simply store last number here and set this to zero initially.
And then I want to emit last number, this last number plus one.
Therefore the first emitted number will be one, and thereafter I will increment last number so that
I will simply have to keep track of what my last emitted number was.
So if that we should emit incrementing numbers, the next task is, of course, to make this listenable
from outside.
I can do this by adding ad output in front of it with parentheses and output needs to be imported from
at angular court.
Now this event can be caught from outside this component here.
So that is my own event now firing and I should be able to listen to it.
Integral Fired will be the event name since I didn't assign an alias here.
So in the app component, you're on app game control.
We can listen to this interval fired event and maybe execute on interval fired here.
Of course, you can choose a different name right here in on interval fire.
I will implement this method, an app component for now.
I simply want to log the last number so I will pass it on with Tollerson event.
Remember, dollar signing event gives us access to the event data, which is the number in this case.
So an app component.
I know that I will receive my.
Fired number or something like that, which is of type no, so I can simply output this year so that
if I saved this, we should have a working application, we should be able to click this button and
then on the right in the console, we should see incrementing numbers every second.
And that looks pretty good to me.
Paul, this game, of course, won't work for now.
So let's make it work by, well, implementing this post game button.
So you're all at a click listener to the post game button.
And I want to call on Paul's game here, of course.
So let's implement this method and game control component to and here I can simply call clear interval.
And now I need to pass this interval, which was the reference of my interview.
I want to clear.
So if we do this and reload the application, let's start a new timer.
And of course, we don't see any other values because interval is not firing any more.
No new events are emitted.
Of course, if we restart, we continue at free because our last number wasn't overwritten.
You could do this, but I don't want to do that.
I don't want to reset the game state.
I simply want to pause and resume here.
So this is working now, we need to implement the other components odd and even we already got them
here, odd and even and in there and odd here.
I want to output a paragraph, let's say, where I say art dash and then the number which I output via
string interpolation.
Now, of course, number is a property which doesn't exist right now.
So I'll add a property number, which will be type number, but it's not initialized.
Now, again, this should be passed from outside.
So as you learned it, we have to add at input here with parentheses and importing this from add angular
court.
With that, we're now able to pass the data from outside into this component.
So with that number can be set from outside.
So in the app component HTML file, we probably want to add something below our game control here,
maybe a new row, but without the app game control component instead with the app or component here.
And we will use energy for to replicate this though we don't have an array right now, we have to create
this array in the app component typescript file.
Right now we're logging any fired number.
What we should do something else we should have an array of numbers would be a fitting name and odd
numbers is simply an empty array at the beginning, but can even be clear about which type it will hold.
The type will simply be an array of numbers that would be type definition.
Now, I'm going to duplicate this because we're also going to have even numbers now in on Intervale
Fired, I want to check if the fired number, if it is odd or even now we can check those with modulus
operator if fired number.
And the percentage sign is demarches operator divided by two.
If what remains here.
Whoops, here equals zero.
Well, then we know it's even so, then we should use our even numbers and pushed and you fired a number
on it.
Otherwise, we know there is something left over from this division, so it is an odd number, so it
pushes you, we should push it to odd numbers.
So now we're managing these arrays and with odd numbers, getting items which are odd numbers, which
are odd in up component here in NJ for I can now loop through them.
So odd number of odd numbers.
So looping through this array, I can now pass this to my art component because remember there we exposed
the no input here so I can point to number.
You could of course also choose a different name or assign an alias as you learned it.
And I want to pass my odd number there.
So the number I'm currently at in this iteration, let's try this.
We don't have even numbers yet, but let's see if our numbers work, if we start the game.
We indeed scored one, three, five and so on.
So this is working, this is working as expected.
If we pause, we shouldn't see any other numbers.
Now, let's do the same for even so, for even, I will basically just copy the template code from the
art component, replace even odd with even, of course, and well, here in the even component itself,
at a time file, I will all receive a number which will you have type number and where I have to add
at input with parentheses to make it bendable from outside.
So now just like with on the art component, I can do the same with the even component and bind no from
my parent component, which in this case is the app component HTML5 excuse me, or the app component
in general.
So I'm going to duplicate app art and replace it with app even.
Of course here I want to loop through my even number, so even numbers.
So I'll store it in a temporary variable named even number of even numbers.
Let's pass to even number here.
And with that we should now lock both with art and even in front of it.
Let's see if it reloads and I click start game.
Odd, even odd and even and the behavior you see here that is kind of is below each other.
Well, that simply happens because that is how we placed on an even odd numbers will always be sorted
to the top here.
You would have to manage all in one component to have them alternate.
But that is exactly behavior I want here in this case.
So this structuring where we first have all the odd and that the even numbers with that, the remaining
pieces to change the styling.
Now both templates look pretty much the same.
We have a paragraph in both of them.
So for all the why don't we start this paragraph to be blue, have a blue color, blue text color,
and for even maybe we could choose green.
And since we use style encapsulation here, even though we use the paragraph selector in both cases,
each component will only receive the style set up in the respective stylesheet.
So if we do this and start the game one more time, we see all this blue and even as green.
So style encapsulation is also working fine here and you really see the difference.
So that was our assignment.
I hope you enjoyed it.
And with that, let's move on and dive deeper into components.