We added a lot of functionality in this core section.
Our recipe book is really taking shape.
Now of course there are also some features we haven't added yet which we will add later.
For now I want to make this shopping list input fields here are working so that we can add new items
to our shopping list.
We will overwrite this later when we learned about forums but it's a great exercise to work with local
references and at view child.
For now so what I want to do is I want to work on this shopping list added component here.
Here we got a couple of input fields and we get the Add button which submits our form later delete and
clear.
Now I want to allow the user to add new items.
So what I'll do is I will restructure both inputs to use multiple lines simply to make it easy to read
and understand.
And on the first input for the name I will add a local reference named name input on the second one
I'll add one named amount input.
Now with that setup your challenge would be to get this Add button to kind of use these local references
preferably by either passing them as an argument or more advanced by selecting them with at view child
so that once you click the button you use the values of these inputs to create a new ingredient and
add it to your array of ingredients.
Here is your chance to posit a value and try this on your own.
Then we'll do this together
so where are you successful.
Let's do it together.
We already have our local references here.
So all I have to do for now is add a click listener and a name ID on ADD item and I could pass the local
references or even already local reference store to value here as arguments I will use to add view child
approach though.
So in the shopping list added component all add to on at item method and then at the top I'll add two
properties the name input reference and that will be of type element ref.
As we learned.
Make sure to import this from at angular core.
And it will get a value by using at view child which also needs to be imported from at angular core.
And here we pass the name of the local reference so name input for this first input field.
Well now I'm going to duplicate this and simply renamed as to amount input and amount input ref.
That's the local reference we put on the second input here and with these two inputs added in on ADD
item I now want to emit a new event where I pass this data to the parent component which is the shopping
list component which manages my array of ingredients.
So we learned how to admit our own events so quickly go through that again.
Here I'll name it ingredient added which will be a new event emitter.
Of course you could choose another name for your event.
I will pass an object here as an argument which will hold the name which will be a string and the amount
which will be a number.
And Dad you're also close to parentheses.
Dad here is simply just a type definition.
So that type will be a javascript object with two properties name and a mound where the first property
name is a string and the second one is a number.
So that's not a value.
That's just the type definition.
Now of course for this exact type definition we get our ingredient model so we can replace live this
with just ingredient.
Make sure to import ingredient from the shared folder and then the ingredient thought model file though.
Well and with this and on ADD item we can create a new ingredient here with the new keyword and then
ingredient and we simply passed a name input ref native element value here and that will simply be the
value of the input element and the same for the amount.
But since this is really long Ultra Q new temporary constants so to say or constants to make this code
a bit shorter.
So the ingredient name will be retrieved from the name input reference from the native element which
is the input element and then from the value field and the same for the ingredient amount here.
I will simply get this from the amount input ref and with these two constants here I will simply pass
I N G name and i n g amount here.
So I will create my new ingredient with that data.
Important the constants here are used or I use constant instead of let because we're not going to change
these variables but they won't be variables anymore than as well we only assign these values one time
and you should declare something as a constant.
If you don't plan on changing it so with this I can now admit my own event here and past in new ingredient
data.
Well and with this all we have to do is we have to add at output in front of our own event here so that
we can listen to it from outside.
Make sure to import output from angular core and now in our shopping list component which implements
your shopping added component.
We can listen to our ingredient added event here and there.
I want to execute on ingredient added and we will get some data which is always stored in dollars an
event which I want to pass to my on ingredient added method.
Let's implement this method here.
So on ingredient added I know I will receive an ingredient here of type ingredient that is what our
event emits the data we set up there and now we can reach out to our ingredients array and push a new
ingredient.
The one we got here is data on it.
And with that we should be able to indeed add some whips here add some bread to it.
One click add and you see it on the list.
So we got a half way working shopping list.
Of course the lead and clear is not working we also can select items here.
That is something I'll work on later once we learned more about forms which give us some nice tools
to manage them.
But we greatly enhanced our app in this section.
We added some kind of working navigation.
We are able to select a recipe here and we are able to add new items to the shopping list already.
Even though some of these behaviors will get overwritten later in the course it still is a great start.
Now let's move on and learn more about directives so that next time we come back to this project we
can make our dropdown buttons here work.
See you there.