In the last lecture we learned about this hierarchical injector and that we can choose between one instance
or multiple instances of the same service class.
I mentioned at the highest possible level.
It's actually not the app component.
So let's remove it here.
This provider's array leave it in the constructor and leave the import but the highest possible level
is in the app module.
Here we also have a provider's array added.
If you don't have it and here we can also provide the accounts service.
Make sure to also add to import at the top here.
Then with that little addition heater we're making sure that our whole application everything in our
application receives the same instance of the service unless it overrides it as we did before.
Now with that we can now even inject a service into another service because that's not possible by providing
it on a component level for that we need to provide it in the app module so let's say we want to log
something if we call actually in the account service.
So it would have to provide a logging service in my app module now and therefore I will simply comment
out providers here and why add component decorators and I don't want to call logging service here anymore
so will comment this out and I will actually leave the injection here so that you have it for reference
if you download the code.
I'll also comment it out here in you account component instead.
Let's say I want to use this logging service and the account service and I want to call the log status
change method there because this isn't the end the place where the status changes even because we added
a new account or because we called update status so to use the service there.
Generally we start in the same way we add a constructor and we checked our logging service in this case
set the type import.
This type at the top make sure to add to import and we provided it an app module so you could think
that we are set to go that we can now go to add account coal logging service log the status change paths
to status here and do the same year for update status.
You could think this is how we do it.
And it's not a logical to think so but let's see if this works if we load our app we already get an
error cannot resolve all parameters for account service.
Something's not working.
The reason is if you inject a service into something this something needs to have some metadata attached
to it.
Now a component has some metadata because we have at component a directive has some metadata because
we have at directive account or excuse me a service doesn't have any metadata.
It's just how Angela works that we need to attach some metadata.
And of course not any metadata.
You shouldn't attach at components here.
There is a specific metadata you should attach in such cases.
It's at injectable which needs to be imported from at angular core.
This tail's annual are dead now this service is is injectable or that something can be injected in there
to be precise.
So that's important.
You don't add at injectable to the service you want to inject but to the service very you want to inject
something.
So the receiving service you could say that to be injected in service and you don't need to add it to
any other service if you don't want to inject anything in the service like here for the logging service.
You don't need to add add injectable only added If you expect to get something injected.
Now one important note here as I explained we don't need to add injectable the injectable decorator
here to this class because this is a service which we only inject somewhere else but where we don't
inject anything into this service and you technically really only need injectable if you inject something
into this service.
Not if you just inject this service somewhere else in newer wordings of angular however it is recommended
that you always add at injectable it's technically makes no difference right now in the future it might
though.
So it's already a habit you might get into that you added here.
I do admit it but you could consider adding it also to ensure that in the future it doesn't unexpectedly
break.
What I explained about why you need it and that you don't need it here technically still holds though
with this if I now safeties and we let the app reload now it works.
And now you see that if I save this we still log it to the console with the correct status the same
happens if I click here.
But now everything is centralized into our service and now we're also injecting a service into a service.