So were you successful, here's my solution.
Our creators, users service as we are asked to and in there we, of course export a class to users
service.
We don't need to add at injectable right now because right now we're not injecting a service in there
and here.
And I want to manage my users.
No, you could create one area of users and their store objects, which for each object, it also tracks
the state of the user.
I would go with two areas, so I will have my act for my inactive users to to erase from the app component.
So I'll copy it from there and paste it into my user's service.
But again, as an improvement, you could store objects in one single area there, which then allows
you to switch to status for each object, for each user.
So this is this.
And then I want to add a set to active method here.
I expect to get the idea of the elements should switch and are set to enact the method in here.
Of course, also, you could optimize this by having one method which does Bovon, which receives an
additional argument, which determines whether you want to switch active to inactive or the other way
around.
Well, in set to active, I want to reach out to my active users and push a new element to them.
That new element is in my inactive users, the user with the idea of receiving there and thereafter
I can simply splice that user splice will simply remove this one element in this case here.
Well, now I can copy that code pasted in here and reverse it, push it to the inactive users from the
active users and splice it from the active users.
Now this service is prepared and now in my app component, I can get rid of these two methods.
I also can delete my users here so we can completely clean this component and we can clean everything
in the template of the app component.
We don't need to parse the properties to our components there because these components can reach out
to the service on their own.
Now it is important to make sure that we provide the service on the right level.
If we were provided in the inactive user component and the active user component, we would have two
different instances of that service and therefore it would not work.
We could not switch because we would work with two different arrays.
So with four different arrays actually.
So therefore, this is not the right place to provide it.
We could provide it here in the app component or in the app module.
Now, since we don't plan on injecting this service in another service or something like this, there
is no reason to provide it.
Application wide, though.
You could do that.
That's not wrong.
Not bad, but I will simply provided here in the app component.
But again, just to highlight this, it's not bad or wrong to provide it in the app module.
So here I will provide my users service, make sure to also add the import with that provided on this
level, active users and inactive users will actually share the same service, the same instance of
that service.
So now I can go to inactive users, add a constructor here and get my users service here.
So of type users service, of course.
User service is your name actually.
Make sure to add the import here, too, you always need to add this, that's a typescript feature not
related to ANGULAR, and then I can remove the input here.
We're not receiving it from outside anymore.
I can remove my whole output, my whole event here, and also remove this very limited remove all these
imports.
They're for it.
And now I want to initialize my user's array.
I will do it and on in it as again, it is a good practice to do initialization work in there.
So let's implement on init make sure to import it and then we need to add the energy on init method.
And then there I can set my users equal to the users I fetch from my user service and we're in the inactive
component here, so I should get my inactive users.
Now with that I can simply copy that code over to the active users, replace my input and my output
here too, and remove the input string, remove all these imports, but on the other hand, make sure
to import user service and implement on in it.
So just like any other component, make sure to import on in it too and import the servers.
And here we don't have to admit this event anymore.
Instead, make sure that now users is not the inactive users, but the active users somewhere in the
active users component.
And if we click on Set to Inactive, I want to reach out to the user service and call set to inactive
and pass on this ID.
And on the other hand, in the inactive service, I want to do the same.
Reach out to the users service and your call set to active and pass the ID.
That should be all.
Let's see if this works, if our app here is loaded.
I can still switch my users around, so does the first part does work, but boy, is it leaner, much
less passing around, instead having a clean central service.
Now, the other part of the task was to add discounters service.
So let's add this to the counter service statistics file.
Let's export a class here, the counter service like this.
And here I simply want to manage my active to inactive calendar, which starts at zero.
And while you guessed it inactive to active calendar, which also starts at zero.
And now I simply want to add two methods.
Where I say incremented active to inactive, of course, you can choose another name, and here I will
simply say active to inactive counter plus plus and Lockton you counter so the active to inactive counter.
And then I will just duplicate this to also have my inactive to active counter where I increase the
inactive to active counter property and lock the inactive to active counter property.
You probably dream about inactive too active tonight, but this is our counter service now here you
could add it in multiple places, you could add it here in the onset to active or the onset to inactive
methods.
That would be all right.
But I want to add it here in my user service.
So I want to inject that into a service.
And for this, we have to take two things into account.
First of all, we have to make sure that we provide the counter service here in the app module.
So counter service, make sure to at the airport here to now it's available application wide and therefore
can also be injected into our services segment to inject a service into a service.
What would you need to do?
You need to add at injectable to the service.
Where you want to inject that in, right, so to the users service here, not to counter service to
users, service to the receiving service.
So here I will add at injectable, don't forget the parentheses.
That's a common mistake and deport.
And with that, I can now inject the counter service in the users service.
So here counter.
Lips counter, a service of type counter service, make sure to import this type here at the top to.
And with that and check that here in set to act, if I can call this counter service, and since we
said something to active, I want to call the increment inactive to active because we set something
from inactive to active.
And on the other hand, and is set to inactive.
I want to incremented well, active to inactive.
So this one here.
With that, if we now safeties and let our app reload and I click to Set to inactive, we see that as
one, maybe improve the output here that we say.
Active to inactive, and then we output the number and on the other hand, down here.
We have.
Inactive, too active.
So now let's just reload.
Active to inactive one, two, and now we should add forward to the inactive to active side and some
to the active to inactive.
So this is working.
Everything seems to work as intended.
This is my solution.
Of course, you might have a different solution.
There are different ways of achieving the same.
Overall, you should feel confident using services now.
You should see their benefits and how you might use them in your next project.
Let's move on.