Almost done, we covered a lot in this module.
This has been a very long section in this course but it has been so important because routing is such a
key task in any application.
Now if you have a look at our application, we get a couple of routes in there, /users, /servers
and much more.
Now here's one important thing,
it works fine here on our local setup but actually, this is not something you should take for granted.
If you have a route like this, your domain/servers and you're hosting this on a real server somewhere
in the web, this might not work out of the box because there, routes, the URL is always, this is how the
web works, is always parsed handled by the server first, so by that server which hosts your application.
Now here on the local environment in our development environment, we're also using a development server
but this server has one special configuration
your real life server also has to have and I will come back to this this in the deployment section. The
server hosting your Angular single page application has to be configured such that in a case of a
404 error,
it returns the index.html file, so the file starting and containing your Angular app.
Why?
Because as I mentioned, all your URLs are parsed by the server first,
so not by Angular, by the server.
Now if you have /servers here, it will look for a /servers route on your server,
on the real server hosting your web app. Now chances are you don't have that route here because you only
have one file there, index.html containing your Angular app and you want Angular to take over and
to parse this route
but it will never get a chance
if your server, the server hosting your app decides no, I don't know the route,
here's your 404 error page.
Therefore you need to make sure that in such a case, your web server returns the index.html file.
If for some reason, you can't get this to work or you need to support very old browsers which are
not able to parse paths like this in the client which Angular does
then, you have an alternative approach to using this
nice
URLs which look like all the URLs in the web. You can fallback to our older technique which was
used a couple of years ago, using a hash sign in your routes.
Let's see how we enable it
and then I will explain what it does.
You can enable it in your app-routing.module where you register your routes,
here with the forRoot method. You can pass a second argument, a Javascript object to this method
configuring the set up of the routes.
So besides the routes itself,
now we can configure them
and one important configuration is the useHash configuration which you can set to true,
the default is false which is why we didn't have to pass it.
If we do this and we save that, let's see what happens.
You out of the box see that now we have this hashtag in our URL and if I click on servers,
you see there is this hashtag in between and that's no bug, that belongs here because this is hash
mode routing.
What this hashtag will do is, it informs your web server,
hey only care about the part in this URL
before this hashtag,
so all the parts thereafter will be ignored by your web server.
Therefore this will run even on servers which don't return the index.html file in case of 404 errors
because they will only care about the part in front of the hashtag.
That's how it works
by default and the part after the hashtag can now be parsed by your client, by Angular.
So this is the solution
if you can't get the other approach to work, however I will say that definitely you should try to use
the more prettier routes, using the HTML history mode as it is called with the normal slash routes without
the hashtag.
So this is how you would enable it,
I'm going to duplicate this so to comment this out, to have it there for reference but I will fallback
to the other mode which gives us cleaner routes which really look a lot nicer and more like you're used
to seeing routes from other web apps.
And this is the last piece of the section.