Were you successful with that form, let's build it together, as in the template driven assignment?
I will do it right below the instructions here and I will start by adding the form element here.
And generally I will start by creating it in my HTML code here, though, that will not create the form
for ANGULAR because we will later set it up in TypeScript and then connect it to our template code here.
So as before I'll add a form group div with a label for the name.
So project name would be a fitting description and I'll add an input type text.
Sounds all right.
I'd name sounds all right.
I'll split it up over multiple lines already since we're going to add some things and add a class of
foreign control.
This is the first input.
I'm going to duplicate this because now I want to add the email.
Email of the person who created this project, you could say so let's simply set up the male input here,
make it of type email maybe.
And I want to add that dropdown, so let's add another form group and in there select dropdown.
We don't need the name actually we need a label though, where we set the status.
So project status would be a fitting description, I guess, set the idea to status, therefore.
And in the select, we need our options now.
You could use an array to dynamically populate them or hardcoded them in there.
I will go with the hardcoded approach here, though.
You will typically probably have the dynamic one.
The first value would be, as you see up here.
Stable.
So say stable here and there after we also have critical with a display value of critical and finished
where we display finished.
So this would be our dropdown.
I also want to add the foreign control clause to that and split it over multiple lines.
Then I'll add the button at the end of the forum with to Puttnam Button primary, make it of type,
submit and simply say create project maybe to mix it up.
So does the general set up engy service already running.
Looks all right to me.
Stablest selected by default because it's the first element we added here.
Now let's create this form in TypeScript.
So in my app component here I'll name it project for and it will be of type form group.
Make sure to import this from angular forms.
What else did we learn.
We need to unlock all the react the form directives by going to app module and we don't need forms module,
we need reactive forms module.
So make sure to import that from add angular forms and add it to the imports array here.
With that added, we will later be able to synchronize it for now.
Let's create this form and I'll again do this in energy on in it.
So I'll add the on init lifecycle hook and imported from add angular core and geon in it gets added
here and then I will set my project form equal to a new form group because again the outer form is just
the form group.
Where I will pass a JavaScript object, you configure it now here I want to have, let's say, a project
name control, so a new form control, therefore with a default value of null.
I don't want to pre populated and for now I will only add the validator.
Which requires it to be not empty.
Make sure to import validators from at angular forums, because that's the first requirement.
It should not be empty now for mail.
I'm going to duplicate this and set up my email control.
It's also null, but it has more than one validator.
It does have the required validator, but then it has the email validator.
Again, don't execute these methods.
You only want to pass the reference to the methods.
Well, the final control is this dropdown here with stable, acritical and finished.
So I'll add yet another control.
Now, here, I will name this project status for control.
Here I will set a different default value.
It would make sense to have stablest default value, but that's selected automatically.
I want to change this so I will set a two critical desisted value we need to sign with a lowercase C
at the beginning because that's the behind the scenes value HTML knows.
So let's pass a string with critical here and well we don't need any validators because we can't unselected
anyways.
This is our form.
Of course.
Feel free to also Nestor's to add a form group if you want.
This would be an extra challenge.
Now this is the basic setup where all this on the same level in this forum with this form created,
we need to synchronize it with our HTML code again, just because it's important for this, you will
need react the forms module and then I can go to my form here and with property binding bind form group.
To my project forum, to this forum we just created.
Now let's also connect the inputs like here with foreign control name, of course, to tell Aneela which
name does our control have in a forum and our forum here, it's project name for this first input.
So I'll past this year for the email.
It will just be email.
And for to drop down, if we have a look at our tax code, it was project status, so I will pass project
status here.
Now our forum is connected.
I will now also add energy, submit to submit it.
And called on Save Project maybe and create this method now in my typescript file here and the app component
types could file and here I simply want to log this project for and value because I'm only interested
in disvalue.
So energy service still running as mentioned before, it's recompiling.
Just looks good.
No errors.
Let's enter something here and lets it create a project and we see the value looks good.
Looks like we successfully connected it.
Now if we have a look at our instructions here in the HTML code, we finished this part, we created
the form, we added the controls and we set up this basic validation.
Now we are required to create our own validator, which doesn't allow test as a project name.
Well, we saw how to do this and we could do this here in the same file as we did before.
But to mix it up and show you that you can also create your own validators bundle kind of I will create
a new file here in my app folder and I will name it Custom Validators Dotts.
And in there, I will export a class which will name custom validators.
Now you probably don't have that solution, which is absolutely fine.
It's just that I want to all just show you an alternative.
I want you to learn something when looking at my solution to even if you did have a perfect solution
before it.
So this is just an alternative, not strictly better, just an alternative.
In my custom validators class here, I want to have a static function which I'll name in valid project
name.
Now, for such a specific validator, having a global bundle of validators might not make very much
sense, but I guess you can imagine projects, apps where you do have such a global repository of Valderas.
In the end, we're using the built in repository of validators here too.
Now we're creating our own ones.
So Invalid Project Name will receive a form control here as input, make sure to import it.
And this type file too, because we're using to type here.
So we need to tell typescript where this is coming from and we will return an object.
But we again have a key value pair.
Where we have.
Key, which represents our error code, and then a boolean, and now I simply want to check if control
value equals test, and if this is the case, I will return an object where I say invalid project name
is true.
Like this, otherwise I will return null.
So with this, I created my own static method, static is important so that we can access it without
having to instantiate our own class here.
Now, back in our app component, we can assign this by going to the project name wrapping.
It is required validator in an array because we're now going to add multiple validators.
And in here I now want to reference my custom validators class, which would therefore need to import
at the top from dot slash custom validators.
And in there, the invalid project name function, which we don't execute as before.
And as a side note, if you use this in there, make sure to bind it again.
Even if that were placed in the app, component types could fall because it will be executed by ANGULAR
at runtime.
And then this will not refer to what the refers to during development in this case here.
So this allows me to save it.
Let's now check the validity.
If we inspect this input here, it's invalid because it's empty.
I enter something.
It's a valid I test it becomes invalid again.
So our own validator works again.
It would have been perfectly fine if you would have added this to your app component.
Let's now add an asynchronous validator.
So here I will implement the same with async in front of it to make clear what the difference is.
And I'll then also name it invalid project name.
Of course, you could also create design the app component file.
We will receive the form control here and we will return ever a promise of type any or an observable
off type any and observable needs to be imported from our actual observable.
With this in here I again will create a promise.
I will return.
So a new promise which will receive a function as an argument to the constructor dysfunction will receive,
resolve and reject.
And then I will execute a timeout in there, let's say, after two seconds.
I want to execute this function here, this anonymous function, where I will again check if the control
value equals test.
So I.
Assante, Synchronoss validator.
But now, asynchronously, if this is the case, I will resolve this exact same error code here, actually.
So like this.
Otherwise, I will resolve.
So we should resolve them all if it is valid.
Well, and then I can return the promise here now with Dad we can attach this validator.
So besides our custom invalid project name here, let's actually change just to test project so that
we do have two different values to check for, so I can leave the old validator on there and attach
my asynchronous validator as a third argument to form control here.
I will also reach out to my custom validators and then the async invalid project name again, don't
executed only pass the reference on.
I will simply split this over multiple lines to be in line with the requirements of TEUs linta.
So like that.
So with that we configured this form control null devilled value to validators, one of them our own
validator and the asynchronous validator.
Checking for D test project name with Dad.
Let's save this and therefore reload this project and now inspect our project name.
It's invalid.
If I enter test there, it's also invalid if I enter test for it's pending and valid if I enter test
project it's pending and invalid.
So our own asynchronous evaluator is working to.
And with that we practice some of the things you learned in the last lecture's of this course.
Again, feel free to play around with that, build much more complex forms and in the next course module,
we're actually going to apply some of the knowledge you gained in our course project in the recipe book.
See you there.