In the last lectures we did a lot of setup to get the information about the item we're about to edit.
Now let's edit it.
I want to get the item we want to edit and for this in a shopping list service.
I'll need a new method which is simply get ingredient which expects to get the index a number and which
will simply return as the ingredient from our ingredients array.
So the ingredient at this index.
So with that returned we now can reach out.
Q Does new method in our shopping added component and store it in the edited item maybe which is an
ingredient self type ingredient.
And we do this whenever we get a new information that we're in the edit mode I should say so here added
that item will be said equals you reaching out to the shopping service to the item we get from the get
ingredient method.
And here we simply pass our index so with this we get a lot of information here.
Now we need to update our form if we are in edit mode and for this I want to get access to the forum.
Now on the form we do have a local reference f we can use this together with at view child to get access
to it.
So here I will actually use at view child and make sure to add the import from at English core.
I will reach out to F and this will be the shopping list forum of type and G forum.
So make sure to assign this type here.
Now once we got all the new information inside of the subscribe callback and that is of course important
outside of there.
This will not be run each time we get a new information but it might be run before we got any information
at all.
So outside would be wrong inside of this callback here.
I want to reach out to my forum and call set value here and now I want to assign a new value for the
name I will use my editor's item and year the name and for amount you guessed it.
I'll also use my added that item and then the amount and this should make sure that when ever we select
a new item we actually populate the forum with the right values.
We can already try this with any sort of running once our page reloads if I click here.
We indeed select the correct item.
So dad is working as expected.
Of course it still adds it as a new items that we need to make sure that if we are editing we correctly
rename this button to to update or something like this and that we then also do update the item and
don't add a new one.
Let's do this in the next lecture.