Thus far, we always were only interested in the response data of our request,
right? For example when we fetch the post, we get the response data, we map that and we return the subscription
and then we use that data in the component.
Nothing wrong with that and absolutely what we need here
but sometimes you need access to the entire response object and not just to the extracted body data,
sometimes you need to find out which status code was attached or you need some response headers and
in such cases, you can change the way the Angular HttpClient parses that response and you can
basically tell Angular, "hey, please don't give me the unpacked, the extracted response data
you found in the body,
give me the full response instead" and let's do that for sending a POST request for example.
You do that by adding this extra argument to configure the request
and here I won't set any headers or params, instead here we can change the observe key here. Observe takes
a couple of values and intellisense here incorrectly shows that I can only set a body, that actually
is the default and body means that you get that response data extracted and converted to a Javascript
object automatically but you don't have to stick to body. You can for example also change this to response,
by the way you should get an error if you enter something incorrect but response is supported.
Now let's see what this is.
We are already logging the response data or whatever we get back here in the console, so we should see
that when we add a new post.
So let's simply enter some content here,
doesn't matter,
let's send that post and now you see you get back the full HTTP response object.
You have the body in there and conveniently, this still already was parsed and converted to a Javascript
object for you but if you wanted to access it, you would now have to access it by typing response data
body here and you even get autocompletion because TypeScript understands that we request the full
response here. So you still have access to the body but now, you also have access to the headers of the
response, to the status code, the status text,
if it was OK which will be true, if the status code is in the 200xx region, so if it's not a 400 or
500 status code and that can be more useful in some scenarios where you maybe don't care about the body
or not only about the body but you actually want more information than just that. With observe,
you can change the kind of data you get back. Now,
this is how you observe the response,
you can also observe something different.
So here when we delete posts, I will use observe again and I mentioned that body would be the default
and that extracts the response body and converts it to Javascript.
You also have response as you learned,
now you'll also have events,
now what is events?
Let's simply have a look at this events thing by using one other operator which we can chain in here
and we import that from rxjs/operators and that's the tab operator
and that simply allows us to execute some code without altering the response, so that we basically just
can do something with the response but not disturb our subscribe function and the functions we passed
as arguments to subscribe.
So here, I simply pipe tap in there,
I get my my event presumably since we observe events here and I can console log this and you don't need
to return anything or anything like that,
it won't interrupt the normal observable data flow,
it just taps in there, allows you to do something but then automatically lets the response pass through
so to say. So let's see what that gives us.
If I now click clear posts, we see we get two outputs now and these outputs stem from post service line 70
which clearly is this console log.
So it seems like we got two events here - the first one logs an empty object or an almost empty object
where we have type 0 and the second one is the HTTP response object. In the end, you have different type
of events and they are encoded with numbers.
However here in code, you don't have to use these numbers,
you have a more convenient way. We can check event type and compare this to HTTP
event type which is an enum you can import from @angular/common/http.
This is supported in TypeScript only and for Javascript, this in the end just is a map of numbers,
so of zero and so on
and it understands which type of event, so which number here stands for which internal type of event
but here we have a more human readable way because now if you type a dot here, you see the different
translations.
Now these are just the responses for the numbers you see in that log here and you can actually see that
here in the preview. You see for example response has a type of 4 by the look of it,
this is simply number 4 encoded in more human readable text
and again that's a TypeScript-only feature, it is compiled to just that number comparison in the end and
you see that for example sent has that number of 0, so it looks like we had the sent first and then
we had the response event and that was also log.
There are other events too which didn't kick in here, for example when you were uploading files, you would
get back some progress information about that file upload,
how it is going
and so on.
So here,
if you ever for example want to check,
yes,
did I get back the response?
Then you can just compare the event type to this event type, so to this number and see are we having
the response here
and if you do have the response, for example you could log the event body because you know OK the event
we have here is actually my response object,
I can safely access the body. If you just send this,
so if the type is equal to HTTP event type sent, well then and TypeScript is really smart here, then you can't
access the body, here you actually have only the type but you could do something else, you could update
something in the UI to basically inform the user that request was now sent and you're waiting for the
response.
So that is how you can use these events if you need very granular control over how you update the UI and
in which phase your request currently is.
So to quickly demonstrate this again, if I now fetch my posts and then I'll clear them,
now we have our different outputs here and this null statement here for example is from me accessing
the response body which here just happens to be null
but if there were one, then we could safely access it here.
So these are events, obviously something you'll not use all the time but can be very helpful if you need
finegrained control over your request status.