Now handling form input is something you already learned about throughout this course
and here I'll use the template driven approach
but of course feel free to use the reactive one if you prefer that.
Now we got two inputs,
the first one, this e-mail input,
this one will get ngModel of course
and besides ngModel, it then also needs a name and the name can be e-mail
but of course you can take any name you want.
I also want to validate whatever the user enters here, so I will add required because this must not be
empty
and also the e-mail validator,
these are both built-in validation directives Angular ships with which allow us to validate the input
for being there, for being any input at all and for being a valid e-mail address.
Now the password will also receive ngModel and a name which could be password,
again that name is up to you
and here,
that should also be required
and I also want to have a minimum length here because we will use Firebase REST API for authenticating
and it turns out that this REST API indeed requests us to have at least six characters.
So here, we can add the min length validator and give this a value of six, so that passwords shorter than
six will not be accepted. Now I want to disable the button if the form is not valid and therefore on this
form element, we'll use that trick you already learned about in the forms section, we get access to that
form object Angular creates automatically for us by creating a local reference, giving it any name you
want, like auth form but that name is up to you and then you set this equal to ngForm and now
this will give you access to the Angular form object and we can now use the auth form reference here,
for example on this button, to disable it if not auth form valid,
so if the auth form is not valid, then the submit button will be disabled. And indeed now, you see it is
disabled and if I enter an e-mail address here, it still is disabled.
If I start typing a password, it is disabled and only as soon as I have six characters, it gets enabled
and if I convert this to something which is not a valid e-mail address, it also gets disabled. So this works,
we got working validation. Now of course when we submit the form, we also want to do something,
so here on the form element, as you already learned it in the form section, we can add ngSubmit and
there, we can trigger the onSubmit method and forward our auth form or just the auth form value, whatever
you want,
I will submit the entire form. Now in the auth component,
we therefore can add onSubmit here and we'll get our form object here which is of type ngForm as
an argument and therefore you need to import ngForm from @angular/forms
and now here, we can of course for example console log the form value and also call form reset to
reset it once we're done.
So let's give this a try,
let's go back here,
let me enter an e-mail address and a password and you see the form was reset correctly, it was disabled
again,
this button was disabled again and you also see this is the data I got,
this is the data I entered. This is now the data we'll use to actually use Firebase to, for a start, create
a new user and then, to also of course log users in.