You can simply google for far base of arrest API and you should find an article in the official docs
which gives you an overview over the arrest and points firebase offers to you for creating users and
logging users in here on the right.
You see the different things you can do with that back and with that REST API firebase offers you.
It's a different REST API than we used before it's not our database REST API we created automatically.
It's a dedicated authentication API offered by Firebase and we need only two methods.
Signing users up with email and password and signing users in with email and password.
So of course let's start with signing users up because we can't sign in.
If we have no users.
Right.
This is the you are L to which you need to send your request.
So this is the URL we'll have to send the request to you with this data with the email password and
then this return secure token thing which we also have to add to our request body which is a boolean
that essentially should always be true.
Firebase just needs that.
You can ignore that your API might not need that.
Now we'll get back a response with for example the email address.
The idea of the user because firebase automatically creates a new unique idea for each user.
And we all get back that I.D. token which is that token I mentioned on the slide earlier.
So firebase already gives us such a token once we sign a user up.
We don't even need to sign in there after we automatically get that token when users signed up.
We also get expires infield which tells us how long that token will be valid because for security reasons
these tokens will expire for firebase for example day at the moment expire after 1 hour.
Thereafter you even have to refresh them which will not cover a year or log in again back to this year
although we need to send this request and that screams for a new service here that actually deals with
that request sending.
So in the all folder I'll add my off service dog test file which is a service that will be responsible
for signing users up.
Signing users in and managing that token of my user in that of service file.
Let's def for export a class of service and debt service will receive D at in check the bowl decorator
which is imported from at Angola Corps where I will use that shortcut for providing it by setting provided
into route in that object we can pass to injectable alternative would be to add it to the provider's
array of the app module.
Now in debt off service we can of course start relatively simple by adding one method a sign up method
and this method should do just what the name suggests it should sign to user OP it should send the request
to debt sign up you are El therefore we will need the annular H to DP client of course and this needs
to be injected.
So let's add the constructor and now make sure you got at injectable here.
Even if you provide at the service in the provider's array of the app module as soon as you inject the
service into a service you need at injectable not necessarily with that object being passed to it but
you need the at injectable decorator itself.
And now we can inject the H2 declined which I'll store in a private property named H2 DP and to type
will be h to be client and it's imported from ET angular slash common slash H2.
In the sign up method we can now use the H to be client to send had levied.
Let's have a look at documentation post request here.
Send a post request to that you are out so copy that you are all here and here will use the post method
and then send the request to this.
You are out.
Now please note that in this you are L we got that API key thing which in the end is just something
you have to replace with your firebase API key and you can find that far based API key in your firebase
web console under authentication here if you click on a Web setup you don't need all that data about
this here.
This is your API key so grab that key without the quotes closed that and then replace API key here including
the square brackets with that copied key.
This is the U.R.L. we have to send a request to Nelson's supposed request.
We of course also need to attach some data.
So let me attach a javascript object here and that JavaScript object should hold free properties to
free properties.
This endpoint expects email password and return secure token.
These are the free data pieces.
This a back end end point requires and therefore I'll send my email here and I do expect to get dad
here as a string.
I always expect to get the password as a string so I will send the email here.
Email key gets that email value here and then the same for the Password Password key gets that password
value devalues here are the arguments I'm getting.
You could name these differently email and password have to be named like this because our API expects
exactly these keys.
It also expects a return secure token so you must set this as well and as you can learn in the official
docs.
This should always be true.
So they offer let simply set this to true here.
Perfect.
So this now will send an H to the B request to that back and here to this you are L as you learned the
HBP client does nothing without someone subscribing though and we're not even calling the sign up method
anyways so let's return this prepared observable now so that we can subscribe in you off component which
is where we might all be interested in getting the response of that because if we get an error we probably
want to display an error message and was we're waiting for the response we might want to show as I'm
loading indicator so therefore returning the observable such that we know the current state of the request
in the off component makes a lot of sense.
We also can find a format of the data we'll get back because we will get back these six fields here
and therefore I will create a new interface actually here and be of service because I only need it in
here and we don't even need to export it therefore it'll just be an interface which I'll name off response
data and this interface defines how such an object will look like how our off response data will look
like and it will have six properties as you learn kind I.D. token email refresh token expires in and
local ideas.
So let's I add all of them kind as a string as you will see here they are all strings I.D. token is
a string Email is a string then all we got the refresh token and expires in so refresh token is a string
expires in is a string.
And last but not least local I.D. which has degenerated user I.D. that also is a string.
Now why am I defining the interface here.
It is totally optional.
You don't need to do that but it is a good practice in angular and in types called apps to define the
types of data you're working with.
And as you learned in the age to be client module when we sent an HBP request with the angular H2 to
be client these methods your post get ends on these are generic methods where we can hint which type
of data we will get back.
And here we know for this post request we will get back data in this format which is now exactly the
format I stored in this off response data.
Therefore we can add the angled brackets here and simply pass off response data here.
This interface we just generated between these angled brackets so that we inform typescript that this
post request will yield as a response in which body we find data in this format.
This can be helpful for when we want to work with that response was that out of the way in the next
lecture we will actually fired his method from inside our off component and also make sure we handle
potential errors and we handled the loading state correctly.