Well, we proceeded with rendering
the component programmatically,
but now when we try to test that, we had this strange error.
And a quick side note here,
if you're not getting this error, if it just works for you,
then this is the case
because you are using Angular 9 or higher.
This is simply a tiny change
that was made behind the scenes of Angular,
so the general syntax it's on didn't change.
What I showed you works in all Angular versions,
but in Angular 9 or higher,
there was a behind the scenes change,
which makes this work out of the box.
Which of course is great,
but if you are getting this error,
which at all it's not unlikely
because not everyone is using the latest version.
Well, then here's why we get it.
It didn't find a component factory follower to component.
Well, we created one here,
why didn't it find that factory?
Well, ignore the first part,
this here is the interesting part.
Did you add it to Ngmodule entryComponents?
For this, you need to understand
how Angular actually works behind the scenes
when it comes to creating components.
Of course, any component, as well as directives and pipes
you plan on working with,
you need to add them to your declarations array.
And we did this for the alert component.
We did this for all the components that were loaded.
This is important for Angular to understand
what's a component or which components and directives,
and it's all you have in your app,
because it does not automatically scan all your files,
you'd need to tell it which components exist.
Still, this alone only makes angular aware of it
so that it is able to create such a component
when it finds it in one of two places.
The first place would be in your templates.
If in your templates,
let's say off the recipe list component here.
If it finds something like app recipe item,
like this selector,
it basically looks into the declarations array,
finds it there, and then is able to create that component.
Great.
The other place where angler will look for this component
is in your routes.
In your route conflict, when you point at a component there
angular will also check that in the declarations array,
and if it finds it there,
it is able to create such a component and load it.
Now, one place that does not work by default
is when you want to create the component manually in code,
which is the exact thing we're trying to do
in the off component.
There we're creating our own component factory
with the alert component.
And now here, Angular does not automatically reach out
to the declarations array.
It simply doesn't do that.
You can complain about that, still it's the case.
You'd instead deliberately need to inform Angular
that in this case, the alert component
will need to be created at some place
and that Angular basically should be prepared for this.
It will prepare itself for this creation
when it finds a component in the template
or in a route conflict, but here it won't.
Now to tell Angular
to be prepared for the creation of that component,
you need to add a special property to the object
you pass to Ngmodule.
Besides declarations imports and so on,
there is a property we haven't worked with thus far,
and that is entry components.
Entry components also is an array
and it's an array of components types,
but only of components
that will eventually need to be created without a selector
or the route contact being used.
So whenever a component is created by a selector,
or you use it with the route configuration,
you don't need to add it here.
Which is why thus far
we have the added anything to entryComponents.
For AlertComponent, it's differently.
And there, you simply need to add AlertComponent
to entryComponents.
Now, one for note
about this entryComponents property though,
depending on the Angular version you're using,
you might not need it.
If you are working in a project
that uses Angular 9 or higher,
and you can check your package.json file
to find out which version you're using,
if you're in a project with Angular 9 or higher,
you can emit entry components by default
because they're Angular
and the hood uses a different rendering engine.
Its name is Ivy and there it works differently
under the hood.
So the abra syntax doesn't change.
The only difference is that you can omit entry components.
You don't have to specifying a day or two, isn't a problem,
you will never make an error
if you do specify entry components,
just in some cases, you could omit it.
Now, Angular is ready to create it's component
whenever you prompt it to,
and you do prompt it to create that component here.
So now if you saved this
after adding that component to the entryComponents list,
and you try this again, you get your component here.
And this is now created programmatically in code,
but of course it's not working correctly.
We can't dismiss it,
and we're also not seeing a message here.
How can we make this work?