For this, this is the app without lazy loading, so the app as we currently have it, and if you go
to the network tab and you reload the app here on this off page, unauthenticated.
You see, we download a bunch of files here, we have our let me shrink this, we have our polie, Fuld's
Forestalls Jass, Vanderjagt Main Jass.
These are for JavaScript files and we're in development mode here, which is why they are extremely
big.
They will be smaller ones.
We built the app for production because this code is not optimized at all.
It contains many debark features.
So it will be way smaller later and we'll see that later.
But at the moment, you see we have pretty big files here.
Four megabytes, one hundred kilobytes, almost a megabyte, 236 kilobytes.
Now, again, this will shrink significantly.
But still, this is our current file size with lazy loading, we should be able to decrease that.
How do we add lazy loading, though?
Let's start with the recipes module, because, for example, here, when we're not authenticated,
we certainly don't need to load the recipes module code because we can't even access anything from the
recipes module here.
It might also not make sense to load the shopping list module even though we can access it, because
unless we do, there is no need to download that code.
So let's start with the recipes module.
Nonetheless, there we have the recipes module and we have its own roots here in the recipes routing
module.
Now, having the Rawat's registered here is an important starting point for a lazy loading to work,
your feature module needs to bring its own roots.
As we're doing it here, it needs to bring its own root config.
We're doing that here and it needs to bring that with Warchild, which is also what we're doing here.
Now, one thing we'll need to change, though, that path recipes here.
I will change it to an empty POV because now we need to add something to our app routing module for
lazy loading to work here.
I'll again add another route and that will be the route for recipes.
Soda pop I just removed from the recipes module.
Now, here I'm in the app routing module, important, I add that POF again here, but now I don't add
a component which I want to load, but instead you add load children.
That's a special property in a config which Angler understands as please only load the code content
or add a module.
I'm going to point you at when any one when the user visits this path.
Here, let me show you what this means.
We can now add.
A string here, not a type, not a component type you pointed, but a string, which is a payoff to
the model you want to load when dispatcher or when this path here is visited.
And I, of course, want to load relatively from the routing module.
My recipes folder, and they're the recipes.
Module, not the recipes routing module, but the recipes module, and now you also need to add something
here, it's not just a pop, but you also need to add the name of that module because Angular can't
know that and it needs to know the class name because technically it will go to that path and then try
to dynamically import a specific object from that file.
And theoretically that could be named anything.
We are, of course, following that naming convention of naming this recipe's module in this case and
here when the file name is named Recipe's Thought Module.
But no one is forcing us to follow that naming pattern.
And therefore we explicitly have to tell Angler what the name of the exporter class in that file is.
And you add that by adding a hash tag and then that name, so low children points at recipe's, recipes,
recipes, dot module dots and then hash tag and the name of that class.
The effect of that will be that now the code is split at that point and everything else this path here.
So this entire module and everything that module uses.
So all the declarations of that module will be put into a separate code bundle, which is then downloaded
and passed on the MOND as soon as a user visits this page, but not sooner.
And that is simply achieved by the angular Seelie, essentially analyzing this when we build our app
and it will then analyze the recipes module at which we point here and it will look at what we declare
in here and so on, and we'll post a code of all these things we declare here into that separate bundle,
which is now built separately, detached from our main bundle with which the app starts important.
For this to have a real effect and save code is that you have these import statements only in the recipes
module and you don't have any old import statements to, let's say, the recipes component in, let's
say, the app module, because ultimately for the build process, it's important what you import here
at the top.
What you import here like that forms module, which I should remove in the app module.
What you import here is all bundled together into one code bundle.
So in the recipes module, in the end the bill process will look at these imports which are required
for this to work, but it will look at these imports and whatever is included here will be included
in the same bundle.
So if you have another even unused import, add something like this lying around in your app module,
then this part would be included into the app module code bundle, even though you're not using it there.
So to have the biggest effect and save the most code, make sure your imports are at the top are correct.
If they are, then you'll get the biggest possible effect from that code splitting now into recipe's
routing module.
It's important that you have an empty path because you have to keep in mind that we now changed the
route conflict to include the path here in the app routing module and it will load the recipes module
whenever we visit recipes and therefore into recipes module.
We now already are at recipes and hence here in the recipes routing module, which is only kicking in.
Once we do visit this module, we should start with nothing because again, we already are at recipes.
Now, save all that and quit your build process and restart energy serve because after adding lazy loading,
you will need to restart that to ensure that it really has an effect and is taken into account.
Now here I'm getting an error and the issue is that we should remove the dots.
Now, one note about this syntax.
In newer versions of ANGULAR, you have an alternative syntax and this syntax might even fail in your
project.
So if you are getting an error like module cannot be found when trying this out, which we'll do in
a second, or if you want to switch to that, more modern, different syntax for any other reason here
is that obvious syntax you could use.
Instead of having this string here to identify the module which should be loaded, you can add a function
here and anonymous eral function and in the function Bordo you call import like a function so you don't
use import as we do it up there to import modules, but you call it dynamically as a function to import
you then pass the path to the module.
So slash recipe's recipes module and now you don't add a hashtag thereafter to identify the module,
but instead import resolves a promise.
So now you call, then there and in this promise or in this, then lock, you pass in a function which
receives in the end the module which was loaded here.
Hence I named the argument M and on this module object you can extract your modules to recipe's module
in this case.
So this here is the end, an alternative, Syntex.
You could use for loading routes lazily instead of using the string you see in the video store after
you can use this function.
Now, generally, it doesn't matter which of the two approaches you use, but this is the more modern
one.
And if you are getting errors with the approach, I'm showing the lectures with just a string based
one switch to this one instead.
Let's restart, and she served thereafter, and this looks good, however, now when it loads, you
should get an error like this.
And do you have an idea what might be causing that?
Well, in the model, I'm still importing the recipes module.
Now, the recipes module is the module we're now trying to load lazily.
So we should only have this part here, this route where we use low children.
We must not import recipes module anymore.
Otherwise we're importing it both eagerly and lazily at the same time.
And that will cause an error, of course, all the remove that import statement.
Otherwise it will technically work.
But you won't save anything in code size.
Now, if that's saved, you should be able to save this again.
Recompile.
And now this looks good.
No error.
And now let's go to the network tab here and reload this page.
Now, the vendor file is still pretty big because that's just angular.
But Manges actually shrank previously.
That was, I think, 117 kilobyte.
So definitely above one hundred, now it's seventy five.
So this shrank and we can see where it went.
If we kaleen that here and we do login with valid credentials and now we are redirected to recipes.
And indeed here you now see.
That you have this recipe is recipes module Jaspal here, the naming might differ, but that has the
41 kilobytes by which our Bundall effectively shrink roundabout, and that is that lazy loaded code
snippet, that lazy loaded module.
And we can interact with that just as we could before.
So that is all working.
But now we're a lazy loading and this shrinks our initial bundle size.
Now, of course, the big bundled of for one megabyte bundle did not shrink.
But again, this will be optimized later.
And the bigger your app grows, the bigger the features are.
Your lazy loading, the bigger the effect will be.
Of course, if you have a large app with an entire area in that app that the user might never visit.
If you lazy load that, it might have a huge impact because you can save so much in that initial bundle.
Now, of course, it makes most sense to lazy load parts of the app where there is at least a slight
chance of the user never using it, for example, in this application.
You could argue that lazy loading the off page doesn't make too much sense because the user will always
see that, though I guess that's also only correct if you assume that the user is already locked in,
the user is not logged in, we can visit the recipes page and therefore will never the off page and
therefore even lazy loading the off page might make sense.
But if you have some page which will always be visited or with a very, very, very, very high chance,
then lazy loading that page or that module might not be worth it because you have to consider that lazy
loading, of course, comes with the downside of that extra code, Bonnel being downloaded later and
therefore once it's needed, there might be a slight delay in your app since that code needs to be downloaded
and parsed.
So you're basically just postponing that, though, while also showing optimization technique with that
in a second.