We're nearing the end of this module and I want to conclude it by diving into one other optimization
technique we can and should perform before we ship our app to production.
So before we deploy our built angular app onto a server, and that is ahead of time.
Where is this Just-In-Time compilation and what's that?
Well, in our angular application, we're of course writing some code are angular code and our template
code and our templates, of course, include special angular syntax like NGF and Ferenz on only Angular
understands this templates we're creating.
That's not a one to one snapshot that's going to get rendered into the real DOM.
Instead, Angler will pass our templates and then update the real DOM based on the instructions we placed
in our templates.
So all our components and our directives are in the end translated to commands that will be used to
alter the real DOM JavaScript in the browser.
Doesn't understand our templates.
Angular does, so we write our templates for Angular because Angular understands all these features.
So whilst we use the typescript compiler to compile the types good code to JavaScript code, which of
course is understood by the browser, we also have another compiler in that built process working behind
the scenes as part of a..
Surf, which is the angular compiler that is included in the angular framework.
It's a crucial part of the angular framework, and it's actually quite big.
The angular compiler itself is written in JavaScript.
It's relatively large and it's part of the angular application you are seeing in the browser with Engy
Surf.
So that angler compiler takes to compile JavaScript code and your templates and actually translates
all the logic there into concrete instructions that update the real dumb disk by default happens all
in your browser because the angular compiler is part of the angler code you're shipping.
This process is called Just-In-Time computation because the angular templates are compiled just in time
when the rendering occurs in your browser.
So the angular compiler runs in the browser at runtime.
The obvious downside of this is that this compilation process takes time.
It's super fast, but still it's a small performance hit and the angular compiler.
So the entire code that is just responsible for compiling or templates is not that small.
It's actually quite large and it's part of your angular application, even though it has no purpose,
it has nothing to do with your business logic other than bringing it onto the screen, which arguably
is important, but still a bit annoying that it has to be part of your application.
The good thing is it doesn't have to be part of your application since the angular compiler is responsible
for converting your template code into your template.
Instructions into a JavaScript commands the browser understands we can do that during development as
part of the build process.
And that process is called ahead of time computation because we compile the angular templates ahead
of the execution time, then the angular template compiler runs during the build process before the
app is deployed and not in the browser.
Now, DNG ServPro says as of now, by default, uses the Just-In-Time compiler because that's better
for debugging and fast updating of the running application, and there's nothing wrong with that during
development.
We have no problem with shipping a too big application where the compiler is part of the code because
we're not optimizing the code size during development.
We want to have a good development experience with rich error messages and so on.
But as soon as we're preparing ourselves for production and for building our angular app for production
to then upload it on a server, we want to optimize our code as much as possible and shrink it to as
small of a bundle as possible.
And we do that with a command.
You'll also see in the deployment section I quit and you serve here.
We do that with energy build, but there you actually add dash dash profit for production.
This command takes your angular application and now does not spin up a development server where you
can see it, but it actually builds your entire app into a few files which you can then deploy now showed
a deployment process in a separate module.
But let's already execute this command because this automatically does an important optimization for
you.
It uses ahead of time computation.
You don't need to configure anything special.
That's the great thing.
It works out of the box, but it does it for you.
And here we now get an error.
Property control does not exist on type abstract control in your recipe added component.
This error didn't occur earlier because the Just-In-Time compiler is a bit more forgiving than the ahead
of time compiler does.
Ahead of time.
Compiler does some extra checks and here it found code it didn't understand.
So let's have a look at the recipe component HTML file there.
The problem is this part.
This part works with the Just-In-Time compiler, but the ahead of time compiler basically does not understand
that disk partya recipe form get ingredients gives us back a form array that has a controlled property.
It doesn't know what we get back here.
It knows we get back in.
Abstract control for Mouret is an abstract control, but basically an extended version with this extra
controls property.
Abreau controls don't have a controlled property and that is the problem ahead of time compiler has.
The solution is to remove that code from the template and move it into the typescript code.
There we can add a new Gater property.
Let's say here.
With the get keyword.
And then we named as ingredients controls a gater property is like a function which you can use like
a property in a template.
You can't set a value to it, though.
You can only read it.
That's.
Achieved by using to get key word here in front of the property, name the signature, then looks like
the function signature with the parentheses in the curly braces.
And then there we return this recipe form, get ingredients.
And now to inform TypeScript about the type of this and that, we know that there will be a form eRate
we wrap this part here into an extra pair of parentheses and add as form array here.
Form array needs to be imported from adding life forms.
This is a typescript instruction that tells TypeScript all this good.
This term here or this expression here will resolve to a form array and therefore it does not complain
about us using controls here.
Now we're returning this and therefore the only thing we did is we made this more type.
Securer might seem redundant, but it is important for the.
Ahead of time, compiler to not fail anymore, now we can use ingredient controls, disk geter property
here in the place where we previously had that code snippet.
And now if we save that and we rerun Engie Bill Prot, now, this will actually work.
Let's wait for this to finish.
And hear this now before we have a look at what this generated, let's all the rerun and you serve here
to see whether dad also works and to again have a look at the development file sizes, which were quite
big, if you remember.
Let's wait for this to build.
Here it is, let's log in real quick here, go to the recipes module, fetched recipes and then maybe
also added one to see that the edit page really still works.
That looks good.
Let's create a new recipe where we add an ingredient.
So this all works without errors.
Now, that is good, of course.
Let's now have a look at what this engy built command generated.
It generated a nudist folder, this folder contains a folder with your project name, and in there you
got multiple files which are basically which basically contain the content of your application.
So your code files, but now bundled and optimized and decreased in size as much as possible to be as
small as possible.
Let me actually inspect this year in my finder or in the Windows Explorer to have a look at this.
And there you see.
These files are much smaller.
Remember that in development, we can see it here actually in the network tap if I reload this page.
We do have files which are free, dot eight megabytes big and one megabyte.
Now, here, if you have a look at these files there, Weismuller, they shrank significantly in size
because of all these optimizations and ahead of time computation is one important optimization because
it removes the angular compiler from the final bundle, which is super important and huge, of course.
So definitely always build your application with Energy Bill Dashboard before you want to deploy it
somewhere.
But speaking of that, deployment is also something we'll focus on next in this course.