[Maximilian Schwarzmuller] Angular 14 introduced
an amazing new feature: Standalone Components.
And over the next minutes,
I will explain what exactly Standalone Components are,
why this feature was added, how it works,
and which problem is solved by it,
and we'll explore basic Standalone Components,
along with more advanced use cases,
like using Standalone Components with services,
routing, or lazy loading.
I wanna highlight right away, though,
that this feature was introduced
with Angular Version 14 in preview mode,
so as a feature preview.
This means it's not fully stable yet. Details might change.
It's not the recommended way
for building production Angular applications,
and that's why my Complete Guide Course
does not use Standalone Components as a default,
but it's very possible
that Standalone Components will shape the future of Angular
and might become the default way
of building Angular Components and Apps
once all the details have been finalized,
once everything has been polished,
and once this feature has been battle-tested
and is the recommended default.
It's not the case right now,
but it's still really interesting to dive into this feature
and play around with it,
and that's therefore what we'll do over the next minutes.