Now, to understand what exactly
Standalone Components are
and which problem is solved by them,
I prepared a basic demo project,
which you find attached to this video.
Now, this is a standard Angular project,
nothing spectacular about it.
What's important though
is that this project uses Angular version 14 or higher.
What I teach you will also work with higher versions.
Here I'm using the release candidate
because I'm recording this
before version 14 stable was released
but, of course, everything I explain is true
for the stable version as well.
I also again wanna emphasize
that this is not the only way of building Angular.
Instead, it's a preview feature,
so you should use NgModules,
you should use everything I taught you
in my Complete Guide course.
This might become the future of Angular though.
Maybe some details will change.
We'll see in the future.
But what exactly are Standalone Components?
And which problem is solved by them?
Well, for this, let's take a look at this demo application.
It is a very simple application in the end
but it does have a couple of components,
it does have a custom directive and a service
and a shared module where I make this directive available
to all other modules that are interested.
I've got my app.module
where I'm declaring various components,
where I'm importing the SharedModule
so that these components can use the directive,
exported and declared in that SharedModule.
And then in those components which I have,
I'm using the other components.
So in the app.component, I'm using the welcome.component.
In the welcome.component,
I'm using the details.component
and in the details.component,
I'm using my custom directive.
And I'm also using my service.
And if you would install all the dependencies
with npm install,
and you then would start the development server
with ng serve,
then you would get an application that looks like this
and please note that the navigation won't work yet.
We'll add routing in a couple of minutes.
But then if you open the console,
you'll also note that if you click on this area here
at the bottom, those clicks are registered
because of our service.
You see the custom directive in action here.
It highlights this last paragraph.
And it is a standard Angular app therefore.
However, standard apps like this,
and all Angular apps in the end can have one problem.
There's quite a lot of boilerplate code you have to write.
You specifically have to add all these modules,
like the app.module, or the shared.module
to organize and declare your directives
and components to import and export modules
into each other.
And whist this is not really difficult,
it can be annoying.
It's a lot of boilerplate code you have to write,
it's a lot of extra work
and it can make refactoring rather difficult.
And it's, of course, not something you have to do
in other libraries or frameworks like React.
Now, Angular needs those modules internally.
It needs to know which components are available
in which other component and so on,
and that's why this feature exists.
It's not there to make your life more difficult.
Instead, it's needed internally by Angular.
Nonetheless, it would be nice
if you could get rid of these NgModules
and it turns out that this is exactly
what Standalone Components will achieve.
The Angular team worked hard
to build a way of using Angular
that allows us to get rid of NgModule,
to use Standalone Components
and standalone directives instead,
which don't need to be declared in some module.
And the best part is that this new mode,
which is in preview right now
can be mixed with the old way
or the current way of building Angular apps.
So you can mix Standalone Components
and directives and so on
with NgModules as you will see over the next minutes.
So that's the problem.
We have this boilerplate code
and we wanna get rid of it.
How can we now use those Standalone Components though?
Well, let's build our first Standalone Component here
at the example of the details.component.
This is a regular component,
which is declared in the app.module.
Now we wanna convert it to a Standalone Component
so that we can see
how we can build such Standalone Components.