So how are standalone components built?
Well, it turns out that you just build a regular component,
as you already know it,
and then you add a special property, a special flag,
to the object that is passed to the @Component decorator.
And that's the standalone flag, which is a Boolean,
which should be true.
False is the default and does not have to be added.
True sets this to be a standalone component.
And internally, this will change many things.
Because now, this component can be used in other components
without declaring it, though you still need to make Angular
aware of it.
If you change this to true, and you save this,
you will note that now the app fails.
It fails because this is now a standalone component,
but it is still declared in NgModule, and that is wrong.
Because now, when you switch this to standalone,
you should no longer declare such a component,
in this case, the DetailsComponent, in any NgModules.
So therefore, here, we should get rid of it.
Remove it from the declarations array
and remove the import.
With that, if we save this, it kind of works.
But it's actually gone.
We no longer see the details part down there.
Now, we also don't see an error in the console,
but it's gone.
The reason for that is that it's actually not yet known
by Angular.
Now, all Angular sees is that, in the WelcomeComponent,
there is an unknown HTML element,
and therefore, it does not output anything.
Because, yes, we as a developer know that DetailsComponent
is the element, or the component, with that selector,
but Angular doesn't know that.
Because even if you switch to standalone components,
you still must make Angular aware of those components.
But you don't have to do it in a module anymore.
At least, not necessarily.
Instead, what you have to do, is you have to go
to the component that should use this standalone component.
And, of course, one standalone component could be used
in multiple components.
But here, we only have one component
that's using app-details, and that's the WelcomeComponent.
So we have to go to that component.
And there, we have to add an imports property to this object
that's passed to the component decorator.
And here, we have to point at the standalone components
we wanna use in this component.
So in this case, I wanna use the DetailsComponent.
Hence, I point at it by importing DetailsComponent
and adding it here.
However, you'll note that if I now save this,
it indeed fails because this imports property
can only be set if the WelcomeComponent
is also a standalone component, which it is not.
Now, we'll switch it to a standalone component
in the future.
For the moment, let's instead get rid of that here
by commenting it out.
And let's find a different way.
Because I did mention before,
that one good thing about standalone components
is that you can combine them with NgModules,
so that you can migrate to standalone components
in a smooth way.
You don't have to rewrite your entire application,
instead, you can start switching individual components
to standalone components and still use them
in your other components that are part of NgModules.
If you wanna use a standalone component
in the various components that make up a module,
all you have to do is go to that module,
in this case, the AppModule.
And now, instead of adding
the standalone component here, to declarations,
you add it to imports.
In the past, you typically added other modules here.
Now, with the introduction of this standalone components,
directives, and pipes feature,
you add all your standalone components, directives, or pipes
that should be usable by the other components of this module
here, to this imports array.
So in this case, DetailsComponent,
which now, also, must be imported here.
It's imported and then added to imports here.
With that, everything compiles,
and we see our standalone component again.
And if I open the console,
you see that clicks are also still registered.
And all of that works, except for the custom directive.
That does not work. The highlighting is gone.
Now, we'll fix this in a second,
but before we fix it, let me come back to this AppModule.
What's the idea of standalone components
if we still have to add them here?
I mean, the only thing that changed
is that we now add them in a different place,
here, in the AppModule.
And we now, actually, have more code to write,
because we did have to add this standalone flag
to the DetailsComponent.
Well, this is only the case
because this standalone component
only gets used in one other component,
which is part of an NgModule.
So we're in the middle of a migration process here.
It will be less code if you only have standalone components
or if you have a standalone component
that's used in a bunch of other standalone components.
Here, we have the worst of both worlds.
So we didn't actually gain anything yet,
but we'll get there over the next minutes.
This is, however, how we can add
such a standalone component.
And therefore, in the essence, all you have to do
is set this flag and then add it to imports
either in an NgModule, or,
if WelcomeComponent would be a standalone component itself,
here, with help of imports, like this.
But that is something I'll get back to.
Before we get back to this, let's make sure
that our custom directive is working again, though.
Our custom directive is not working anymore,
because while I do still use it here
in the template of my DetailsComponent,
this component is a standalone component,
and therefore, decoupled from an NgModule.
Yes, it still has to be imported there,
but it's not aware of any other things
that might be made available by that module.
Specifically, the DetailsComponent
does not know about the SharedModule,
because it's only imported into this module,
it's not receiving anything from that module.
It is, however, the SharedModule
that has my HighlightDirective.
Now, what if I wanna use this directive here,
in the DetailsComponent?
Well, there are two possible solutions.
We could turn the HighlightDirective
into a standalone directive,
because standalone directives can be imported
into any other components where we wanna use them,
including standalone components.
But let's say that's not an option yet.
We need to keep it in this module right now,
because we're in the middle of a migration process
and we don't wanna turn this directive
into a standalone directive yet.
Well, that's no problem, because in my standalone component,
the DetailsComponent here, I can add the imports property,
which I already mentioned before.
And you cannot just import other standalone components
or directives that should be usable
inside of that components template,
but you can also import other modules.
As I mentioned, you can combine standalone components,
directives, and pipes with NgModules, just as you need it,
so that you can have a smooth migration process.
So here, I can import the SharedModule, like this.
Add the import up here, and add it to imports here.
And with that, if I save this, this works again.
I got my styling back, because my HighlightDirective
is now doing its job again.
Because now, the standalone component
knows about this module,
and about the things exported by that module,
like the HighlightDirective,
and therefore, the directive is able to work again.
Now, as a side effect, since in this simple Demo App,
the DetailsComponent is the only component
that uses this directive, I can actually get rid of
the SharedModule here, in the AppModule,
because the other two components in there
are not using anything from that module.
If they would be using anything from that module,
we, of course, would have to keep
the SharedModule import here.
But with this Demo App, we can get rid of the import here,
and we don't have to add it to imports here.
And the app still works.
The directive is still doing its job, because now,
my standalone component, the DetailsComponent,
is directly importing that SharedModule.
So that's, now, how we can get started with that.
But we're still in the middle of our migration process here,
learning about standalone components
and how we can blend them
into an existing module-based Angular app.
Which is important because, for the near future,
that is what you're most likely going to do.
And even in the long-term future,
you will always work on some Angular applications
that will use modules,
but wanna move to standalone components,
or simply wanna use both.
And that is absolutely possible.
But now, let's actually dig deeper
into standalone components,
and let's migrate all these components
to standalone components,
so that we can see how that will work.