So in order to migrate everything
to Standalone Components and directives and so on,
let's actually continue with the highlight.directive.
This directive is exported by the SharedModule
but in this demo app, we only use that module
and that directive in the details.component,
which already is a Standalone Component.
Since that is the case,
we could actually turn this highlight.directive
into a standalone.directive
by also adding the standalone flag
to the Directive decorator object like this.
So just as components,
directives and actually also pipes
can be turned into standalone building blocks.
In this case, I'm turning the directive
into a standalone directive.
Now, with it turned into a standalone directive,
it must no longer be added to any declarations
in any modules, and therefore here in this demo app,
we can actually get rid
of the shared.module all together therefore
because we don't need it anymore.
Now, in the details.component,
we are, of course, using that SharedModule
so we should get rid of the import.
And instead here in the imports array
of the details.omponent,
we should import the HighlightDirective itself
because that's important.
When you are working with Standalone Components,
standalone directives and so on,
then you always must import them into the other components
where you wanna use them
or with imports into the modules
where you wanna use them, as shown before.
It's not enough to just add this flag.
You also need to import the things,
the directives and components you wanna use
in other components into those other components.
So in this case, I wanna use the HighlightDirective
in the details.component
because I'm using it here in my template.
Hence, I have to add it to imports like this.
But with that flag added here to the directive,
and the directive added here
and the SharedModule gone
because we don't need it anymore,
everything works as before.
We also got no error here.
And we are now using this component successfully
and we now migrated another building block
to be standalone.