So now that we also migrated this directive,
let's migrate more components.
And the next step probably would be to migrate
the WelcomeComponent.
Now here, in this component,
we therefore also turn this to standalone
by setting standalone to true,
and now, we can readd this import
and also add DetailsComponent to imports here,
because, as mentioned before,
if you wanna use a standalone component or directive
in another component,
you have to add it to the imports array of that component.
In this case, the WelcomeComponent wants to use app-details,
so we have to add DetailsComponent here
as an import to the file, and then mention it here
in the imports array of this component.
Now, with that, it will fail however.
Now, for one, we now should remove DetailsComponent
from imports here, not because it's needed technically,
but because in this module, we only added it,
because the WelcomeComponent needed the DetailsComponent,
but since the WelcomeComponent is now itself specifying
the DetailsComponent already,
we no longer have to do that here in the module,
because the AppComponent is not using it.
If it would be, we would keep it here,
but since it's not, we can remove it here and remove this.
But that's not the reason for the error,
the reason for the error is that the WelcomeComponent,
of course, must not be added to declarations anymore,
because it is now standalone,
we added this flag to it after all.
Now, we have to do what we did before therefore,
instead of adding it to declarations,
we should add it to imports,
and with that, we migrated another component successfully
and the app still works.