Now that we also migrated
the welcome component,
it's time to finally migrate the app component
as well though,
because this will then also allow us
to get rid of this entire app module.
So therefore we should go to the app component
and there also add stand alone and set this to true.
Now in there I want to use the app welcome
or the welcome component
so therefore we should add imports as you learned it
and import the welcome component
and also add an import to the file here.
Now, with that, it will fail though
because the app component is of course
an important component.
Yes, we would have to remove it from app declarations.
But if I now add app component here to imports
it will still fail,
because as mentioned it is a key component.
It's the root component.
If we want to migrate the root component
of our application and turn it into a standalone component,
we also have to change our bootstrapping code in Main TS.
Instead of bootstrapping with a module
we now wanna bootstrap a component
and just a component, because we just have a component now,
we don't have a module anymore.
I mean, we have one here, but we don't need it anymore
because the root component is standalone
and the idea behind standalone components is
that they work without modules.
Therefore in Main TS
we now bootstrap the application,
not with this code.
We can get rid of that therefore.
Instead we call a bootstrap application function
which is imported from @angular/platform-browser.
We import that, we import this function
and cue bootstrap application,
we pass a pointer at our root component.
So in this case app component.
I'm importing app component from app app component,
and I'm pointing at it here.
I'm passing this pointer at this class
to the bootstrap application function.
And with this, if we saved that,
our application works again
I also got no error here,
the service still works,
the directive obviously still works.
And now we migrated everything to standalone components
including the root component,
which now must be bootstrapped with help of this function,
which takes that single standalone component
instead of an entire module.
This all also means that we can get rid of app module now,
of this entire file.
Because this browser module which was imported
is made available by bootstrap application anyways,
it's made available by default.
So we don't need to take care about that.
And other than that, we only had imports here
and we don't need that anymore.
So now we can get rid of app module.
And that was our goal in the end.
And that is the biggest benefit we can get
out of standalone components.
Because now I got rid of both modules
which I had in this application at the beginning
and we therefore now have less boiler plate and leaner code.
And if I save this, the app of course still works.
Now, of course, we did have
to add all these standalone flags
and these imports properties,
but it is possible that maybe in some future
standalone components will be the default
and therefore this flag doesn't have to be added anymore.
Because in the future may be true is the default here
and hence this can be omitted.
but right now that's not the case yet.
But then we would have less boiler plate code.
And regarding imports,
chances are that this is never going to disappear,
but of course it's still less code to write
and less boiler plate
than you have with all those modules,
especially in bigger applications
where your modules can get very complex.
So this is now this app migrated
to standalone components and standalone directives.
As a next step, let's take a closer look
at services with standalone components
before we then take a look at routing and lazy loading.