Now, I wanna take a brief look
at services with Standalone Components.
I do have one service in this demo app
and it is a service as you would always define it.
It's a class decorated with @Injectable
where I provide an object
with the providedIn property set to root.
This, in the end, makes sure
that this service is provided to all components
of your application,
all your components and directives can inject this service
and all those components and directives
will operate on the same object based on that service.
Now, this works just fine with Standalone Components
as you can clearly tell
because no adjustments were needed here.
However, you might recall
that this is not the only way of providing services.
Instead of doing it like this,
which is the recommended way typically though,
you could have also added this service
to the providers array of a module.
And that would have been fine as well
and it would have also made that service available
to all components and directives,
and it would have made available a single object
of that service.
What you can also do
and what you could do before Standalone Components as well
is you can go to a component
and add the providers property
to this component's decorator object.
And again, this is not new.
You could do this with Angular 2 already.
And then you can also add your AnalyticsService here.
Add a import to the file
and then point at the class here.
And if you save this, you will notice
that this still works as before.
So that's another way of providing services.
Now, the difference is that if you add a service
to a component like this,
every component gets its own object.
So if you use the same service for multiple instances
of a component, you get multiple instances
of that service as well,
and there is no shared state.
Sometime that's needed, often it's not.
Therefore, you rarely do that.
This behavior is not new though.
It always worked like this.
I just wanted to mention again
that you can still use it,
even if you are using Standalone Components.
Now, if still, for whatever reason,
you don't wanna provide a service globally
by adding providedIn here,
you can also bring back the old feature
of adding it to a providers array.
Previously, you added the NgModule
with a providers object,
which was an array of services.
Now in such a application that doesn't have modules,
you can go to the bootstrapApplication function here
and add a second object,
which allows you to provide some configuration.
At the moment, there's only one property you can set though
and that's the providers property.
And here you can do exactly what you would imagine.
You can add your globally provided services here as well.
So here I can also add my AnalyticsService like this.
Add a import to the file, add the class here,
make sure you don't have providers
in the DetailsComponent anymore
and still with this kind of code,
you will see that if I open this,
my service still works.
So this is the equivalent
of having a providers array in a NgModule.
If you wanna provide some service globally,
you can add it here with this second argument
that's passed to BootstrapApplication.
Now, here this is really not needed.
Therefore, I'll comment this out actually.
You could do this but it's not needed
because here the best way of providing this service
is to add this providedIn syntax.
Still, I wanted to mention it
because it is important to understand
how you can work with services
and Standalone Components.