Now with all those basics
about Standalone Components out of the way,
let's move one step further
and let's take a look at Standalone Components
combined with routing
because, of course, in many Angular applications,
you also need routing.
For this, attached you find an updated starting project,
which is the same project as before
with all those components migrated
to Standalone Components,
at least the components we worked on thus far
but we've got some new components in there as well.
We've got an about.component,
which renders a simple dummy About Page
and a dashboard.component
which renders a dummy page,
which also has another routerLink in there
because there we can navigation
to this today.component,
which is another dummy page.
Now, what's interesting here
is that the dashboard components have their own module
where I'm specifically declaring the DashboardComponent
and then the DashboardRoutingModule,
and the DashboardRoutingModule
is responsible for navigating between dashboard
and this TodayComponent
and it's worth noting that they are provided
with the forChild method, making them lazy loadable
because that's the idea.
I have this dashboard-routing.module
and the module and its routes
should be loaded lazily when they're needed
by the app-routing.module.
This is also new, another new file I added
to this starting project,
and in this app-routing.module,
I am defining some routes,
the root route to the Welcome Component,
the about route to the AboutComponent
and then the dashboard route,
which loads this dashboard-routing.module lazily.
So that module I just showed you
is loaded lazily here.
And again, this is all default Angular code.
That is what you already know.
That's nothing special.
But this also won't work like this
because at the moment,
this app-routing.module
is not wired up because we have no app module.
We removed that app module after all.
Therefore, if you ng serve this,
if you start the development server here,
you will notice that this fails
because in the app.component template here,
I'm using the router-outlet
but this won't work anymore
because the app.component
is a Standalone Component
and does not know what to do with that router-outlet
and it also doesn't know about these routes.
So therefore, that's what we'll have to fix here.
Now, as a first step to fix this,
we have to make the app.component
aware of the router module,
the router module that's built into Angular
so that it knows the router-outlet
but also the routerLink directive
because routerLink and router-outlet
are things totally unknown to Angular
if you're not making the router module available.
And right now, the app.component
doesn't know about it because it's standalone.
So just because we have an NgModule here
where we are defining the RouterModule
does not tell the app.component about it.
Instead, just as with our own customer component,
we have to import the RouterModule here.
We have to add it to imports here
in our app.component and also add the import here
at the top of our file.
With that, this error is gone
but now we don't see anything on the screen.
The reason for that is that Angular now does know
about the router-outlet,
it does now understand this
and it does understand routerLink
but it's not aware of those routes yet.
Now, to make Angular aware of these routes,
we have to go to main.ts
where we bootstrapped the application
and here we basically
have to add our routing module to providers.
Now, the routing module is not a service
but forRoot actually acts as a service.
Now, to make the app-routing.module work here
in main.ts, we have to import a special helper function
provided by Angular Core
and that's the importProvidersFrom function.
We have to add this here
to our providers array on bootstrapApplication
and it's a function, so we execute it.
And then to importProvidersFrom,
we add a pointer at AppRoutingModule, like this.
So we have to import AppRoutingModule
from this AppRoutingModule file
and then we point at it here.
We pass a pointer at this routing module class
to importProvidersFrom.
And this in the end makes
our standalone root component aware
of our routes and makes
the overall Angular application aware of our routes,
so to say.
If we save this now,
our welcome page is back
but we can now also navigate to the About page
or the Dashboard page.
And it's worth noting,
if we reload the application on the Home page,
and we open the Network tab in our browser dev tools
that this dashboard page is loaded lazily.
If you watch the HTTP requests here,
you'll notice that if I click on Dashboard,
the code for this component
is only downloaded when it's needed.
So lazy loading works just fine here
and it's also worth noting
that all of that works in a application,
in an Angular app where many components,
including the root component
are actually Standalone Components.
So app.component is a Standalone Component
and nonetheless, by connecting our routing setup like this,
we are able to use routing with our app-routing.module
and with a couple of components
that are not Standalone Components at all.
Dashboard, today and about are not Standalone Components.
Instead, they are registered in a different module
and in a different routing module,
and everything works just fine.
So again, you can blend modules
with this standalone approach also when using routing.
But you can also choose a different approach,
turn those components into Standalone Components as well
and then also adjust the routing code accordingly.