So how can you migrate those components
to Standalone Components,
and which adjustments are needed then?
Let's start with the AboutComponent.
Here we can add the standalone flag,
just as we did it before and set it to true.
And if this component would be using any other directives
or other Standalone Components,
we would have to add them here to the imports array.
But for this component, that's not the case.
And now this AboutComponent
is in the end referenced here in app-routing.
There we have this AboutComponent
at which we're pointing, which we wanna load here.
Now, if we are dealing with a Standalone Component,
this will still work.
If I save this code, if I even restart ng serve
to be super safe that this all works,
you will notice that if I reload the app,
we can still visit About as before.
So you can use Standalone Components here.
And this shouldn't be too surprising
because the WelcomeComponent
already was a Standalone Component
and navigating to it worked just fine.
However, if you are dealing with Standalone Components,
you can also load them with a different syntax,
which will actually use lazy loading
because with this syntax here,
you are not loading this component lazily.
Instead, it is included in the main bundle.
But with a Standalone Component,
you can go to your route configuration here
and add a special loadComponent key here.
And now loadComponent, just like loadChildren,
takes a function,
which should return the result of calling import
and then here we point at the component
which we wanna load lazily,
add then and then simply extract our component here
from the module, which is loaded lazily.
So from the file which is loaded lazily.
Now, this is a brand new feature,
a brand new syntax,
which only works with Standalone Components.
If we save this, the application works like before.
We can still go to the About page
but if you open the Network tab again
and you reload the app on the Home page,
you will note that when you go to About,
the code for this page is also just downloaded
when it's needed.
And this is actually an enhancement you get
with Standalone Components
because now with Standalone Components,
you can load individual components lazily
without having to wrap them into a module
like this dashboard-routing.module, which uses forChild.
Without Standalone Components,
even if you just wanna load a single component lazily,
you basically have to wrap it into such a routing module
where you use RouterModule.forChild
and then you have to load
that router module lazily with loadChildren.
That's how you have to do it prior to version 14
without Standalone Components
even if it's just one component you wanna load lazily.
Here with Standalone Components,
this is now made way simpler.
We can use loadComponent
and point directly at the component
which we wanna load lazily.
You don't need an extra wrapper routing module.
So this is a great simplification which we get here.
Now, if you have multiple components
that should be loaded lazily,
you can still use the old approach
of having a separate wrapper module.
But it's also not something you have to do.
You can simplify this code as well.
And for this, first of all,
let's turn these components, today
and dashboard.component
into Standalone Components as well
by adding the standalone: true flag to them.
Now, these are Standalone Components
and we could use them in any other components
by adding them to the imports array
of those components,
but we can also use them with routing.
Of course, back in our app-routing.module,
we could use them by simply repeating
this syntax here, for example.
Or even without lazy loading with this syntax.
But we can also still use loadChildren
but instead of adding this extra wrapper module
and this extra module,
we can get rid of dashboard.module.ts
and actually also get rid of dashboard-routing.module.ts.
And instead here in the dashboard folder,
which has these components which I wanna load via routing,
we could add a new file,
for example, named routes.ts,
the name is up to you though,
and in that file, you can simply export a constant
or a variable maybe named DASHBOARD_ROUTES.
The name is up to you.
And that should be of type Route array.
Route is a type imported from angular/router.
And then here you set up your route configuration objects
and you have a path nothing,
which should maybe load the DashboardComponent.
So you must import this component
and then point at it here.
And you add another object
with a path of today
where you point at the TodayComponent.
Alternatively here, you could also use loadComponent
to load this component lazily only if it's needed.
So you could be more granular if you wanted to.
Here I'm loading both routes together
but not when the application starts
but instead when we navigate to the dashboard area
of this application.
And here we just have a route definition.
To make Angular aware of this,
what we can do now and what we have to do now
is we have to go back to the app-routing.module
and here for the dashboard route,
instead of using loadChildren
to point at the dashboard-routing.module,
we use it to point at dashboard/routes
and then from that file,
we import the DASHBOARD_ROUTES constant, which we exported.
So this will now load these routes lazily
but we only need to define the route definitions here.
So again, we save a lot of code.
We don't need the wrapper modules
because we converted the dashboard.component
and the today.component to Standalone Components.
Well, and with that, if we rerun ng serve
to make sure everything is picked up,
if we reload the application,
we can go to Dashboard and About,
and this all works.
Now, as a last step to make sure
that today's highlights work here,
we should also go to the dashboard.component again.
So to this component,
and add imports here
and import the RouterModule simply
to unlock all these router-specific directives
like routerLink, which we're using here
because otherwise, this is not available
in this Standalone Component
because you must never forget Standalone Components
are totally decoupled from any ng modules you might have.
And here we almost have no ng modules left.
We have the routing module though
but they're decoupled from all those modules
and therefore, they don't know about the RouterModule
in this case.
If you use routing features,
routing directives in this component,
you have to add RouterModule here to imports.
And with that, this link will work again.
So now this all works.
We have routing back with less modules
and more Standalone Components.
And we now only have the routing module,
which we still need here to define our routes,
which we make available in main.ts
for Bootstrap application with help of importProvidersFrom.