Now, that's it for this introduction
to standalone components.
It's now hopefully clear how they generally work,
how you can convert components to standalone components
with help of this flag.
That you must add all the things that are used
inside of a component to this imports array,
no matter if it's another module or as we had it
in case of the details component,
if it's a directive or anything like this
and that with all those standalone components
and directives, you can get rid of pretty much
all NG modules, which saves you a lot of boiler plate code.
Now, you also saw that mixing and matching is possible.
You don't have to migrate everything.
You can migrate some components and still import them
into your modules or use modules in your components.
That is both possible.
Again, don't forget that it's a preview feature.
Things might change, things might get easier.
New features might be added
but already you can build Angular apps with that,
the recommended stable way is to still use
NG modules though.
This feature is primarily meant to be used to play around
with it and test it and find out if it works for you.
That's the idea behind this feature right now.
It does, however, have the potential
of simplifying Angular apps in the future.
Maybe this becomes the officially recommended way
of building Angular components.
Maybe in some future, no more NG modules are needed
and of course that would be great
because that would mean less boiler plate code
and that is probably something we all could live with.
For the moment though,
it is a feature to play around with and experiment with,
and hopefully I could help a bit with all of that.