In this module, we'll dive into angular universal, which is an addition to angular, you could say.
Now, as you know, Angular allows you to build frontman's user interfaces, user interfaces that run
in the browser, your entire angular app runs in the browser.
Angular Universal now allows you to pre render your angular app on the server.
So it's not a server side framework like express chips or anything like that.
You won't use it to write server side code, but it allows you to on the fly pre render pages, your
users visit so that when the users load the page, they get that finished page served back and that
initial rendering doesn't need to happen in the browser.
And only subsequent actions by the user are then handled as always, in the browser only.
Let me show you what exactly I mean.
Here's the recipe book we built now for you, right click here and we view the page source, then what
you see here is that you don't see much.
We got the app root element here and then a bunch of secret imports.
And this is how a normal angular app looks like.
These script imports here are, in the end, our angular application.
So the angular framework and decode, we wrote, compiled, optimized and bundled together and approved
here simply marks the place where our code in the end will start rendering.
The angular app that we see this on the screen is simply the case because the angular apps, all these
scripts do their job and they change the page we're seeing after it has been loaded by the browser.
It has happened so fast that we don't see that.
But this is what's happening now.
This approach generally is fine, but in some situations it might have downsides.
Imagine that your users are on slower networks.
In such cases, the JavaScript download might take a time, and until the JavaScript code has been downloaded,
your users will see nothing or take search engines, a search engine.
So the crawler of the search engine looks at different websites to index them, and the search engine
only sees what's initially downloaded by the server.
It doesn't necessarily wait for all your scripts to be done with rendering what the user sees.
So a search engine might not see what the user sees in the end.
Instead, it might see, well, this and as you can imagine, this is not so great for getting a good
index score because you don't see much.
Right.
And that's what the search engine sees for such reasons.
It would be good if that initial first request.
So when you first visit the page, when you first load, it would be presented on the server so that
we get a real HTML page sort back.
That page will still contain all the script imports because it will be converted into an angular app
after it has been loaded so that subsequent clicks are again handled in the browser, only to be fast
and reactive.
But that first load is handled on the server that fixes the search engine problem and also fixes the
issue of slower connections and angular universal helps us with that.