So here's our code and to add angular universal here, you only have to run one command, you run engy
ad at Engie Universal Slash Express dash engine, make sure to get this right.
Then blank space and then dash dash client project written like this.
And now take the identifier you find in your angular JSON file, this identifier here, this name under
projects introduce after a blank after decline project here with debt, your project will be transformed
such that it still works as before.
And you can still run it as a normal, angular app if you wish.
But you now also have the option of running it on a server and getting that pre rendering stuff.
Notis will take a while because it will do a couple of installations and transformations will do quite
a complex setup.
And as a short side note, until a few months ago, you had to do all of that manually.
And actually later down in the module, I still have the older version of this module where I do it
all manually.
That still works.
And I will leave it in here so that you can also have a look at the manual approach and get a better
idea of what's happening behind the scenes in case you're interested.
So now this is done here.
And now with that being done, there are two important things you need to do before you can take advantage
of this.
The first important thing is that you should head over to your app server module and in there, make
sure you have that module map loader module imported.
Now, if that hasn't been set up for you simply at this by going to the terminal and by running NPM,
install, dash, dash, save and then at Engie Universal slash module, dash map, dash engine factory
dash loader.
Now, that's obviously a very good name.
In the end, this is a crucial package which provides this module map loader thing here, which is angular
module, which we have to add to imports in the app server module, not in the app module, but in the
app server module to enable lazy loading with angular universal.
Without that, your app would fail if you use lazy loading because the Lezley loaded Rawat's wouldn't
be able to be rendered yet.
So let's wait for this installation to finish here.
And with it finished.
Make sure you at the airport and then add the imported module, map, loader module, package or module
as it is here to imports in the engine module, in the observer module file.
Now, that's one thing.
There is another important thing you have to understand, though.
Your code here now is first rendered and executed on the server, not in the browser.
So the first page to first load is rendered on the server and only after that first page has been rendered
on a server and returned to the user.
Only then a normal single page application starts to run in the browser of the user.
That has one important implication.
It means that certain browser only APIs are not available, namely in our project here, local storage.
If you search for local storage where setting data in local storage and we're also reading data from
local storage.
I'm extracting user data from a local storage down there in my order log, in effect, this would fail
on a server because local storage is a browser only API.
It's not available in no chance.
It's not available on the server.
Therefore, now, to fix this, you should therefore go to your app.
Component types could fall where we are dispatching this order login action and make sure you don't
dispatch it when this gets rendered on a server.
Now, for that to work or to avoid doing this on the server, you need to find out whether you're running
on a server or not.
And that can be done by injecting something special here into the app component.
You can inject an identifier provided by Engelhard that tells you on which platform you're running,
basically.
So let's store does injected value in a property and I'll name it platform ID because that's what we'll
inject in the end.
And now you don't inject by assigning a type here as we always did before, but instead now you use
a special decorator, which we haven't used thus far because you rarely need it used to inject decorator.
Normally dependency injection works such that you defined a type here in angular looks for this type.
Now we're not injecting a class though, or an object based on a class, and therefore we don't use
the type of a class, but we inject a hard coded values, so to say.
And Disvalue has an identifier defined by a which we can also import from Anglicare, and that's the
platform ID identifier that's a constant provided by ANGULAR.
And you use it here with add inject in front of this argument now in front of this argument to construct
a receives and there you pass that identifier platform ID and this tells Anjelah, please look for the
globally provided value with this identifier and inject the value which is globally provided by Angular
into this class and store it in this platform ID property.
That's what's happening here.
Therefore we don't need to assign the type here.
So now it does inject that we can use this here, an engine in it to check if and now we need one more
thing from Angular and now that's coming from the angular.
Common model, that's a method of function which Angella provides the ES platform, browser or server,
whatever you want, functional to go with its platform browser.
And this allows us to check whether the platform is a browser to platform.
This code is running on so we can run is platform browser.
And this function requires such a platform ID, and that's why we injected it, so as an argument to
the function, we passed this platform ID and with that, Angella is able to find out where our code
is running.
And I only want to dispatched you all to log in here if we're running on the browser, not in the server.
Now, here I have this log in my app component Halib from App Component Engine in it, and I only have
that in here to prove that this still runs in the browser.
So it's not just running in the server because that would be bad because there we won't try to log in.
It will also run in the browser.
So in the browser this will be repeated.
So the page will be pre rendered on a server, but once it served, this code will run again on the
browser and therefore all the logging will work in the browser, but not in the server.
That's good because all the login relies on local storage, which is not available on the server.
With all of that, we're now done setting up angular universal for this app.
And this work around here is always needed when you are working with some browser only API and now with
that.
We have a look at Pakistan, Jason, we see there is this new build, as is our command, which we can
now run NPM run, build coal in SSR, which will now build our app for angular Universal, to be precise.
It builds it with the energy build command and production mode and then also creates a universal service
side built, so to say, and that stand allowing us to serve this app.
So let's wait for this to finish and a few words about serving this app.
Then you will need a notorious server.
So a host, a Web host capable of executing no chance to serve your Angella Universal app.
A static host likened into deployment, marginalises course will no longer do because you no longer
have a static site.
It's now no longer HTML, JavaScript and access.
Now you have code that runs on the server and hence you need a server that is capable of running that
code.
So if you now deploy your angular universal app, you need a server that is able to run node jazz and
on that server you can then run a command, which will show you in a second or which I can show you
right now.
Already it's this serve SSR Command.
You would take your entire folder here in the end, upload that on your node server and then run NPM
run services are on your node server to get that server up and running and serve angular universal so
that when requests hit that server, they are pre rendered and users then have the pre rendered thereafter
a normal, angular universal application.
So now it is finished executing.
And now I'm running the command which you all would run on the server.
You deployed your app to its NPM run serve Colen Ezat.
This will now surface through no chasten on this host localhost 4000.
You can now visit this app.
So here it is, and if I opened the developer tools, you'll also see hello from App Component here
in the browser log, which means this code also ran on the browser or in the browser and not just on
the server there.
It also executed.
You see it here, but there.
Thanks to our check, we didn't execute the code which accesses local storage.
And now back here, if I now inspect the page source we see here, we got some real contender.
What we see on the screen really was returned back by the server.
And that is, of course, how it should be.
This is how it should work, because this ensures that our page is loaded and presented, as it should
look like, and that search engines see our page the way they should see it.
So this is how you can enable angular universal.
Now, as I mentioned, you had to do a lot of that manually only a few months ago and offer later down
in this module, you'll find that full manual approach just in case you're interested in seeing what
happened behind the scenes.
Basically, what we do manually, there has been an automatically that engie ad script we used earlier.