Now, I'll go back one step and restart it so we have the added universal rendering, yet let's say
we still have that app that only renders in the browser.
There is another way of adding universal rendering using nest eggs.
Nest Eggs is a service site framework for a notorious it's not an angular library, not an angle framework.
It's a server side framework.
And I have a video on YouTube, but you can check out where I thoroughly explain what Nest is.
I attached a link to that here on this lecture.
So Nachas is a service side framework, but it borrowed a lot of ideas from ANGULAR.
It is basically like angular for the server side in quotes, because it fills a totally different role
being a server side framework.
So Nest's is pretty exciting and all the uses TypeScript and as I said, borrows some ideas from Angular
and the team behind Nestor's really likes Angular.
Therefore, they also added a command which you can use with Engy add.
We can use energy at at Nestlings, Engie Dasch Universal.
You can run this in any angular application.
And this will now also set up universal rendering, but with a nest gess application attached to it.
Now, the difference to the approach before is that before we had a simple server that simply pre renderers
our angular pages.
When we visit the page now here, that will work differently.
Let me quickly enter the name of the application before we continue.
We get it here in the angular Jason file.
It's this name here.
So let's use that.
And now back to what next that's different.
Ewer, what's special about in this case, what Nestea does now is it also sets up universal rendering,
but in addition, it gives you a full nest gess application to go with.
And SJS is a service that framework which you could use to build an API.
So with Dad, you would have a simpler approach of getting a full stack angular app where you don't
just have the browser front end, but where you actually also have everything you need to build a server
side API to which your angular app then could talk.
You don't need to use Nestor's.
Of course you could build an API with node expressed with PHP, with Java, with Python, or you use
a service like Firebase or you maybe have an application that doesn't need an API at all.
But if you want to build a full Steg app where you also write your own server side code and build your
own API to which your ANGULAR app can talk, then this is an easy way of getting started.
So now that this is done, what we have actually is our app here, but we now also have a server folder
and in there we have a very simple set up for Nest's application.
Again, in that YouTube video I mentioned, I will formally introduce you to next year.
So if you want to dive into writing your own API with that dead video should be helpful here.
Does is already set up to simply render our app pre render our app on the fly.
So right now it's only doing what we did with the approach before as well.
But now with the possibility of easily turning this into a complete full stack application by adding
server side code here.
Now, one important note, though, just as before, you should make sure that in your normal angular
code, in the source folder, in your app server module, which still was added, you have that module
map loader module added to imports.
So make sure you have that here.
If it wasn't added automatically, I show you how to add this.
In the last lecture, you basically installed this package at NBC Universal Module Dash Map Dash and
you factory dash loader.
Whence does this installed as a dependency you import does module, then add it to imports.
And then there's one other thing which we also did in the last lecture, which you need to do for this
approach as well.
You need to make sure that in your app component, this code you are the login code doesn't run on the
server and you can avoid that.
This happens by checking whether you're executing this code on the server side or on the client side.
And I explained all about this in the last lecture.
So here, I'll just quickly add to fix by importing something from at Angular Common.
And that something is this is platform.
Browsr.
Function.
And I also explained that you need to inject something with the inject decorator, you need to inject
the platform IDEAglobal, which ANGULAR exposes you do so in the app component by going to the constructor
there and then you simply add at inject.
Platform, I'd stored it in our private property, for example, platform ID seems to be a fitting name
and then here an NGO and in it you check if is platform browser, you pass this platform ideas of value
and only if that is true, so only if the code runs in the browser.
This should get executed.
And now you run this just as you run a normal anon nest eggs universe lap by running NPM run build colonies
SSR and then followed by NPM run SIRF Colen Ezat.
And you need to deploy this application if you want to deploy it on a no charge server, just as you
do it for a nonserious universe app.
So that does not change.
So let's wait for this to finish.
And now with this finished, we can again run, npm run, serve coal and SS are in.
This will now well served as EBP still in a similar way as before.
But now using this Jass and taking our SJS server into account, if you would want to deploy this,
however, you would still deploy the dist folder and the package.
JSON file deployed us onto a server and then they're installed the dependencies and run the services
I recommend here, which also just use this node to well run the server file.
So now this is up and running.
It's running on the same port as before and therefore we can simply reload this page here and you can
ignore this error, which is just related to life, reloading, loading.
What does matter is that this application works here and that we are able to use it and to work with
it.