Welcome to this module, in this module, we'll dive into angular universal, which is a tool provided
by the angular team basically and strongly built into the Seelie, which allows you to pre render your
angular application on the fly on the server.
Now, why is that interesting?
Here's our recipe book.
And if we inspect the page source here, we see that there actually is not that much to be found.
Right.
We got a bunch of script imports, some information in our hit section, but then mainly we got nothing.
We got our app route and that is it.
Now, the reason for this is that angular, of course, is a CLI insight framework and all our content
is rendered in the browser after this app has been bootstrapped, which is done by these script files.
Now, there is nothing wrong with that in general, but of course the user sees that.
But search engines see that and therefore it might be worth exploring a different way of rendering.
Our angular app and angular universe is a tool which basically provides a nice bridge from the awesomeness
we have with Angular in the browser.
This high reactivity to the pre rendering of pages so that the HTML we get back from the server actually
is a pre rendered snapshot of the page and once it's DENDE runs in the client.
So in the browser it's a single page application again.
So we want to get the best of both worlds and angular Universal can help us with that.