Getting started with angular universal is pretty simple if you're using the angular Seelie, which you
should and which we are doing in this course on the GitHub page of the angular Seelie, you can dive
into their official documentation and that documentation here.
That's basically a link to the wiki.
There you find some link to stories on the right here and then to universal rendering.
That's the article we're interested in here.
You can learn more about how to enable that universal rendering.
And it's just name Universal, because your angular app then runs on both the client and the server.
So here you learn how to integrate that into an angular Seelie project.
And thankfully, it's pretty simple.
It all starts by adding additional dependencies.
So we'll go through that and all the other steps step by step in this module.
And just one important note.
I will be using visual studio code in this module simply because I'm recording this at a later point
of time because it was recorded after the rest of the course was recorded and I switched the IT.
Now it's still the same code.
It's still the recipe book.
It's still the same project, just an angular six project that's important with a different ID.
And with that, let's continue and let's dive into all these steps and an able server side rendering
with angular universal.