So let's get started and let's get started by installing some additional dependencies, let's just copy
that command here, go back to the project and let's quit the energy search process and instead run
that NPM install command.
This will install additional packages which we need for the server side rendering to work.
The packages we do install are mainly the platform server package provided by the angular framework
and then some helper utilities.
We need to write to the server side code, which will do the pre rendering.
Let's go back to our step by step guide.
Then the first step is to adjust our app module.
Well, there in our source folder we have the browser module and we should now call with server transition
on that module, pass a JavaScript, object to that and set an app ID here.
That can be any string of your choice.
Like my dash app, for example.
This will be used by angular universal to basically correctly transition from the server side to decline
side and with transition, I mean things like continuing the app in the state.
You got it from the server.
So if, for example, on the server you already fetched some recipes from a database, then you of course
want to continue with that state on the client and therefore does make sure that we keep that state
and that the transition is done correctly.
OK, so that's the first step.
We call with server transition.
Now we need to create a new module, a new engie module for the server side, because there we start
the app a bit differently than we do on the client side.
You can copy that code you find here and I will walk you through it step by step.
So let's copy it and let's create a new module next to the app module here.
I will create the app server DOT module to file and paste in that code we just copied.
Now, what do we find in this file?
We do import to the server module from at Angular Platform Server and we add that to imports.
This is a crucial module which is required by angular universal to render your angular app on the server.
You can also see that we import the base app module, which we also use in a client to we import it
from our app module file and we add it to imports.
Last but not least, we have that module map loader module here, which has a very complex name but
does just one important thing.
It ensures that our lazy loaded routes, all the work on the server and with that our module here is
finished.
Now we just need to make sure that we also have an entry funnel for our suicide code, a main Dotts
file for the server and therefore named Main not server Dotts.
Let's edit next to our client side, main doctor's file here, let's add mainboard server dots, and
in there, we just have to do one thing, we'll export something.
We'll export our app server module, which we, of course, find in the app folder and there in the
app server module file.
This allows us to point at this file and then indirectly, automatically point at that file.
And that is all we need to do.
We just need to pass on that reference to the Apsara module, so to say.
With that were done regarding our module set up in the next videos, we'll tweak our typescript compilation
configuration because we need to compile typescript code a bit differently for it to run on the server.
And then we'll actually set up that simple note just server, which will do the pre rendering and already
see that in action.
So let's continue.