Let's continue by adjusting the types of configuration we need to adjust it, because our default typescript
config, which is responsible for compiling our typescript code to JavaScript code, that won't work
for the server side there, we, of course, want to execute our angular code.
So we want to execute our angular app there, but we need to compile it into code that does not run
on the browser, but on the server.
And for example, node jazz, which is the server side language you have to use for that pre rendering,
uses a different import export syntax.
So we need to compile our typescript code differently.
And to add to this compilation, we can take its config, not apologize and file and duplicate it.
And let's rename it to TIAs config dot server dot json file.
Now in there you need to switch the module from S 2015 to Common JS.
You can also find this here.
Now, the other settings are OK, but we need to add one extra setting, we need to add some angular
compiler options.
You can, of course, all just copy the entire snippet here.
Now, I will just add these options and they will configure that angular compiler, which is not the
typescript compiler, but an additional compiler which compiles the angular templates.
So your HTML code with all your directives and so on to native JavaScript code dis compiler needs to
know what your starting module is.
And here I'm pointing at the observer module file without the extension hash tag and then the class
name we find in that file.
And if you didn't change anything about that observer module, then this default setting should work
for you.
Now we can compile our angular app, which is written in typescript, of course, into a version that
can be run on the server.
For that, we just need to tweak our angular JSON file a bit there, we need to add a new built.
Command the server command, and I'll just copy the entire command.
Let's go to the angular Jason Folden and that search for the architect node there.
We have to build command, which builds it for the client.
And below that, I will add my server command.
Now, you could add it anywhere in that architect node, by the way.
I will add it here.
And that server command will allow us to run the Seelie or run the build process through the Seelie
to take our typescript configuration automatically and then build our app for the server, optimize
it and do all the heavy lifting for us.
For that, it will take a specialized builder, a build tool which is shipping with the Seelie or as
a dependency of Seelie, to be precise, which is suited for server side packages.
And we said some options and now here is an important option, this is where we want to build our app,
too, and I will named as this.
Recipe dash book now just a side note for the normal build process, the output path is just set to
decide.
Let's change this to this slash.
Rouzer.
And now go back to our service site, build and maybe change this to this server so that this is really
clear that this is the server site built.
Now, we also defined the entry point, which is this newly added mainboard Servatius file and which
typescript configuration to use.
Now, with that, we set up the build workflow and we can already test it to run our new server command
here.
We simply run engy run, not npm run, engie run.
Then the name of your project which you find in the angular Jason file here under project.
In my case it's Nc5 Complete Guide, then a colon and then the command you want to run.
So anything from that architect node built for example or in our case server let's add it here and hit
enter and this will now run our build command here which we just added with our typescript configuration
and it should spit out a folder.
This server which holds a main dot jazz file, which is to built angular bundle for the server side
or at least some part of it, which is required to do that server side pre rendering.
Now, that is the build process, which we need to adjust as a next step, let's add a simple note,
just server, which is capable of running debt free rendering process and serving our angular app.