So let's see what our next steps are.
The next step is to actually add a simple note express server, which allows us to run our application.
So for that will we can scroll down a bit.
We will create a new server dot t file directly in our route project folder.
You can just copy that entire file here.
But again, I will explain what we're doing here.
No worries.
So let's copy it.
Let's create it next to the angular Jason file the server dot t file.
Yes, we'll write this in typescript and paste into content.
Now, for this to run, we need to install some additional dependencies.
So let's run, npm, install, dash, dash, save.
And one dependency is to express chaske package which you install of just express not express chars,
just express.
This is a framework for node jazz, which we use in Deadfall to conveniently handle incoming requests
and sent back responses because we have no choice.
We are writing our own server, which is doing all the request, response, handling, and we need no
trace because it uses JavaScript and it's therefore capable of running our angular app.
So that angular, universal thing for now can really only be used with no choice.
We then also have a couple of our imports here, which are default nosiest packages.
So that will work since you have no choice installed.
Just as a side note, check notorious dot org and feel free to download the latest notorious version
there.
If you encounter any issues from this module, because you will need a fairly recent version of no chance
for it all to work.
But back to our dependencies will install the ExpressJet framework.
And that is actually all which we need to add for now.
So let's hit enter to download this and also store storage entry and package Dodgson.
And let me then walk you through this file.
Now, in this file, we first of all import some things.
The first two imports are needed by ANGULAR to be correctly set up on the server.
We also do import them into client side bundle and we need to load them early on the server side for
everything to work.
Then we're importing something from platform server which will allow us to bootstrap our angular app
on the server.
We import enabled mode, which we then call here to basically turn our app or set our app to production
mode to put some optimizations into place.
Then we import the express package, that notorious framework.
We import the joint effort from a default notice package which allows us to join multiple POV segments
and file names into a long, absolute POV on the operating system.
And we import Rietveld Sync from the file package No Choice offers, which will allow us to work with
files and we will need that to load our indexed HTML file, which we want to parse and pre render so
populate with real content in this server side code.
We're then creating our express app that is must have to be able to use the express features.
We then set up the port number where we want to serve this during development four thousand and we stored
the path to our dist folder in a well constant here.
And this is just constructed with the help of this choice method where we take the current working directory
and then add the dist folder.
So this constructs an absolute path to the disk folder.
Now it becomes interesting.
We read in that index HTML file from the browser subfolder in that folder and that doesn't exist yet.
Let's create it by running the normal client site, build with engy, build Dasht as brought.
This will now build the package for the client side as you're used to now.
This will do lazy loading ahead of time compilation.
It'll include all these things.
It's a normal build and it will build it into that browser subfolder in the disk folder because that
is what we changed in the angular JSON file there.
I changed the output folder to disk browser.
They are for once, this is done in this folder.
We will have the second it's not done yet.
We'll have a second folder, the browser folder.
Now it is done, here it is.
From that browser folder we're pulling in that index HTML file, we're importing that into our Servatius
file with this line and important, we're converting it to a string.
So to text, that is our template.
We then import our features from our compiled main file and here there actually is an error.
Our file is stored in this server and it's just named main, not main bundle.
So remove the bundle here.
These are features which were created when we built our app for the server side, and they are required
to make that connection between server side and client side and pre-built the app on the server.
We then import provide module map from this package to make lazy loading work.
And then here we're putting it all together.
Express G.S. knows so-called template engines.
These are basically tools which enable Express to pre render HTML files on the server, not just with
ANGULAR, but typically with other server side rendering engines like Puck Ejaz or handlebars.
It can run JavaScript code there too.
And now we use it with the angular server engine.
We create that engine by telling Express that we want to use it on HTML files and that we then want
to basically set up a renderer which should use our template as a preset the templates based on the
file we pulled in with some default options which we won't overwrite.
The defaults are fine where we provide that module map, which is a required to internally and able
lazy loading because it will basically give you a pass on the information about which extra chunks we
have.
And then that's it.
It'll then called this callback here where it passes on the pre rendered HTML.
So Dad will be our pre rendered HTML page for whichever route we requested.
This registers this view engine or this configures that, I should say with this line.
We're then registering it as our HTML engine.
We're basically saying, hey, please add the engine to the Express app for HTML and we defined the
HTML view engine here.
We then also have to inform, express where to find our views, and there were saying, you find them
in the dust folder, in the browser folder.
Now Views is a big word.
We only have one index HTML file, but that's still an important piece of information.
Where is this located?
We're then setting up Express to always return all files from within the browser folder aesthetically
so that when our app does run in the client and we want to get the JavaScript file or some Sears's file,
that this can be downloaded.
And then we're saying all routes, which we don't know.
So basically all routes, because we have a wild card, will be handled by rendering back a new page.
And we're pointing at the specific template we want to use here, the indexed HTML file in our browser
folder into this folder.
Since this is registered as a views folder, the view engine will kick in.
And since it's an e-mail, follow this HTML view engine will do its job and that will therefore pre
render that file.
It will take the index HTML file and fill it with life.
This is our server side code.
Now, we can't execute it just yet because it's written in typescript for no to work.
We need to compile it to JavaScript because Node doesn't natively work with TypeScript.
So let's write some compilation logic in the next lecture before we can finally see this in action.