Back in the instruction page here, we can see what we have to add to compile our Servatius file to
JavaScript, we will use Web pack, the built tool, which is also used to compile the client side typescript
script code.
We can't just copy that configuration.
Let's copy it and add it directly in the root folder.
There I will add a web pack dot server, dot config dot.
Just not just file and paste in that code.
Now Peg is a tool and I will not go in great detail through that.
We're basically saying take the Servatius file, build it for no chance, be aware of node modules and
so on and include any dependencies we need in that Servatius file and then output it into the desert
folder and keep the original file name, which is server.
In our case, we then add a so-called module loader to add extra features and here we add the T.
S loader, which we installed earlier, which will basically do the typescript to JavaScript compilation.
We then have some plug ins which are basically extra tools running over decompiled code, which will
do some adjustments which are required right now to fix something.
Chances are they will not be required in the future.
With that, we can run our build process and to run it, copy that Web server line you find here at
the bottom and add it to your package to chase and fall to the scripts section.
I add a new script here, which is this Web server script, and that is a script which will use WPEC
the built tool, which is available because it's used by the Seelie anyways, and it will take our WPX
to a conflict file, which then will compile the Servatius file.
We can run the script by running NPM Run, not engy but NPM run WPEC Colan server and this should compile
our Servatius file to a server.
Jaspal Now when you run this the first time, it asks us whether we want to install the webpage Seelie
entry.
Yes.
Here because you need that tool to be able to run that webpage build process.
So let it install that.
And once it is installed, it'll start with compilation.
Now, you may ignore the wording here, and you should now find a server jazz file in your dist folder.
We can now test this fall by running note this command is available since you have no choice installed
on your machine disk slash server, not just no.
Make sure you have both the browser and the server subfolder there with their build packages and hit
enter.
Now, we got a note server listening on localhost four thousand, so let's grab that link and let's
open it and then you tap into that URL and hit enter and I get an error here.
I get an error, which is telling me that something failed regarding the static injector.
Now, you might not be getting that error when you're watching this right now.
This is an error you'll always get and you can fix it by going to that Web server config file and by
setting the mode here.
Mode, a new property you have to add to.
Non.
Hit, enter and run that NPRM run WPX to recommend again to rebuild it again, and once it is done again,
rerun note disturber and revisit this localhost four thousand page.
And now you should see the recipe book here for you.
Now go to recipes and you reload.
You should see that if you inspect the page source, it actually contains the real content and not just
your app root node.
So this now is the content of your page pre rendered on the server, and it should work just as it works
on the client.
But now everything is pre rendered on the fly by the notorious server and desists angular universal
in action.