So we added this angular, universal pre rendering, how would you now deploy this application with
that added, you would basically still deploy to dist folder, but now you need to deploy it to a server
which is capable of running a node server because your hosting service where you deploy server Jast,
who needs to execute that server JS file, it needs to run that on the server.
That's really important to understand.
This file needs to be run on the server and therefore you can't use HWC as free anymore.
For example, you need some server where you can start that file and run it.
With such a server though, you just ship the content of the disk folder to it and then configure it
to run the server.
Jaspal and you're done.
This is how you would deploy it.
Still deploy the content of this.
But now to a server, which is not a static server, but one running.
Notice that it for angular universal.
I hope this is helpful.
You can always dive much deeper into this.
By the way, this is a basic introduction.
This is how it works in a nutshell.
This is what it does on the fly pre rendering.
Always keep in mind you have a single page application again once it runs on a client.
And if you want to dive deeper, you can visit universal dot, angular dot io to find server resources
and to get a page off that project where you can also learn more post questions or issues to be precise
and dive deeper into that.
So with that, let's move on.