Hi, everyone, welcome to this video.
In this video, Wiltern online only angular application into offline available one by adding a service
worker and as you will see, does a super easy to do with Angular.
And I will show you how to turn into such an application and how you can then also configure it to fully
meet your needs.
So let's dive in.
We'll start with this very simple, angular application here, and you can find to code to that project
attached to this video, and this is obviously a very well simple, not too exciting, angular app.
It is rendering a list of blog posts, dummy blog posts, which are fetched in our app component here
from Jason Placeholder.
All that is just a page exposing a dummy rest API, which you can use to get some demo data to display
on your page.
You can also send dummy post requests to them and so on.
But that's not what we'll do.
We'll focus on getting data.
So this is normal a'la app.
Not too many features, but it represents a typical angular app.
We got more than one component and we also got our posts.
And if you watch closely, you'll see them all using some special fund, which I'm actually pulling
in in my index HTML file here.
I'm importing this OSVALD font here from Google fonts.
So this is what makes up our angular app.
Now if we inspected in Chrome, we can go to the application tab here and developer tools and we can
turn this to offline mode, which means we're still online.
We don't have to quit our wi fi network.
But this will simulate that we got no Internet connection.
And if I now reload the page, well, obviously I get an error that we don't have an Internet connection.
If I go back online, it works again.
Now, let's see how we can actually fix this or change this behavior with the help of a service worker
and how we can easily add such a service worker to the app with angular.