Let's first of all, understand what a service worker actually is.
Now, this is how our JavaScript code typically behaves.
It runs in a single thread.
That means our Web application, which can consist of multiple pages or in the case of an angular app
with one page only.
This app often uses JavaScript.
And if you are using ANGULAR, you're of course using JavaScript because ANGULAR uses JavaScript.
So this JavaScript code, the entire angular app runs on one single threat and JavaScript has its features
to still handle asynchronous code and not block the execution.
But this is all normal JavaScript.
Now, JavaScript and the browser also offers us to run an additional threat.
We can run a so-called weap worker and a special form of Battisti service worker on another threat.
So this is still then uses one of the same threat.
But it's a different threat than your main JavaScript code.
And the important part is that this threat is kind of decoupled from your HTML pages.
So this means that this can also continue running in the background.
For example, on your mobile phone, that is something mobile browsers typically offer.
This can continue running and it could therefore also do advanced things like receive push notifications.
Take my full progressive Web app course if you want to learn more about this.
But one other crucial thing that a service worker can do is it can manage all your different pages in
case you got multiple pages or you're a single page if you're building an angular app and it can listen
to outgoing network's request so it can listen to you requests going out of your webpage.
For example, if you're fetching the assets off that Web page to see us as code to font JavaScript or
also data from an API, the service worker can catch these outgoing requests and do something with them,
like, for example, cache the responses in a special cache storage or then also return these cached
responses back to your page so that it also works.
If you got no Internet connection, of course, only if there is a cached version available.
This is what the service worker does.
It can be seen as a proxy between your app, your front end app and DDH request you're sending to the
backend.
It proxies that request, which means it catches it does something with it and might then allow it to
still go on and leave the app.
But it could also block this.
Now, configuring such a service worker and writing it from scratch is something you can do and something
you learn in my full progressive web app course there you also learn about features like push notifications
and so on for this video will focus on how Angular can easily add such a service worker to our angular
app because it turns out that there is a special package we can install for that.
Let's quit engy service and now here it's important that you're using the latest Seelie version for
that project and this project does.
And then you can run energy adds to add a third party package.
But that's more than just a NPM library, really some functionality to your app and only some features
can be added because essentially does will execute a command which has to be defined by whichever package
you are targeting.
So not every not even close, not every third party library supports this feature, but there is a special
library which does support it, which you can target with at angular weight.
And if you run this, this will actually configure your existing project to use the angular service
worker package and start with a pre configured service worker.
So does a lot for you.
You can already see it added some things to the index HTML file like the no script section to give a
warning of JavaScript is turned off because we need that.
Of course we need to turn on it loads this manifest here, which is also generated now that is important
for actually having a launcher icon for your app.
If you have it on a mobile phone, you can even save it to the home screen and then started with that
and you can define which icon that should use and so on.
So DataStore manifest adjacent file again.
Learn more in that course I mentioned for us.
Interesting is the app module because in the app module we are using a service worker module which is
imported from at angular service worker.
And this is really an official package of the angular framework and it does what it sounds like.
It registers a service worker, which will be that proxy that catches outgoing requests and does something
with them, and you will learn how to configure what it does to them later in this video.
Of course, we use it here by calling the register method and dare we target dng S.W. worker dot js
file and you won't find that file here.
And the reason.
Your dad is the disk file will actually be auto generated.
It will be generated during the build process and it will be in the disk folder, Darfur, and it will
hold your service worker, which will contain a lot of functionality, which you don't have to and typically
don't want to write on your own.
And here it's all configured to only be added if you're building for production in the assets folder.
We see some icons were added for that manifest adjacent file and in the project folder we see that in
the package to trace the file.
Something changed.
For example, the angular package was added, which includes that angular service worker package.
And we got this NGF config file disaster file where you can configure that service worker, which will
be generated.
But we'll take a closer look at this in a second.
The angular adjacent file, which manages to Seelie project all the was adjusted a little bit there.
Service worker is set to true for the production build.
This is required because the service worker will cache certain resources and to ensure that the newbuild
updates the service worker, these resources will contain a hash and dad will then also be injected
into the service worker, which is why we need to make the build process aware of the fact that we need
a service worker.
This is how it works.
Now, let's simply see that in action, let's create a production build by running energy, build dash,
dash prot.
And this will now bundle and optimize the entire app use ahead of time, computation and so on.
And it will spit out our angular app in a dist folder.
And there we should then also see the service worker.
So let's have a look to close the source tab here.
Let's refresh your statistic folder of the Angler folder for the project.
And there we see that Engy S.W. worker JS file.
You remember that is the file we are importing in the app module here.
We're registering it here.
So this can be found in the disk folder.
Indeed, if we have a look at it, you see there's a lot of code in there because, well, it's actually
pre generated for you to do all that caching and so on in a very efficient way.
And now let's simply do what it lets simply see what it does.
And for that, you need a Web server you can run to host your production.
Appia, you could do it with Engy serve.
It but there will actually not see the service worker in action correctly because it will only build
it in memory.
So therefore what you should do is install a lightweight node server.
And thankfully, there is one, you can install it with NPM, install Dadge to install it globally,
HTP server.
This is a package you can use to launch a simple node based server which will host the content of the
folder you run the command in and to command you need to run is just.
It should be their server, so let's navigate into our disk folder and there in the angular folder and
let's run HTP server and then you can assign a port with the ISP 881, for example, and build and bring
this up.
And now you can Wizzit localhost.
881, and you should see your angular app there.
Now this app looks like a normal app now reloaded once to make sure that the service worker can do its
work and go to application again.
We should now see that under application we got that energy worker running.
And if you don't see that, try reloading the page one more time.
Also, make sure to clear the storage here entirely.
If you worked with service workers and Dysport served on your local domain before now, you should see
that.
The interesting part is if I now take offline again and I reload, it still works, right?
We still see the same content as before, even though we're offline now.
How can that work?
If you go to the network tap and we clear it and we now reload, we see we're making a bunch of requests
here and they're all essentially served from DNG service workers here.
So from the service worker, this is all served.
The interesting part is the Post's request here, probably, which is still kind of can connect to the
outgoing server for that.
Let's again disable Wi-Fi and let's try this again.
And now it just does not work, but what we can see still is that for one, there is a Baggara and intended
behavior in Chrome, which leads to these API requests still going through, even if we simulate offline
mode.
But more interestingly, we see a white page.
We don't see that there is no Internet connection error.
Now, we would not just see a white page, we would see any content we add here.
If we lowered our page, so we essentially see everything that's hard coded into our angular app, the
dynamic content is missing.
We'll take a look at this in a second.
But all the hard coded content is there because what we can see in the network tab, instead we're loading
the main page, the styles, not the font, but the styles, the JavaScript files, all that is loaded
from the service worker and to failing things are the font and our posts.
Let me turn wi fi back on.
And I'll leave that simulation mode, which didn't work too great, I guess, and now, of course,
if I reload, it again works and let's now change something.
First of all, let's change something at the app component there.
I'll add one tech where I say my posts.
Now, let's quit that HP server, go back into the main folder and let's run energy, build dash dash
again and let's see how this now changes the app.
And if I'm right regarding my statement that hard coded content would be cached.
So let's wait for this to finish for that built to finish.
And once it's finished, let's go back into that test folder and there into that angular folder and
let's run our server command again.
So HP server on that port.
Let's reload the application here and you might need to reload twice and you should see my posts.
The reason for that double reload is that the service worker was loaded and the service worker is aware
of the fact that the index HTML file changed or that the script rendering content to it changed.
To be precise, because of that hashing thing.
I mentioned this hash table which is automatically generated and all default having hashes because by
default it would, of course fetch these resources from the cache.
So we would see the old version.
We don't want that.
So we take the new version by or we let us give the new version by using that angular service worker
package, which takes care about that hashing and the fact that the service worker is aware of the new
version for us.
So we get that now if we go offline again, you see that is also part of the loaded page.
And if I go fully offline by treating of wi fi, we still see that.
So now the font and the API call, the API data is missing, I should say.
So that is what I now want to change and to change this and get that same page here when we're offline,
where as I'm getting when I'm online, we need to change the service worker config, which can be done
in DNG as conflict adjacent file.
Now in this file, you can configure how the angular service worker behaves.
So let's take a closer look.