Now, this fall is actually not that long, it's a Jason fall Jason format, and first of all, we have
the index page.
This indicates what is the root page of our app we want to cash and load.
And that, of course, is the index HTML file sitting directly in the root server folder we're serving
from.
And then we get a so-called asset group or actually asset groups.
It's an array.
And in there we got two asset groups.
These objects, which we have in there now, asset groups are configurations that define which static
assets should be cached and how they should be cached.
Dynamic assets, for example, would be the data from the API.
So data were fetching, which might change on that API.
So it's not static, it changes frequently.
Our HTML file, our JavaScript code will also change with every build, but after to build it static,
it's not changing in some database or anything like that.
So that's what asset group is.
We can give such a group a name, whichever name you like, and you can then define how is should these
assets be loaded.
Prefect means that when your page loads angular will go ahead or the service worker will go ahead and
already pre fetch all the assets which are specified in this asset group, which means that puts it
into cash even if you haven't needed them yet.
The alternative to pre fetch is lazy.
You can use that too.
And Dad would only load them once you needed them at least once.
The advantage of lazy is, of course, that you don't occupy all the bandwidth right at the beginning.
The downside is that if you need it for the first time, it will not be there.
So if the user loses the Internet connection before the asset, let's say this successful is required
to first time, it will not work because it will not be cached with pre fetch.
It will be cached even before you need it.
There also is update mode.
I guess you can see it down there.
Now, this is important for the case that you're pushing a new version of your angular app and data
for all of your service worker to your server.
And the user is already browsing on that server and it will get informed about the new service worker.
And now the service worker can already pre fetch the updated assets or also load them, Lezley, when
they are required.
Now, the assets which should be loaded are the resource.
Then resources has one key property, the files.
And there you have an array pointing to the files you want to cache.
You can point at something like the HTML file and this is always seen relative from the dist folder.
So from the folder you will have in the end once you deploy this.
But you can also set up patterns like every successful or every JavaScript following the root folder,
or you could say every successful in any subfolder.
This is what this pattern would say.
So you can also set up patterns like this or directly point at the file you want to use without the
hash because you can't know the hash in advance.
Angular will generate that automatically, will take the unhatched file names here and then automatically
generate a service worker which will take the hashes into account.
Now you we get a second assist group for well basically all images we got and so on.
It differs from the first one in regarding the fact that it's only preloading that if we need them,
if we visited them or used them at least once, and this is leading to the behavior we have right now.
Now we got one allostatic essid, which is not included here, and that is our external front.
It's not changing or at least not regularly.
So we can treat it as static, but it's not included here because it's not one of our files.
But we can take it from the file by just copying that entire link, which will be requested eventually.
And then we can go back to the end GSW conflict file.
And there we tell Engelhard that we also want to cache this.
Now, we don't added to files because this is for local files.
There is an additional resource type can define and that is you or else it's also an array of strings.
But here we put you or else like this one, which are reaching out to our servers to then fetch resources
from there.
With that added, let's save that file.
Quit your server down there and let's go back into our route project folder and let's create another
build with energy build KROT like this.
And once this is done and we revisit the disk folder and served that again, we should see that the
font is also loaded in an offline mode.
So we go into the disk folder into ANGULAR, a rerun that HP server command and let's reload that page.
And with it reloaded, and you might also close it and open a new tab to ensure that the new service
worker gets really loaded and it's not still using an old one with that loaded, you can take that offline
box here again, or since I always needed to do that, simply turn wi fi off, go to the network tab
to see all requests and reload the page.
And now you should see that the font here all is not marked as red, but is actually loading the font
as it should.
So this is now also working.
It's not all the fetching this and we're still or now again able to use it in offline mode, that font.
Now what about the API?