Regarding the API, we can all do pre fetch this.
For that, we add a new configuration item, and that would be data groups.
Remember, we got ESSES groups here for the static files, essentially data groups for dynamic data.
So typically data you request from an API data that might change frequently.
How is a data group configured?
It is an array because it's data groups here, but one data group is then again an object.
Just as an asset group.
You then define a name of your choice like posts, but that name is totally up to you and then you define
the you or else you want to handle with this group.
And in my case, that is the U or L.
I can see in my app component, which is where I make this HTP request this you are L T.J. some placeholder.
This is what I'll take and this is what I'll put into the URL array as a string.
You could now also add a version here.
If you got an API, which might have different versions and the version changed, then you could lock
the version in here to, for example, cache different data pieces side by side for different API versions
here.
I will not use the version.
And instead, what you can add here is a cache config.
This is another object where you can now in detail configure how this data should be cached.
And for that you can, for example, set a max size.
This is a number and this defines how many entries do you want to cash?
And so that's important.
This does not mean how many posts, for example.
This means how many responses.
Now for this single you are l we will only cache one response at a time.
But if you had a more generic URL with a star, let's say four different endpoints, then you might
want to make sure that only for ten outgoing requests the answer was cached to not pollute your cash
and grow it infinitely because your space is actually limited and managed by the browser.
So you don't want to cache everything.
So here we could say cache five responses again, for example.
It doesn't matter.
We can then also add max age to define how old should the data in the cache be before we get rid of
it and definitely fetch new data because you might want to fetch from cache first to deliver something
onto the screen as quick as possible and then maybe reach out to more up to date data behind the scenes.
But for dead, you, of course, need to know, is the data and the cache still valid or should I always
fetch new data?
This is defined as a string, which you write like this.
You could say one day or twelve hours or fifty minutes.
This is essentially the format you have.
Details can be found in the official box and you find a link to that attached to this video too.
So you're I'll go with, let's say, six hours and then you can also add a timeout.
The timeout is defined in the same way.
And there you could say, if I'm waiting for a response for, let's say, ten seconds already, then
I want to fall back to the cache and not wait longer.
But I don't want to use the cache immediately.
I want to wait for these ten seconds at least.
So could say ten seconds here.
Last but not least.
And that's important because it works together with the above values, the strategy there you kind of
two types of strategy, freshness, which means always try to reach out to the back end first and only
use the cash if you're offline or performance performance tries to get something onto the screen as
quick as possible and it will take Max age into account.
You know, whether it should absolutely reach out to the back end or just use the cash value on the
apparent freshness will take time out into account to know how long to wait for a response before it
uses to cash.
So I will go with freshness here and I will save this.
And now you know the game.
Let's go back and let's build this again with Dash Dash brought.
And what we should see is that now that we built this, that if we then go back to the built project
and serve it, that is actually ten works in offline mode.
So let's bring up that HP server, reload this page and as I mentioned before, feel free to close it
because a news service worker to be registered should also be able to be loaded without you closing
that tab and opening a new one.
Angler can handle that.
But by default, does this require a default for a new service worker to go active or to turn active
and do its job?
You need to reload the page also because Angular does not use the new updated code.
You might ship onto the server and loaded into your already running app because that might break.
You're already running app so close to tab open a new one now in a new tab reload at least once so that
the API responses can be cached.
The first reload loads the service worker, the second one loads the API responses, then turn off the
Wi-Fi and load again.
And what you should see is that you still got your posts here.
Now one thing you can notice is that the fonts are missing because and that's just something you have
to know about Google fonts.
The way it's loaded, it takes to you or else this is the URL where it goes to and tries to fetch different
than the average URL we put in there is to one which just holds the rules for the font and then that
extra URL.
So let's add that muli gathered information here.
Now replace this at the end here with Star Star to load any funds from the URL close to HSP server and
built this one more time as you saw it before with Energy Bill Dash Dash.
And we could already see that the API data was loaded, at least so that this was present.
Now with this build one more time, let's again go back to our disk folder and let's serve this one
more time.
But then open a new tab for it to become active, reload this one more time to store to make sure that
the responses are really stored.
I should say, and now let's go offline again.
And reload the zap.
And you see the fonts are there, too, and in the network tab, we see everything is fetched, the
posts fail.
But that's the problem because we take that from the cache, which works.
You can see it here.
Response.
There it is.
And this is how we can use the service worker, the angular service worker package, which you can easily
add with the energy add at ANGULAR, a package which includes that service worker package, which also
gives you that manifesto JSON file and which overall is something you have to learn, but then gives
you the powerful tool of making your Web app offline available.
Now check the official docs, which you find attached to the video, of course, and I hope that this
was helpful.