Throughout this course, you learn a lot about angular, of course, the framework, how to build amazing
apps with it and the many features it includes.
Now, what's all the part of Angular and therefore could also call ANGULAR a platform and not just a
framework, is the SEAL, AI and the entire infrastructure it gives you around your projects and around
your code, because the code, of course, is the heart.
The framework allows us to build amazing web applications.
But with the SEAL, AI and the project which is configured and a lot of useful tools around declined
around your projects, you actually also can have a very easy and great time building, publishing,
deploying and managing your angular projects.
And that's exactly what we'll have a closer look at this module in detail.
We'll have a look at Angella Project and the different configuration files again so that we understand
what we really can do there and what their role is.
You will see how you can create and manage projects and many things inside of these projects.
We'll take a look at something which is called Schematics and Builders, which is a set of pretty cool
features, which is included in angular projects at the angular Seelie and which is worth knowing about.
We'll have a look at projects, apps and also how to build libraries, because thus far in this course,
of course, you learned how to build Web applications with ANGULAR.
Now, what have you wanted to build a library that can be used in multiple projects.
That's also something we'll have a look at.
And we'll also have a look at a couple of other things.
For example, at deployment, browser support and much more.
So let's dive in.