And to dive in, let's create a new project now for dad, make sure you are using the latest version
of the Seelie with NPM, install Dashty at a regular Seelie at latest on Mac and Linux.
You might need to add a pseudo in front of this on Windows.
You don't.
Now, once you got that installed, once you got that latest version installed, let's create a brand
new project.
And you know how that works with Injinoo.
Now, actually, before we create such a project, lets it enter here without entering any name.
Now, what you'll see is that if you do that, you actually also are prompted for a project, names
you can also use to command in a shorter way.
Now, let me skip this or cancel this with control.
See for now and type engine you dash, dash, help the dash dash help flac can be used after any command
to learn more about the command at the different configuration options you have available.
So in this case, if I had enter, you see there are a bunch of flags we could add after the command
so we could type engy new some name of our choice and then for example, dash dash collection or dash
dash commit.
And here you see a description of what these configuration flags do.
Now these flags change over time.
New options are added, some options are deprecated.
So going through all of them does make a lot of sense here.
But there are some which I want to draw your attention to this year.
For example, will it become important later?
Create application?
It's set to true by default, so you only need to add it if you want to disable this.
And right now, this doesn't make much sense to us, but will later see why this command can become
very important and useful.
It can become important if you want to manage multiple applications at libraries instead of one angular
Seelie managed project.
Again, more on that later.
Dry run can also be interesting if you just want to see what dcl I would do with your command, with
the engine you command here without actually creating the content on the disk does might sound like
it doesn't make much sense, but if you're passing multiple configuration flags, adding dash dash dry
run will spit out what the CIA will do thereafter so that you can verify whether you will get the project
you want without actually going through the full set up process and writing everything to the disk,
which can be nice at times with inline style and inline templates, you can set up whatever new components
are going to generate will actually start with inline styles or inline templates or with external files.
This can save you the hassle of setting this for every newly generated component individually.
The prefix command allows you to configure the default prefix every new component you generate with
the end you generate command will have.
Now, let me also know that this point that many or most of these options actually can be changed to
the existing project later to and it will show you where to change them and where to generally adjust
the configuration in a separate lecture.
Of course, routing allows you to specify whatever you want to start with a routing module and some
initial routes.
Skip tests allows you to define, however, newly generated components and services and so on will have
testing files next to them.
Skip Install allows you to create a new project with the files written to the disk without the NPM dependencies
being installed.
This speeds up the creation process and you can then always install the dependencies manually later.
So these are some interesting options here and engine you dashers help allows you to go through them
in detail.
In addition, also check out the official documentation and that is true for all the things that will
be showing throughout this module.
I will also reference the official docs from time to time.
There you find the latest up to date information about Angler, the Seelie, the different configuration
files it uses, and for example, here often does Seelie.
You find a list of all the commands it supports the Eleusis so the shortcuts you could use.
And of course, then if you click on a command, you find detailed information about this command,
what it does and which options you can set.
There you see a bit more information about the different configuration options here.
So definitely all the check out these pages here.
If you want to learn more about the Seelie in general or the individual commands with that, let's create
a new project here.
So here I'm going to write engine you angular config and simply hit enter without any additional flags
now than here.
I get asked where I want to add routing and I'll choose N for no here and I'll choose C as as as my
well stylesheet format so that I don't want to use SAS or Eskisehir, which you could do though you
can choose that and then you can write your styles with a style preprocessor like SAS.
Now since I didn't choose to try run or skip install, this creates the full project, installs all
dependencies and writes everything to the disk.
And I'll be back in a new lecture once this is finished.