So here is the project which was created, and I did open it in visuals studio code, which is a free
idea which I can strongly recommend for Angela or for Web development in general.
You find words for every operating system and you can install it and you should see something like this.
Now, I tweaked some settings there.
For example, I installed a special theme here.
I installed the Dakhla theme.
And you can install extensions by going to the extensions area here under the extensions.
And there, for example, if you search for Dacula, you can find that Simmi installed, which of course
is totally optional.
I also installed the material.
I can seem to have Neisser file icons, which is also optional, and this is also optional.
But my recommendation, I also installed the Angular Essentials extension pack by John Papà, which
installs a couple of extensions that make your life as a regular developer much easier in pseudocode.
So I do recommend as angular essentially an extension after installing all of those and activating them
and reloading, you should have a project that looks something like this.
Now, I did add a prettier RC file to configure Prettier, which is the file for Metcher I'm using.
And I set it to use single quotes here.
Basically just how it should auto format my code or the formatting is something you can do with a keyboard
shortcut here.
If you search for format, document this shortcut.
Will auto format your code with a tool of your choice, in my case, prettier, which is part of that
angular essentials package.
And this will make your code easier to read, fix simple errors and simply give you a better time as
a developer.
This is the starting project, therefore, and this is a typical Angella project as it's generated by
the SEAL.
I haven't changed anything in there.
Now, of course, you know this project, right?
We worked in a project like this for the entire course.
We get the source folder with the app folder, and in there we can add our angular components and services
and directives, set everything and write our angular app.
Now, we'll not focus on creating an app in this module.
Instead will focus on the project and what you can do with the app where the seal I can help you, how
you can deploy this and so on.
So therefore, now that we have this basic setup and we understand what we do have here, we also see
we have tons of configuration files here.
So why don't we take a closer look at those to fully understand what the seal I gave us there.