So it's configuration file time, we do have a bunch of files and let's go through them to understand
what we got here.
Now, please note over time some files and the content of some files can change.
But the general idea, of course, is the same.
Now, let's start with the editor config.
This is a file which in the end is picked up by some editors, by some I.D. like stuccoed.
And it basically tells the editor how to, for example, do indentation in this project so that it can
override your user default settings or to the default settings and make sure that the code and this
project actually is the same for all users across the entire world, no matter which ATM they use.
So this is simply a code style thing.
Does, of course, does not affect the way Angouleme works or how you write angular code.
It really just influences how to code looks like and is formatted.
Phrygia RC, by the way, is kind of related to this, but it's not part of a default angler project,
at least not at the point of time.
I'm recording this.
This is a file I added here to tell this auto formatting tool year, which I'm using behind the scenes
to basically use single instead of double quotes.
So in the end, this should work together with Ed config.
Now I skipped git ignore, git ignore.
Of course matters if you're working with git get is a source control tool.
It helps you create code snapshots and go back to older code snapshots.
If you mess, something happens on and you can learn more about get with the attached, get starting
resources and get ignore is a file which basically tells git which files it can ignore, which files
don't want to manage with Git because they will be regenerated frequently like node modules which you
generate by running NPM install and so on.
Now, the angler, Jason Paul, is a bit of a more complex file, this manages your entire project configuration
and it will come back to that in a second.
Let's give it for now and let's move on to the browser's list instead.
The browser's list file is an amazing file.
This configuration file is picked up by the angular Seelie when you build your project for production
and it basically tells the angular Seelie which browsers you want to support with your project.
Now the seal it takes is information about which browsers you want to support.
In my case, you, for example, that I don't want to support Internet Explorer nine to 11, which you
would have to change your remove, not as you see if you do want to support it.
And I will then use this information, for example, to adjust your S.O.S styles and prefix them to
support all these browsers and also to load the right polie files and create the right code bundles
that include those polie files and more on polyphenols and what the Seelie does with them later.
But this really allows you to control which browsers your application supports.
And of course, you want to be as restrictive as possible here and not as open as possible because that
will ultimately lead to less code, which your users have to download.
So if you know you don't have to support Internet Explorer nine to 11, well, you should not supported
the Anglo framework, by the way, does support those browsers, but still excluding them can make sense
to ship less code the kharma config file here.
That's a file which is used for testing in the end for unit tests where angular dangler Seelie uses
kharma behind the scenes.
And unless you really know what you're doing, you should leave it the way it is.
It allows defined you and how your tests are executed and so on.
Package locked.
Jason is a file which is generated based on your package, that Jason file, which in turn is a file
that manages the packages your project uses and the workings of those packages.
Not with my current theme.
I see.
That's a bit hard to read.
So let me quickly switch just to a default dark plus theme where this is a bit easier to read.
Now, what do we have here now?
This package that Jason file has a couple of scripts we can execute.
We can also use just the energy Comando, so we can ignore this behind the scenes.
This uses the energy command.
More interesting are the dependencies and def dependencies.
I did talk about them early and of course, already in the end, these are the third party packages
our project uses to build our application and to run successfully.
That includes all the different parts of the angular framework are exchequers for observables and then
some dependencies of the Angella framework.
But we also got some development dependencies which are tools we only need to build our project.
So this is not code which will be part of our running application.
These will be tools that help us build the application efficiently.
That's the angular Seelie and then a couple of tools used by the Sea Life for compiling and optimizing
the code.
We got Kharma for testing, we got typescript for compiling, typescript to JavaScript and so on.
Now you use this file by running NPM install in the terminal or a command prompt.
Navigate it into your project folder.
And here I'm just using the built in one which you get with terminal new terminal.
And this will basically create that node modules folder based on the dependencies mentioned here.
It will also generate a package to lock Chazen file, which stores the exact workings of your third
party dependencies, because here in packets of choice, you specify some minimum requirements and use
some flexibility.
And then once you do run, NPM install, you lock in certain exact versions which are saved in here.
And last but not least, we got the TIAs config files down there.
Now we see free conflict, adjacent files, descant figures to typescript compiler.
And if you took my understanding, typescript course here in Euterpe, which of course is not a hard
requirement, you know what you can set there?
The official types of documentation, of course, is another great place.
Now, unless you know what you're doing, you can leave the default here.
But there you can set Certa interesting things.
For example, you can add strict mode by setting the SATORU and now typescript will be way more restrictive
regarding what you're allowed to do in your code.
Does can be a pro and can be a con, depending on which kind of code you're writing, how many third
party packages you're using and so on.
It can force you to write cleaner code, but it also sometimes means that you have to find workarounds
to get something to work in typescript, which, you know, will work.
But we're typescript doesn't fully understand your code.
So here you can configure typescript and you have to base configuration file here and then to a specific
configuration files which extend this base configuration file for testing for the testing environment
and for the real app compilation.
And there are some detailed settings can be set for the concrete compilation of the app.
Now, what you'll also see, by the way, is one extra flag, which is not default, typescript, and
that's the angular compiler options.
This is picked up by the angular compiler, which is not the types of compiler, which is the compiler
that kicks in after types compiled your typescript code to JavaScript.
Dangler compiler will then compile your angular application.
So your compile JavaScript code and your HTML template runs on into instructions that can be executed
at runtime.
So instructions to insert buttons and Adam to add event listeners and so on.
So the real DOM instructions that the browser understands, that's what the angular compiler will do.
And you can configure DAT compiler as well.
And unsurprisingly, again, the official docs are a great resource here under def workflow, a Iot
compiler angular compiler options.
You find detailed information about the angular compiler and which options you can set there.
Now, as always, mostly the default will work for you, but you can check out this detailed documentation
here to see whether you need to set some other setting there to build your angular application to where
you want.
And last but not least, we have to Tiercelin Jason file here.
This simply is used for lending, which checks your code quality and basically tells you whether you're
following best practices.
And you wrote your code in a good way.
Does if you get errors here, these are not real errors.
These are just approvement recommendations on how you could improve your code, though, of course,
sometimes there all just is a recommendation which you don't have to follow because not all these recommendations
are best practices.
Some simply are.
Opinions which you don't have to share.
So this is what we have here in terms of configuration files.
Now let's again think about some angular Seelie commands before we dive into that missing configuration
file, Dangler Jason File.