So before we explore, does Angler not Jason fall, let's see which angler Seelie commands we can use
inside of a project we used, Engie knew outside of it.
Now we can basically use all remaining commands inside of it.
Now you can type energy help here, not engy Dash does help, but just engy help to learn about all
the commands.
And of course, as mentioned, you have that page in the official documentation.
They're under seal commands.
You'll also see all the commands.
Now, some commands are really niche commands, which you really need, but of course there are also
some commands which you'll need all the time, for example, and you serve, you know, this one, it
serves your application now just as before.
If you add dash to help thereafter, you get details about this command and you can see there are quite
some flags you can set.
Now, not all of these flags are required.
Of course, the defaults work just fine.
But for example, you can set a port flag here to use a different port than the default of four thousand
two hundred.
You can add Dasht as Pirot to actually serve your app in production mode, to have kind of an idea of
how it will work once you do build it for production.
This, however, is not something you can use on a real web server.
It's not production ready.
It's just a preview of how production mode will work.
You also have dash dash open.
This will actually tell these Seelie to not only served yet, but to open the app in a new browser tab
once it's done, serving it up so so that you don't have to manually open it there and so on.
There are a bunch of configuration options you can set there.
Again, most of them are rarely needed, but if you do need them, well, here they are.
As mentioned over time, they might change.
But still, this command and the official docs here are a great place to learn more about them.
Now, besides energy surf, we also got engy generate an energy generate with Dashty to help.
Allows us to generate things in our application.
Here are the things we can generate.
You saw a couple of them from the course like component's directive's, but you could also generate
guards or services.
You could generate tie pipes or modules, interfaces and interest setters for the be client, an application,
which is something I'll come back to and some neat things like a service worker or a web worker.
You also see additional flags here, but to see all the available flags, you should be a bit more specific.
And for example, say energy, generate component, dash, dash help to see how you can configure degeneration
of a component.
And there you see that there are again a bunch of configuration options.
Now, this might, by the way, be overwhelming by now.
But keep in mind that you don't have to learn those by heart.
The defaults will work just fine in most situations.
Just when you find that a default doesn't work for you, you might want to look into these configuration
flags here and see whether you can change the default to give you the component or whatever you're trying
to generate in the way you want it.
For example, to not use inline styles, to not use inline templates to change the default prefix,
which is added to not generate test files and so on.
And of course, this does not just exist for the component generation, but for pipes and so on.
So you generate, of course, is an important command engine.
Lind uses this Tiercelin I mentioned before.
It will now basically go through your entire setup and tell you if you have any LINTANG errors in here,
everything past.
But for example, if I go to the app component here and I do remove this prefix app route and I wouldn't
list again, it should tell me about this.
So let's wait for this to finish.
And indeed, it found lint error and now it tells you that in the app component fall in line for here,
these electors should be Kabab case and include a dash.
So it tells me that I'm not following this recommended practice of naming my components like this.
So that's limiting.
And you can always use this little command from time to time to check your code.
Quality energy bill, of course, is all that important.
Command to build your project with Dash Dash brought you build it for production so you'll optimize
it as much as possible.
And you also saw before in this course in the deployment section that this will generate ADESTE folder
where you find your generated project files, which you then can put onto a server to well serve your
application from there and to really serve your application to all the users out there in the world.
So here is this, this folder.
Now, I will come back to deployment a little bit later, you learned how you can deploy it, but actually
there is a different way of deploying with help of DCI and that's mentioned.
I will come back to that for now.
Let's ignore it.
So these are these Seelie commands.
And again, I pointed at it before, but check out the official docs to learn about all the commands
and all the configuration options.
There are some commands like Engy Update and add an entry deploy, which will have a closer look in
this module, though.
Before we do that, let's analyze the angler, Jason Valdo, because dad configures our project in the
end, and thus far we didn't have a close look yet.