So what's inside of the Angler Jason file?
This is a file which is generated automatically when you generate a new angle, a project, and this
is used by the CSI behind the scenes to run different Seelie commands and to know how to run these commands.
Basically here you can set some defaults for all these flags you could otherwise add manually to every
command.
And of course, setting defaults is more appropriate because it saves the hassle of having to add all
these flags all the time.
So what do we have in their notice?
Angler Jason File uses, well, the Jason data format to well store its information.
And there it follows a certain schema which is developed by the Angler team, and it's stored in this
folder, not something we should change, just some information.
The wording here, you can leave this the way it is.
This is just the wording of this file format here.
Basically interesting is the new project route entry into this controls where new projects in your project
here in the end are added.
This might not tell you much what our project will come back to that it turns out that you can manage
more than one project in an Angler Project folder.
And thus far, for the entire course, we always had just one project, one app.
While you can manage more, that will show you how later.
And of course, for now, let's go with that one project.
So next, we have this project's entry.
And dear, you have one nested entry per project.
Now, as I mentioned, we have one project here.
And therefore, if I make the smaller we see, there only is one entry.
And that also, you see, is the default project against which our SEAL commands will run.
If you had multiple projects, again, something that will show you later, then you could specify here
which project the Seelie commands like Engy generations on will run against.
But here we only have one.
So let's expand this again.
Now we see which project type does this.
And here it's an application.
Now you have multiple types.
Here you have application and library.
And by the way, you get all the completion, you're either automatically or by hitting controlled space.
The default is application, which is a regular angler web application.
But you could change this to library and it will show you what a library is later in this module.
For now, let's leave it at application that we get the schematics here.
Schematics doesn't tell us much about.
Schematics actually is a really cool feature of the angular ecosystem, you could say.
And we'll come back to what schematics are for now.
Let's ignore it.
Route basically tells the angular Seelie what the root folder of this project is.
And here it's the file folder here itself.
So the entire folder and then where our source files live in.
And you could change this if you want to store your code in a different folder than source, but I will,
of course, leave it at source.
But you can change this here.
You set the default prefix, which is added in front of every component.
So if you don't want to use app, you can use a different one here.
And then you get this architect command here it is architect area, which is the rest of our project
specific settings.
Now here to different commands you can execute can be configured.
For example, the build command.
There you see which tool gets used under the hood.
And this is a tool which is part of the angular deficit package, which is one of the third party.
Dependencies, we have added.
And this basically is just the tool, the configuration to code, which knows how to build an angle,
a project so which steps to execute and so on.
And this tool can be configured with options.
These are options.
You also, at least partly, can set with these extra configuration flags on Seelie commands.
So on energy build, dash, dash Iot, for example, controls that should be built with ahead of time
compilation and by default, as is true.
So you would only need to set this if you want to set it to false, but you can set this with a flag
or if you notice, should always be the case here.
For example, with that Iot option there you see the default is true.
But if I set it to false now, all bills would be done with the Iot computation turned off.
We see where the project should be output into, and here we see that is to this folder and then the
angle of conflict subfolder we see what our route entry Phylis.
And you could change this, of course, what the route entry filed for the angular application is.
And you could change this as well where the poley fields are managed.
You can change this as well.
You can change everything here.
And what's your project?
Specific configuration, faulty conflict configuration files.
Assets allows you to configure which files or folders should be copied over in the output in the source
folder.
We have a assets folder in there.
I have nothing in there.
But if you would store, let's say, an image in there, which I always want to be able to use in my
application, I could store it here, reference it from inside my components, for example, by rendering
image tag there and it would be copied over into the disk folder so that it is available in the served
app as well.
The styles node is one we use for all this, of course, project to include bootstrap.
Here you can set up which S.O.S files ever your old ones or third party package files should be included
in the application by default.
Of course, every component has its own style file, as you learned.
But if you have some global application wide styles, you would add them here.
And these style files are also then used and evaluated by the build workflow and in the end optimized
and copied over.
For example, here you find you copied over Styles's as file, which is empty for the Stiefel project.
But where you could add your default styles here is to file where you would add your styles.
So that is something.
And if you have some scripts, some Java scripts, some JavaScript files which should be copied over,
you could specify them as well.
Now, you might not need this very often because you will write most of your logic inside of your angular
files, of your angular components and so on.
But if you would be using a third party package like, let's say, Google Maps or Lodish or anything
like this, where you may be downloaded, already optimized script file, well, then you can just specify
it here and it will be copied over and included in your application.
Now a side note already more about all these configuration options, of course, can again be learned
in the official docs there under workspace configuration.
You learn about all these settings in great detail and what you can set there and why and in which different
ways you can configure things here.
So in addition to watching this lecture, this is a resource you also might want to check out to learn
everything about what you could possibly do here.
Now, besides the options for the command, you also find configurations this might sound like it's
the same, but the difference is that options basically are default options, which are always applied
with configurations.
You can configure different environments for your options.
So you could say, I want to have some steps or some options which are only taken into account if I
build for production, for example, or if I build for development.
So here we got some production specific settings, for example, that a file should be replaced.
This isn't the environments folder.
And in the end, this simply tells you, Seelie, that it should swap the environment useful for the
environment.
Proteus file when it builds for production.
This allows you to specify different environment variables in the end for the different productions
you're building for.
So let's say you're using Google Maps and you have a Google API key and you have one key for development
and one key, which is more locked down and restricted for production.
Then you would store the development Key India Environments File and the production key in the environment
of Proteus file.
And thanks to this setting here, once you built for production, which you do with energy Bill Dash
Dash.
Brought this configuration will be used and the files will be swapped so that for your production code,
your production key will be used, a little side note dashed as broad as just a shortcut to target production.
The long form is stashed at configuration equals production.
Now, for production just doesn't make much sense because you have the shortcut.
But you can add your own configurations here like a staging configuration.
You can add it and overwrite your own options here if you want to with staging.
So now here I could set my own options like a hottie to falls if I'm building for staging.
And I could target this custom option with configuration staging now so you can add your own configuration
stear besides the default ones which are included.
And as you just saw here with the Atik sample, you can override any default options configured up there.
So these defaults are always used unless they're overwritten down there.
And here you see for production, there are quite some overwrites or some extra settings.
For example, here we have the maximum amount of optimizations and so on.
And you can, of course, find you tweaked us all to your personal liking.
You can add more environments as you learned, and you can configure which options are adjusted, in
which way, for which environment.
It's a really, really powerful.
Now, this is all still for the build command right now.
Let's close this and move on to the server command.
Now, there you see options is much shorter because here we have one main option where we basically
tell these Seelie that for Disserve option, we want to use to build options.
So all these options should be used for a serve as well.
And then we also have this production specific configuration.
If we would if we would run engy serve Dasht as Pirot.
Now, in case you're wondering how you should ever know which options exist, for one, as I mentioned,
you get all the completion here.
If you add new empty quotes, you see which settings you can set there.
And in addition to the official docs I mentioned guide you through that and you can learn more about
the different options there.
Now, then we got an option for internationalization, which I'll ignore.
Here we got the test options for running your tests and how your code should be compiled and used there.
We can configure lintang end to end testing and then we're done.
And this is the angular jasen file.
It can look intimidating, but as always, the defaults are fine for most use cases.
And if you need to tweak something, you got all the completion.
You can check out the official docs to learn more about that.
Now, I want to come back to something I mentioned earlier schematics because it turns out that schematics
this term is super important and helps us build amazing applications.