What are Angler Seelie schematics, schematics are a powerful tool or a concept introduced by the Angler
team or specifically by the Angler SEAL team schematics are basically blueprints which certain angler
commands can pick up.
And, for example, you can have schematics for and generate to generate new building blocks in your
app like components for Engy Add, which we hadn't had a closer look at yet for adding, for example,
libraries or certain capabilities to a project and energy update for keeping a project up to date,
you can build your own schematics.
Angular has some built in schematics which you have unlocked by default, and the angular Seelie and
third party packages can also add schematics.
And that's what makes this feature powerful.
Now, adding your own schematics, of course, a super powerful because you could build your own blueprints,
your own energy, generate command for generating, let's say, a specific version of a component which
you need all the time.
But let me also say that building your own schematics is not trivial.
If you search for angular schematics, you will find an introduction on the official angle, angular
block and also something the official documentation.
And there you also have this offering schematics, part where you learn how to build your own schematics.
It is fairly introductory, but it might be a nice start.
If you want to learn all about that.
It will be a lot of trial and error, though.
And I can also recommend checking out some third party applications schematics because that's what I
now want to focus on.