You might know angular material, it's a third party package actually also maintained by parts of the
angular team, but totally optional.
It adds components.
So pre-built components to your angular app, which follow the material design, spec and material design
as a design language invented by Google.
It looks the way this page looks like now.
You can check out components here and see which components this offers.
And this is, of course, not the focus of of this module here, but there you can get nice pre-built
components, which you can then easily drop into your application to use them there.
Now, if you click on Get Started, we see that we can run one simple command to add angular material
to our project.
Now, let's copy this command and give it a try.
Let's head over to our project, and there I will run energy at at angler's material and angular material
is not the only package which supports the energy at command.
Every third party package can support it, no matter if it's built by the angler team or not.
And there are a lot of third party packages out there.
For example, Ionic, which do support it now to support these packages, need to include certain configuration
files in their package source code.
In the end, an energy add will look for these files and if it finds them, it is able to run.
Now, these files, which these packages have to include dental energy, add what to do and let's see
what energy it does with angular material.
Lets it enter.
And now you see as a first step, it installs packages through NPM.
Now, this is not all it will do though, but it's one part of what it does.
It will install all packages you need to install to use angular material.
That's the angular material package itself, but also some third party dependencies.
This package needs then some packages or some tools might prompt you for certain choices you have to
make, not all.
Some have some definite steps which to always execute.
Here, for example, we can choose a default theme with which we want to start.
And here I'll go for Deep Purple and Amber.
We can also choose if you want to use hammocks for gesture recognition.
And it will choose.
Yes.
Also at Browsr animations with yes, so did we have all these nice animations and hit Enter and now
you see it again updates the package that Jason followed because it now installs more dependencies end.
And that's the interesting part.
It did not just installs on packages, so it's not just a replacement for NPM install.
It also updated some other files.
It updated the main TIAs file, the app module angler Jason, the index age HTML file and style cyesis.
So why don't we have a look at all these files to understand what Engy ad did?
And let's start with Maintenace in May.
And yes, you see it added to import for Hammer, which is a third party package that helps us with
gesture detection.
And that is it actually.
In the index HTML file, you see it included some Google fonts, the material icons in the end, and
the Raboteau font which it uses.
So that is an adjustment.
It made their.
In the app module, if we have a look there, it actually ad at the browser animations module from angular
animations because some angular material components use animations and of course, those animations
should work in these style us as file.
You see it set some default styles for your website, like a default fund, for example.
And in angler Jason there, let's see what a changed there.
There you see that, for example, under the built command, it now also includes our theme stalls so
that our theme is picked up when we build for production.
So that's the end ad schematic, pretty useful for third party packages that support it because it does
not just install the penances and package Jason it all the fastest, but not just instead.
Besides doing that, it also makes a couple of adjustments specified by the third party package that
need to be made so that you can immediately start using this installed third party package.
Now, I did mention and generate and engy update as well.
What do these schematics do?