Now, let's start with Engy generate, we know engy generate, right, we can use it in any angle,
a project that is because Angular and or Seelie has some default blueprints included, for example,
for generating a component, for generating a pipe, a service and so on.
So these are basically schematics or support for the energy generate schematic that is already built
in.
But you could add your own and third party packages can also add their own, not just for energy add,
but also for energy generate.
For example, with angular material installed here, we can run and generate.
At Angler's Materials, basically the name of the schematic provider by default, if you leave this
empty, it's the default Selya, the default angular set up, but you can override it and use a different
one in this case to a material package.
Colen then a name of a supported schematic, and there, for example, NARTH, and of course, in the
official docs of Anglo material.
In this case, you learn all about the energy generate schematics it added and you can use.
So here we can use NARTH and then Aname where we want to create our, in this case, navigation set
up.
And if I had entered now this uses to generate schematic provided by angular material and it adds a
new component.
So under the hood it probably uses energy generator component, but it adds a new component which is
not empty, but which has a different default blueprint in this case.
You see, it has a blueprint where we have a side navigation controller, a toolbar, a button, and
then also can show some content here, like maybe in a main block, a simple H2 header.
This works.
And now let's include this main NAF component here in app component.
Let's use Main NAV like this.
Make sure that an app module, this was added to declarations.
And if we now run engy serve, you will see a nice navigation which works out of the box using angular
material components.
Thanks to this custom schematic, this energy generates schematic added by the angle of material package.
And you could build something like this on your own as well if you wanted to.
But as I mentioned, a lot of third party package to support it.
So this adds on to the default schematics you already have in an angular project.
And of course, here we got an error because it's not made.
Now, of course, its app, Main NEF.
Right.
We can, of course, check the these Lechter here.
So little oversight from my side.
Let me fix this, an app component.
And after fixing this, if you visit, localhost four thousand two hundred.
We get this nice little application here, we're of course, not much is happening, but where we now
could build up on to build an application.
So this is the end.
You generate schematic and what you have built into the I and a Devil project and how third party packages
as well as yourself could add new blueprints to it.