Now, besides energy generate, we also have energy update and energy update is one of the coolest commands
you can find.
Of course, you want to keep your application up to date.
And thankfully, when Angella releases a new version, typically not everything changes.
So typically updating is fairly trivial.
Still, you might have to update a couple of dependencies and package Jason, and maybe there are one
or two smaller adjustments you need to make in code, maybe very simple ones, but still repetitive
ones like adjusting a certain import, adding a new setting on a decorator, something like this.
Now, energy update can be executed like this in a project and it will analyze it and tell you if there
is something that needs to be updated.
And for that, it basically checks every package which supports this schematic.
Of course, all angular packages supported Dangler, Seelie itself supports it.
And, for example, some third party packages like angular material, all the supported.
Now you see here, everything is up to date for me, but if something would not be up to date, it would
show you a table and tell you how you can update.
Now, for example, then you can run commands like energy update at.
At Angular Corps at Angular Seelie to update the angular framework packages, this will actually target
all packages, not just a core package and the angular Seelie package to bring it up to date and run
any migration's.
So any adjustments that might need to be made.
So DISCOM makes updating super, super simple.
And again, if you run just engy update, you will see a table of commands you should run in case your
project is not entirely up to date.
So Engie Update is a command, which is the word for running after every new angular version that was
released to quickly bring your project up to date and ensure that it works with this latest version.
Manually updating wouldn't be that hard.
But of course with Engy update, it gets even easier.
And these are the three important schematics we have here now.
We also have something which is called builders.
And what's that?