We explored schematics.
Now we also have builders, what are builders schematics basically are the tools you run to add something
to your project.
We did a third party library or with generate a new component or maybe just an update with builders.
You can well build your application for different environments.
There are some built in builders and you build and you test insulin's d basically all execute your code,
compile your code analyzer code and then for example, optimize it for production, run tests on it,
or simply tell you how good your code quality is.
So you perform smart build steps there.
There also is another builder and that is Engy Deployer.
This takes it to the next level.
It will also build your project for production, but then also already go ahead and deploy it to a certain
host.
Of course, only some hosts are support there.
It's basically like with Engy at there needs to be a third party package or tool which supports energy
deploy so that you can deploy to a host.
These are automation commands which you also can customize ever by writing your own builder or a deployment
builder, which is pretty advanced, or by hooking into the configuration and adjusting those builders.
Well, let's take a closer look now.
As always, the official documentation is a good place to go.
And there you will see another deployment.
You can learn more about deployment and also about.
Engy deploy.
Here, under automatic deployment with the Seelie, you can learn more about that, and here you also
see the currently supported packages or services which supports the energy supply command.
I'll come back to that.
So this is something you can look into and of course, something we already had a look at an angler.
Jason, you can configure some of these boulders like the Energy Build Command.
Now, we had a look at energy build and energy tests throughout this course.
We saw Angie Lind earlier here and I talked about this configuration.
So that's something we covered.
Let's focus on energy deploy.
Therefore, as mentioned, you can either, of course, deploy manually as we did it in the deployment
section or you utilize to see if you plan on using one of these services that supports the engine deployment.
And here I want to use angular fire, which in the end simply uses Firebase under DOD.
Angle of fire is a package that makes working with Firebase way easier, not just when it comes to deployment,
but also when it comes to interacting with the database, so on.
But we didn't use it in this course because it's not a firebase, cause I only used Firebase as a dummy
back.
And still I want to show you how it is and to deploy command could work.
So first of all, we need to add at Angular Fire to our project.
Why do we need to add this?
Because only after adding this D deploy command supports angle of fire.
How would it otherwise know that it can use this?
Right.
So we first of all have to engie at that angle of fire.
And just as with angular material, this will not just install the package, but also make any adjustments
which are required and install any other dependencies it might need.
So let's wait for this to finish.
Now, you'll see as part of me installing this or adding this, I am asked to select a firebase project.
And indeed, here you need a firebase project.
You probably do have one if you followed through this course.
If you don't have one, make sure you sign into Firebase for that, you need a Google account using
Firebase and is free as long as you stay within certain boundaries, which are quite generous.
So sign in there and create a new firebase project once you created that rerun engie ad at a live fire
and Schuster's Command.
Now, important, if you're getting any errors here, you also might want to install the firebase tools
globally, firebase dash tools on Mac and Linux with a pseudo in front of it.
And once you did install those tools.
Run Firebase, log in to log into your firebase account and thereafter try and get at a regular fire.
Now, with that, this will add a couple of configuration files here, some firebase configuration files,
and now the neat thing is we can simply run and deploy now and it should automatically pick up at angle
of fire as a deployment option.
You see, it now compiles to code because it runs the entire build process in production mode.
What we normally would do manually dust is here as well, but then it will not stop thereafter.
Instead, it will take to build assets, to build files and ship them onto a server.
So let's wait for this to finish.
Here is finished building this.
We can ignore the warning and now it's uploading the files to Firebase to Firebase Project.
And once it's finished, it also generated all the hosting configuration files here.
Once it finished, we get a you are all here, which we can enter into the browser.
And there we see our simple angular application.
Now, you can then administer this application both with this configuration file, the Firebase Jason
File, and you can always redeploy it by running end deploy again or of course, all the from inside
your firebase console.
And there you could all connect a different domain with it if you wanted to.