So now that we talked about deployment, let me come back to the browser's list, I mentioned that this
is important for telling ANGULAR which browsers you want to support.
And this, of course, is related to deployment.
ANGULAR will take the information here to auto prefix your Sears's code correctly, but also so that
it knows which poorly fields to load and which different versions of bundles it should generate.
And what do I mean by that?
Angular has a built in feature called Differential Loading.
Now we have our Angella app and we're hosting this, let's say on Firebase or HWC as free or any other
hosting provider.
No matter if we used energy apply or not, we're hosting it somewhere and now our app hopefully gets
visited by users.
We might have user AI who has a modern browser and user B who has a legacy.
So an older browser.
Now the thing is user A with a modern browser, let's say the latest version of Chrome or Firefox needs
no or less polie fills.
All the features we use will work there just fine and therefore we could ship a smaller code bundle
to the user because our code doesn't have to be compiled down to super old versions of JavaScript and
we might not need any or all polie filters.
So these packages which enable certain features in a browser user, on the other hand, needs a version
which is compiled down to way older code, and he or she needs all or at least more polie fildes add.
So a bigger bundle needs to be shipped.
It is what it is.
The problem is, of course, we can always ship a bigger bundle so that we support both B and A if we
always ship the most optimized and smallest bundle possible, we ignore a user.
B there just just won't run with differential loading.
We do both.
The Angler's Seelie actually produces multiple versions of your app when it builds it for production,
you could say, and it produces a small code file which runs first when a user visits your page to identify
which browser does user is using.
And then this small initial code file determines which bundle gets served to the user.
So with differential loading user using, a modern browser has to download less code than a user using
an older browser.
And this gives you the best of both worlds.
You support all users, but you make sure that every user just has to download the code it really needs.
And this is built into ANGULAR.
In our disk folder, we actually see two versions of every file, right to main to polie files and to
runtime files.
And you see the names are different.
IA's five basically is the word before the users with the older browsers.
E 2015 sounds similar, but it's totally different.
Uses way more recent JavaScript and Dhafer also will be smaller for polie fills.
It's the same, of course, here.
They both look very cryptic and large, but actually the more modern version will be smaller and the
same for the runtime here.
So these are all files that you deploy and they will be executed automatically and indexed HTML indeed
to runtime file executes first and there it then decides which Aybar files it needs to load.
So that's how this works.
So desistance differential loading feature, which you get out of the box and you do partly configure
it here with the browser list there you tell Angella which browsers you want to support and distils
angular how it should build an optimized these different bundles.
In addition, you have a setting in TIAs config, Jason, where you specify to target JavaScript where
you want to compile for, and here it's compiling for modern JavaScript.
If you set this to an older one, then you force are all users to use this older one.
So differential loading really just is a feature to be aware of, not something where you need to do
much.
You have it out of the box.
And this allows you to ship code that works for all users but does not force all users to download all
available code.
All in one word about polie files.
You've got this polie Felicitas file now.
Crucial polie fildes like this one are included by default.
Simply by having this import statement here, Angella will do the rest.
If you are using certain features like, let's say, animations, and you need to support browsers which
don't natively support them, specifically Internet Explorer or Safari, then you would need to comment,
as in and Ronda's NPM install command to make sure your angular animations all work in those browsers.
So it always comes down to which browsers you want to support.
And you see detailed instructions here inside of this Polli Felicitas file.
So this is how you ensure that your app works for everyone and how you automatically take advantage
of this differential loading.
Of course, as always, you learn a bit more about this here.
The official talks under deployment, you can learn more about the French loading and how it works and
why it's awesome.