And with this, we're done with managing our application.
Now, there is so much you can do, but you hopefully got a good overview of the different features
and the ecosystem here.
Now, want to come back to one thing I mentioned earlier, multiple projects.
Now, I mentioned that inside of a singular project or folder, I should say, you can have multiple
projects.
Now, you start with one project, but you can actually add a new one with energy generate and then
you can generate one of two project types, a library or an application.
Now, let's start with an application here, if I type and generate application, and I may be named
as backend because let's say I have my back end UI for my administrators and a front end UI for my end
users, if I hit enter here, this will go ahead.
And ask me the same questions I got when I created this project where I want to add routing and which
Stolle preprocessor I want to use, and now you see it adds a new project folder here.
And in that project's folder, it has this subfolder named backend, which is the name I chose, which
basically has a new angular project in it, a bit slimmer because they share the same root angular Jason
file and package jasen file here, but it's own dedicated config files, its own source folder.
And in there basically what we already know, this is a separate, angular application.
Now we could surface which with engy serve and then project equals backend.
This is important of course otherwise and you wouldn't know that it should use this project.
You can set the default project.
Angular serve were engie serve for any other command will use in the angler Jason file there.
At the very bottom you have this default project setting which in my case is set to my starting project,
angular config.
And if you set this then engy server for engy build without any extra FLAC will always run against this
project here.
I ran it against backend.
So unsurprisingly, if I visit localhost 4200, I now see this brand new project backend being served
here.
Now you could argue that this is an ugly project structure, though.
Having a projects folder as part of our other main project.
I'm not too happy with this.
Well, we can do better.
Let's go back to the main terminal and to the folder where we create our new angle, a project, and
now let's create a new one.
Engine new.
And now let's say we're building a singular shop, but it's totally up to you.
Does this just a dummy name?
Now, you might remember that there is Tarshish help, which you can use to run some commands.
And there was a create application FLAC.
And I will set this here to false.
Now, if we now run this, something interesting will happen, it now will generate some files, but
actually less files than before.
It will installs on the penances, but it will not create a brand new angle or application by default.
Instead, let's wait for this to finish and see what it gives us instead.
Once it finishes, it gives us a folder that looks like this.
So we have to config files.
We know, but of course the app folder is missing and now indeed here we can simply run and generate
application, for example.
Back end.
And what it will do now is it will create that new projects folder thereafter and create it in their.
So you see, here it is, so now we have to cleaner structure, which is nice if you have multiple angular
projects in one root folder.
Now every project will have its own subfolder in the projects folder, which I would argue is cleaner
than what we had before.
So in case you want to work with multiple projects instead of one angular managed folder, this is how
I would recommend that you do it.
Create the project with engine you your name and then dash, dash, create dash applications set to
false enter after.
Add your different applications with the energy generate comment.
Now, although of course you cannot just generate applications.
So Web applications, you can also generate libraries.
Let's take a closer look at that.