To create a library, we run and generate library, an alternative to application.
In this case, let's say my button, because it's an amazing library where I will share my own custom
button component, which every other application should be able to use.
And that's maybe important.
What is a library?
A library differs from an application such that you still write angular code and there you still build
angular components and so on.
You can grouped them with modules, you can add directive's.
That does not change, but it's not meant to run standalone as a web application.
Instead, it's meant to have some code that can be shared across multiple angular web applications.
So something like angular material, angular material is angular library.
It comes with a bunch of built in components and you can use these components in any application.
So this is an angular library and you can build your own.
Now, we already made our first steps by creating it with the energy generated library command.
You see, you generally get the same as before, but there are some differences.
For example, we have the energy packaged adjacent file, which in the end allows us to configure this
library in a certain way.
In the source folder we see we have a public API, its file, where we in the end export to different
things that make up our library.
And in the lit folder we got some starting files, for example, on my button component where we can
write our own library component already added to a module and also a service, which you can or cannot
use now to learn all about library creation.
Of course, as always, the official docs are your friends.
Under technique's Angella libraries creating libraries, you can learn all about creating and also deploying,
publishing your own custom libraries to NPM for dad.
You will also need that NPM account, though.
So this is in the end something you can also do.
And building a library really is straightforward here.
For example, I could build my own custom button, which of course is super amazing there.
I will use energy content so that users can pass in anything they want between my custom button tax
and that's it.
So of course, the most amazing button in the world has no stall's, no extra features.
You absolutely need this library.
Now, with that, we already would have a very basic library, which we now can configure.
And again, the official docs can help you there to learn about how to exactly configure this.
And with this, we are also able to build libraries and share them across even our own angular applications
or also publish them to them to share them with others.