And this is it for this module.
Now, there is always more you can cover, but I've found it important to all to point you at the official
docs so that you know where you can dive deeper if something is unclear or you are interested in one
specific features, because Angela is a huge topic.
It's the framework.
And then as you saw in this module, decentered Seelie ecosystem thing.
That's why, as some people refer to ANGULAR as a platform, because it's more than just the framework,
it's also all these extra tools and helpers and features.
And this ecosystem, of course, also keeps on evolving, which is why the official docs are a great
resource to dive into the specific features you might be interested in.
Now, of course, discourse is about angular, the framework and how we build web applications with
it.
That always was the heart of the course and that is honestly what most developers are interested in.
You want to learn how to write and build angular applications, but if you want to take your knowledge
to the next step and maybe get a bit more productive with all these Seelie commands with deployment,
with maybe custom schematics and so on, then this module hopefully showed you what you can do there,
where you can learn more and how to read all these configuration files, how to use all these commands,
how to manage your projects.
So I hope this was helpful.