In this video, we'll do just that, we'll load an angular component.
Well, this would be pretty boring, so we'll do it an exciting way.
We'll load it dynamically as a custom element, as a native Web component, instead of a normal angular
component.
What's great about that and how does it work?
Let's take a closer look at this and this video.
So let's get started with angular elements.
What is angular elements?
It's a feature of the angular framework that allows you to turn your normal angular components which
you use in your angular app into native web components.
Web components are basically custom HTML elements.
You could say they are part of the of the Darmouth JavaScript API.
They're not related to ANGULAR and you can use them in vanilla JavaScript apps or ID apps built with
our frameworks.
So that's Web components and that is what you can create with angular elements.
Now before you get too excited right now at the point of time releasing this video when ANGULAR six
was released, the web components are building with angular can only be used and angular projects still.
And the obvious question then is why would you build web components at all?
What is the use of angular elements if you can only use these elements inside of an angular app?
And the answer is they are useful for loading dynamic content.
So let's say you got a content management system on your back and on a server and there your editors
can create HTML code.
They know how to write HTML code and therefore they create the content that gets loaded into your angular
app in HTML.
Now so far that is fine, but what if you actually want to enable them to also use some of your angular
components in the HTML code they prepared?
If they do that, if they use your angular components selectors and you then load does content dynamically
in your angular app, it will actually not work because your angular app is compiled ahead of time or
even with Just-In-Time computation, it's compiled before the content is loaded.
So if the content contains these elector of angular element of angular component, this will not work.
It will not recognize that.
Let me show you what I mean.
Here's a brand new angular project created with the angular Seelie important if we check the package.
Jason General, I'm using angular version six and I'm using our test version six.
And I installed Dietrich's task complete package to have no issues with our extras.
This might be needed at the point of time recording this.
I need it for the Angular Elements package which will use in the future.
You might not need this.
All angular packages should by default, support your Express Syntex.
If you want to learn more about what changed with Angular six and why does Agricultures six thing is
so important?
Check out these separate videos I created on that.
My Angular six update video NTR Extra six update video.
But back to the angular components.
Let's create a new component.
Let's name it a large component, maybe a normal angular component.
So in there I'll expert a class alert.
Component like this, and of course, we could create that with the Seelie to all imported component
decorator and then they're all defined My Selecter, which is app alert, let's say, and a template
which could be, of course, an external file, too.
But here I'll simply add a diff.
And inside of the diff I'll say this is an alert and then we even output a message here.
So some string interpolation.
Last but not least, I'll add my Stults array here with a string in there to define some styles for
this template.
And there I simply want to start Maldive, give it up border of one pixel solid and lieke background
of, let's say, Salmen.
So this is like red color and a padding of 10 pixels.
And last but not least, let me also define a font family and segment, by the way, should not be a
string.
Let me to find a font family of sans serif.
Now this is my my style for the for the alert.
Now the alert uses this message property.
So I have to add it here and I want to make this bendable from outside, so decorated with that input
which I have to import from angular court.
And now with that the component is finished and we can now use it to use it.
We have to add it to our declarations are right there.
I add my alert component and with it added here we can go to the app component to its HTML file to be
precise.
And then there we can use my newly created app alert component like this.
And of course also pass a message which since its string can be passed like this without the square
brackets.
This is just a shortcut in case you are passing some text.
And there I could say this is a normal angular component.
With that, if we save all these files and we go back, we see our component there.
Now, the styling didn't work.
Yeah, I should add more semicolons instead of commas with that, now we got this alert.
So this is a normal, angular component.
Now, let's say in the app component, we actually want to load this dynamically.
I got this content property there.
It's null initially.
And now let's say instead of outputting this component like this, we have a death.
And on this death, we use the inner HTML property binding to bind to the content in the app component
in the constructor.
For simplicity reasons.
I can then add my timeout just to simulate that this is an asynchronous task and we're getting this
from a server.
We don't have to put it into a timeout.
We can also run this code once does loads.
Just adding this to well, give us a little bit of time to prepare for the data to arrive, I guess.
And in that function that executes here in set timer, I now want to set this content to, let's say,
a string that holds HTML paragraph.
So this is all obviously not using our element.
I just want to show you that this works.
We're now rendering this paragraph.
If we inspect it, we see a paragraph surrender to the DOM because we're using in our HTML.
Now would be great if we could use our own element there.
So if we could use app alert here, like this app alert.
And now we also set a message of.
Rendered dynamically, dynamically, because we don't include it in our component template, we are
not including it in the app component HTML file, but here were hard coding it into our code.
But we could easily imagine that this is coming from an API call, that we're fetching this from a server.
So if we do it like this and then we reload our app, we can wait forever.
We won't see anything here.
And if we inspect our approved, we see that the def indeed is empty.
So nothing gets rendered here.
And the reason for this is that this is rendered as HTML code, but it's not recognized as an HTML element.
Appleford is not a built in element.
It's our own component.
But that exactly is what I meant.
Angular will not consider this after it has loaded our app because the compilation of the templates
and therefore the part where it understands your components.
Electra's is already done by that point of time.
And this doesn't change if we remove this from set time out and execute it right at the beginning of
this component.
So we don't see anything ever.
So this is not the reason.
The reason indeed is that ANGULAR doesn't compile this code and angular elements fixes this issue or
this problem.
You could say it allows us to basically take our angular component and put it into a totally encapsulated,
self bootstrapping HTML element, which you can dump into your angular app in this way, for example,
and which will still work.
Now, how do we create such a component?
We need to install angular elements and you can already see that I added an import up here, create
custom element.
This has been lurking around for a while and it seems to be what we need now.
Make sure that you install the angular elements package with NPM, install Daschner safe at Angular
Elements just in case this isn't installed already.
I'm recording this with a beta version, but of course.
But a point of time you're watching is it probably was released as part of the normal angular framework.
So once this is installed, you should also ensure that especially for the beta version might not be
a problem in later versions, that you got our task complete because this is required for this to run
at least right now.
And very important that you add this line to your packaged adjacent file.
This is a polyfoam which right now also is required for this to run.
This might also change in the future.
But right now you need to add this.
So at this line with this version and rerun NPM install thereafter to download it and add it to your
project.
And with that polie full installed, you can go to Deepali Fields to file.
And there you should add these two lines import at web components, custom elements, slash custom elements,
Stutman and import.
Add Web components, custom elements, slash source slash native chhim.
This might also change in the future, but we read now Nita's to enable custom elements to ensure that
this works, that the native element, this custom elements package or the angular elements package
spits out that this element works.
Therefore this is needed.
So with that all added with the polie fields added in with the packages added, we can now try creating
a custom element.
And for Disney constructor of app component.
You want to do this in a place that runs early in your project.
I'll create a new element and I'll name it Alert Element.
The name is up to you all stored in a constant which is named like this and I will use create custom
element and now I need to import my custom element.
I want to do this on the alert element, so you should make sure that you add an import to that.
So import alert component from and now it's.
Alert component and there, of course, it should also be alert component elements to the constant,
but we pass in the component to create custom element.
Now create custom element also needs a second argument.
This argument is used to configure this element and there we need to pass the injector.
We're using now angular uses, dependency injection, as you know, and the injector is basically the
tool which DAST is injection.
And we provided to this custom element so that the element behind the scenes is able to connect itself
to our EPSO to say therefore we simply inject the injector.
So import injector from adding Lacourt and with it injected in that object you're passing to create
custom element, you add the injector kit and as a value, the injector you're injecting.
That's a lot of injection going on, I guess.
So with that, we created a custom element and designed it already is a native web component.
Now we can use the custom elements API and important.
This is not an angular feature.
This is a feature provided by JavaScript and called The Finder.
This allows us to register a custom web component.
And again, Elad element is just such a component.
It's the same as we could have built on our own.
So therefore, here we first of all define the tag by which you want to select it and just doesn't have
to be the same one as down here.
So we could also use my dash alert, for example, and then you pass in the element.
So not the component, but a third element.
So our custom element now with this, we can use that.
So down there I use my alert instead of Appleford because I changed tack.
And now if we save this.
It compiles and if we go to our application.
Nothing happens, but if we inspect the console, we actually got an error that we.
Well, that doesn't find a component factory.
Now, as I said, angular elements are only available in angular apps right now.
So what we have to do at this point of time is we have to add the entry components array to our app
module into components essentially as an array of components which you don't use with its selector or
wire routing, but where you want to tell Angular that you're eventually going to use it.
And this is exactly what will happen for the alert component.
We declare it that's important so that the ANGULAR can find it.
But we also need to tell Angular, Hey, you won't see me use a selector for this, you won't see me
loaded with routing, but eventually I will need it.
So please be prepared to load it when I need it.
And that is why we also have to load the angular component excuse me, the alert component, not our
custom element, but the angular component here into our entry components array.
And if we do that and we save the app will reload and we get at least a warning, not an error.
Sanitizing HTML stripped some content.
Now the custom element is in the end a bunch of JavaScript code and this is sanitized.
So this can't be rendered with inner HTML.
That's a security mechanism to avoid a crosseyed scripting attacks.
We want this mechanism, but in this case we know our content is safe and therefore we want to be able
to output it.
We can do this with the help of the DOM.
Sanitiser, you can also check this, it's the Tom Sanitiser object or class, which you need to import
from that angular platform browser and with it injected, you can wrap this custom HTML code, which
again behind the scenes will use a lot of JavaScript.
You can wrap this with DOM sanitiser bypass security trust HTML so that this HTML code and whatever
is connected to it is trusted.
So now with that, if we reload this, we do see our alert after a second.
But this time it's loaded as a custom element.
If we inspect it, we see our template here and we see the styles we apply to it.
But this now actually is loaded as native web component, still only usable in angular projects.
This will probably change in the future, though, but already useful for dynamic content like this.
Since we sanitize it, you should, of course, make sure that you know that this content is safe.
But with that, you got a really great tool to load content into your app and control it as an angular
component and do all the fun stuff you can do with components whilst getting it from another source,
which is not hard coded into your angular project code when you're compiling it.