Welcome to this video, Annual Monster, you went through the whole course and you learned a lot about
Angular, you should feel confident using its features and building Web apps with it.
Now, you learned about all its core features, some advanced features, how these features work together
and how you use them in a real application, which you didn't even deployed.
So these are all the building blocks you need to build amazing web applications with it.
Now, of course, really learning and mastering a framework means using it.
So use it both example projects, pick some Web pages you like and try to rebuild them maybe in easier
versions of them with angular dive into the individual features of angular, maybe even dive in the
source code of angler.
It's open source in the end, or have a look at the official documentation to dive deeper into some
specific use cases.
Also, there are some advanced courses and tutorials available.
For example, I myself do have some courses on Udemy which allow you to dive deeper or use Angerer in
conjunction with other things like ionic cuttable mobile applications or together with notebooks as
a backend.
These are all great next steps and whether that's a course by me, some other tutorial or in your own
example project, I'd be very interested in seeing what you build, what you do.
So definitely send me a message if you build some amazing project or anything like that.
All the best to you.
See you maybe in other courses and simply have a great time.