Now this course section is optional
because this course section will act
as an introduction to TypeScript, the programming language
which we are going to use for all
this entire course, since Angular embraces TypeScript.
But TypeScript in the end is just a programming language
extending Java script.
So if you know Java script, learning TypeScript
is rather straight forward, and you should be able
to learn those key TypeScript features by simply going
through the course step-by-step.
Nonetheless, in this course section
if you wanna quick introduction to TypeScript
or you wanna have a summary of the core features,
I will introduce you to what exactly TypeScript is
and why we might wanna use it, what its benefits are?
And we are going to explore some of its key features
and types, which we use all the time.
Now, that being said, we will not cover every single
TypeScript feature which you see in this course
since you will learn it step by step
when going through the course as mentioned.