- [Maximilian] So what is TypeScript
and why would you use it?
TypeScript is a so-called
"superset" to JavaScript.
It's a programming language
which builds up on JavaScript.
It extends JavaScript you could say,
and that is really important.
The core programming language
still, is JavaScript.
So the base JavaScript syntax you know,
how you write JavaScript code,
if statements, for loops,
objects, all that does not change.
But TypeScript then adds more features
to the JavaScript syntax.
And most importantly, it adds
static typing to JavaScript.
And that's also where the
name comes from, TypeScript.
It adds static typing to JavaScript,
because JavaScript on its own
is actually dynamically typed.
And what does this mean
and why is this useful?
For this, I prepared a
very simple example here,
which you find attached.
Now this is not an Angular project,
that's a standard, empty project basically - with
just an HTML file and a JavaScript file.
And I prepared this project to show you
why me might wanna use TypeScript and why
Angular, in the end, uses TypeScript therefore.
This is a standard JavaScript function
and a standard HTML file,
which has no actual content
but which imports this script file.
Now, if I open this file in the browser,
simply by copying the path here
and then opening that path in the browser,
if I reload this page and
open the developer tools,
I see seven here in the developer tools,
in the JavaScript console.
And I see seven here
because in this script file,
I define an "add" function,
and then I call this "add" function
and store the result in this constant
and then I log this constant.
So that's standard JavaScript,
nothing fancy here.
Now JavaScript has types.
JavaScript knows the concept of types.
For example, here, the two
values which I'm passing in,
are of type "number",
and that's something JavaScript knows
on its own, without TypeScript.
The important thing just is that,
JavaScript as I just mentioned,
is dynamically typed.
Which means that this function here,
does not expect any particular types.
It just knows that it will
receive two parameters,
and that's it.
So it's not statically typed,
the types for this function are
not announced ahead of time,
instead it just takes whatever it gets
and then tries to execute this code.
And that code happens
to work with numbers.
But this code also happens
to work with strings.
And hence, if I convert my
two numbers into strings here,
by wrapping them with quotes,
then I got two different types here,
I got two strings instead of numbers,
which are types JavaScript knows.
And if I change it like
this and saved as file,
if I reload, you see now we get 25 here,
because now the plus operator
does not add these two
arguments in a mathematical way,
but instead it concatenates two strings
because it receives two strings here.
And that shows why just
JavaScript is okay and great,
but why it might not always be best.
Why having static typing
could enhance your code
and prevent errors like this.
Now, of course you
might say, "Which error?
I can simply not call "add" like this,
I just make sure that I
always pass into numbers,
and it won't face this problem."
And that's true, but in a bigger project,
with lots of code files,
and potentially a lot of people
working on the code base,
you might sometimes call a function
or use some object in an unintended way.
And then you could run
into problems like this,
because nothing is warning you
that this is not how you
should use this function.
Nothing is telling you,
that this function
actually wants two numbers,
instead of two strings or any values.
And that's where TypeScript can help us.
Because with TypeScript,
and I'll show you this code
even though we haven't
installed TypeScript yet,
but I have it installed
on my system already,
and we will install it together
in the next lecture too.
But let me show you this first.
So with TypeScript, if I copy this code,
what we will be able to do is,
we can add type annotations here,
simply by adding a colon
after our parameter,
and then adding the type
which should be used for this parameter.
I'll do this for B as well.
And we'll also not just be
able to use type annotations
on function parameters,
but as you will see
throughout this module,
we can use types and many
other situations as well.
So now I am making it clear,
with TypeScript that here, I
actually want two parameters
which both should be of type number.
And hence, I already get
an error here in my IDE,
which tells me that this
argument of type string
is not assignable to a
parameter of type number,
pretty helpful.
And with that, I can catch such an error,
such an unintended use of this function
before I run and test my code.
And that of course allows us
to write better code in the end,
because we can avoid such errors
and we don't have to track them at runtime
but we see such errors right,
when we start writing code.
And that's why using TypeScript
could be worth a thought.