I wanna conclude this basic introduction
to TypeScript with a
slightly more advanced
yet very important TypeScript feature.
And that would be Generics.
Now this can be tricky
to wrap your head around,
but I'll try my best to explain
it such that it makes sense.
Let's say we have a function here,
which I'll name 'insertAtBeginning',
and this function takes
an array and the value
as parameters,
and the array should be
any array full of any kinds of values.
And the values should be any kind of value
because I don't care in this function
if it's an array full
of numbers or strings
or of personal objects.
Whatever it is, what I
wanna do in this function,
is I wanna create a new array,
for example by using the spread operator
and copying the existing array,
that's a standard modern
JavaScript feature
also supported by TypeScript.
And then in front of that old array,
I wanna insert the value.
And then I want to return
this new array here.
That could be a utility helper function,
which we create to have a function
which we can easily call to add a value
in an array without
changing the existing array.
So the advantage of this function could be
that the original array never changes,
but instead we're getting
a brand new array.
Now for this,
I could of course have a demo array with,
let's say free values,
and then I get my updated array
Where I call 'insertAtBeginning'
and I pass in the demo array.
And then a value of minus one let's say.
With that, I know that the updated array
will be this array with minus
one inserted at the beginning.
So this will give me minus
one, one, two, three.
And hence thereafter I might
wanna do things with that array
which I can do with an
array full of numbers.
But the problem is that updated array,
if I hover over it
is inferred to be of type any array.
So an array full of any kind of values.
TypeScript here doesn't pick up
that it's an array full of numbers.
Why, because here I have any, as a type
And I can't say that I only
wanna allow numbers here,
because what if I want to
use this utility function
with an array full of strings?
So we need any, but at the same time
that kind of removes all
kind of TypeScript support
we might be getting after
calling this function.
We're not getting any good
TypeScript support for updated
array thereafter, because
that is an inferred
to be an array full of any kind of objects
or any kind of values.
And that's not useful.
If I then for example, try
to access the first element
and called split here, which
I could call on a string.
I don't get an error here.
I would get a runtime error instead
because I can't call split on a number.
But again, TypeScript doesn't
know that the first value
in updated array is a number.
We know it as a developer,
but because of our type
definitions here, which we need,
TypeScript doesn't know it.
And to work around such problems,
we have this feature of Generics
and that's why I had does
lengthy introduction here
because it is important to understand why
this feature exists.
With this Generics feature,
we can convert this function
to a Generic function.
For this we use a special syntax here
after the function name,
in front of the parameter
list, we add angle brackets
and that's now not a
standard JavaScript feature
but really only a feature we can use here
since we're using TypeScript.
And in here we can define a
Generic type which will only
be available inside of this function.
Typically that's called T for type
but any identifier of your choices okay.
Now you can use this
type in your function,
including the parameter list.
And here I'm saying, I want
to use this for my array.
So my array will be
full of Ts and my value.
This should always be of type T.
But how does this help us?
Well like this set of codes
it's just very cryptic,
but now when we call this
function, now TypeScript actually
is able to understand that
it should look at the concrete
values of the arguments here.
And it understands that
this is an array of numbers
and this is just a number and
they are free to understand
that updated array will
be an array of numbers.
Because of this generic type
feature, because we're telling
TypeScript that the type
here is actually not any type
it's not any kind of value.
Instead, we tell it that
the type of this array and
of this value should be the same
just that this is an array,
but it's an array full of
the same types of values
as this single value has it.
And that's an important
piece of information.
Therefore, TypeScript is
able to look at the type
of demo array, which it knows.
It knows that this is a, an
array of numbers it's able
to infer this, and it looks at this type.
And then it knows that
logically, the array which gets
constructed here has
to be of the same type
as the input array.
It's able to infer this here.
And hence, it's able to infer
that what we get back here
has to be an array of numbers.
And if I would call,
'insertAtBeginning' here
with an array of strings
Like this, and I then
pass in a string here,
and I have my string array here,
TypeScript is also able
to infer this correctly
because again, it looks
at this type and this type
and it knows that the return
type is of the same value
as this type, as T input
array, enhance it again,
infers this correctly.
And therefore for the updated
array here where it knows
that it has to be an
array full of numbers.
It's now able to warn me
when I try to call split.
It tells me that this does
not exist on type number.
So that's just as important
feature of generics.
It's simply helps you write
functions in this case,
which are type safe yet flexible.
They are flexible.
They work with any type,
but then once a certain type
is used for that function, execution,
that type is locked in and known.
And that allows you to get the best
of both worlds, flexibility
and type safety.