Now, I got one last feature,
which I also wanna cover here.
And that would be classes and interfaces with TypeScript.
And we know classes from modern JavaScript already.
You can define blueprints for objects,
with help of the class keyword.
And again, this is a keyword supported in TypeScript
but it is actually also supported in modern JavaScript.
Now with classes, as I just said,
you can define blueprints for objects,
which you plan on instantiating.
For example, here I could create a person class,
or let's maybe create a student class,
and then you can add properties and methods to that class.
So for example here,
we could say that every student
should have a first name property,
and we can assign types to these properties to make it clear
that this first name property here should be a string.
And then we may also have a last name which is a string,
maybe an age, which is a number, and may be a courses array,
which is an array of strings.
Now, with that, we define such a blueprint.
Now we can also add a constructor function,
a constructor method, to this class
to then define the default method that will be called,
when we instantiate a new object based on that plus here.
And here, we could accept certain arguments
like first which is a string, last which is a string,
age which is a number,
and courses which is an array of strings.
And you see that I have the same argument names
as I have properties and therefore we could then
set first name equal to first,
this last name equal to last, this age equal to age,
and this course is equal to courses.
Like this.
And if we do that, we can define a new student down there
by instantiating this student class like this.
And then we can pass in these values for our parameters
to this constructor function.
By the way, of course your class
doesn't have to take any arguments in the constructor.
You could also set those properties in a different way,
for example, by assigning default values
or after you created an object with the dot notation.
But here I'll then pass in my values for these different
arguments
like this.
And with that, we create such a new object.
And on this student we can now use the dot notation
to access the different properties.
And if we had any methods besides the constructor function,
we could call those methods as well.
And speaking off that, we can add a method here.
Let's say the enrol method,
which allows us to enroll this student into a new course.
And therefore we could accept
the course name as argument here,
and then add it to courses,
like this.
And that's how you add a method to such a class.
This is the method shorthand notation.
You have the method name, then your parameter list,
and then the function body, so it's basically defined
like a regular JavaScript function,
with the important difference that we don't have
the function keyword.
We don't have that.
And that then is how we add a method.
And now we could call this method here,
and call enrol and pass in React
as another course this student is enrolled in,
and thereafter if you would access student.courses,
this would include both Angular and React.
That's how we can define a class.
Now, the special thing about TypeScript and classes
is that we can define all the properties
this class will have in advance
and sets the types for these different properties.
In standard JavaScript, we would not do that.
We would not have these property assignments.
Instead properties would be added
by just setting them inside of the constructor.
With TypeScript, you can define them ahead of time,
including their types.
And also very important, with TypeScript
you can control whether a property or a method
should be publicly accessible, or if it should be private.
Now, private properties and methods can only be used from
inside this class.
Public methods and properties can be accessed from outside
through this dot notation.
And therefore as you can tell by default,
all these properties and methods are public,
because by default I can access them all.
But we could say that courses should be private
by adding the private keyword
in front of this property definition.
And then we could of course add another method.
Let's say listCourses, and there we then return
this.courses.
Now this might be a bit redundant,
we don't really gain a lot by doing it like this.
We gain a bit more if we called slice,
because then at least we return a copy of courses
and make sure that if someone would push a new element
onto this array from outside this class,
the original array inside of the class
would not be altered, but in general
this is just an example.
Now with those adjustments made
I can't access student.courses here,
I get an error.
Instead I can call listCourses
if I wanna see all the courses this student is enrolled in.
And that stands simply another TypeScript feature
which you will also see in action for all of this course.
Now it's also worth pointing out
that it's a very common pattern in TypeScript
that you would define properties like this,
and you then assign values to those properties
through the constructor.
You don't necessarily do it in all the classes you create,
especially with Angular, you will see a lot of classes
where you don't do it,
but it's definitely also not uncommon.
And because it's so common
to assign values to those properties
which you defined before,
you can do it in one step with TypeScript.
Instead of defining your properties here
you can add these modifier, these accessor keywords
in front of your parameters in the constructor method,
and add public in front of all the parameters
that should be set up as public properties,
and add private in front of all the parameters
that should be set up as private properties.
Then, you don't assign values like this.
And I'll now change this to first name and last name here,
auto format this, and now this in the end
leads to the same result as we had it before.
So this is a shorthand notation
for defining certain properties of this class
and their types, and for also letting the user
assign values to those properties
when that class is instantiated.
So this code down there still works,
but now with that shorthand notation.
And that's this classes feature,
which is also part of TypeScript.