Now, another important feature,
kind of related to classes and objects in general
is the interfaces feature
and that's a feature which only exists in TypeScript,
not in vanilla JavaScript and any interface code,
which you write, which you'll see in a second,
will therefore not be compiled to JavaScript.
Now, what are interfaces?
In their most basic form,
interfaces are really just object type definitions.
So we could say that we have a Human object
in our application.
And we can define it with the interface keyword.
Then curly braces thereafter
and now here, between those curly braces,
we can define the structure,
the type of any Human object we wanna create.
So we could say a human should have a firstName,
which is a string.
And should maybe have an age, which is a number.
And then let's say every human should also have a method
to greet other humans.
And for this, we can add greet here
but now, very important,
we don't add the method definition,
we don't add the actual code
that goes into that method
but instead, just the type of that method,
which we can do like this, for example.
Now we're saying
that every human should have a greet method,
which actually is a method that takes no parameters
and returns nothing.
Now, we can use this interfaces as I just said
as a object type.
So if we have a new variable named max,
because I wanna store information about myself in there,
then I could make it clear
that this should be of type Human, like this.
And now if I wanna assign a value,
I'm not allowed to store a number.
I am allowed to store a object
but only an object
that has this structure.
And I now also get auto completion.
And I have to make it clear that there is a firstName,
an age and now I have to add a greet method as well.
And here we now have the actual code,
not the type definition.
And now this works
because this object, which has stored in max fulfills
the requirements set forth by that interface.
So we can use interfaces to define object types.
But we could also do this with the type keyword
to create an alias.
Like this, that would work as well.
So why do we have interfaces then
if we can do the same with the type keyword?
Well, for one, of course,
interfaces are simply an alternative
and you can use interfaces instead of the type keyword
when you wanna define object types
but they also have one other extra feature,
which the type keyword does not give you.
Interfaces can be implemented by classes
and when they are,
they force classes to have that structure defined
by the interface.
Now, this might sound very abstract
but this can be helpful if you're building an application
with multiple developers
and you wanna ensure that a certain class written
by another developer has a certain structure
because you for your part you're working on need
that class to have that structure.
You need that class to have a certain method, for example.
And it's the same for Angular.
Angular, as you will see in this course,
also has a couple of interfaces,
which we will use from time to time in this course,
which then force us to add certain features
to the classes we define.
And we will work with a lot of classes
when working with Angular.
And Angular gives us interfaces
that force us to add certain features to our classes
so that it then is able
to use these classes correctly internally.
And you'll see all of that in action throughout the course.
Now, I'll give you an example.
Let's say I add a new class here,
Instructor, and I wanna make sure that this class
has this shape
because someone else who's working
on the team needs that class to have that shape.
Then we can add the implements keyword
and implement our interface before we add the curly braces
to start defining the class.
And now because I'm implementing this interface,
I'm getting some red squiggly lines here
and I'm being forced to correctly implement this interface,
which means I have to add the firstName property
of type string here.
I have to add a age property of type number here.
And I have to add a greet method here.
And only if I add all of that,
no matter which exact code I then have
in that greet method
but only after I add the general structure here,
this error goes away
because I'm now correctly implementing this interface.
And that's another key part of interfaces.
They don't just act as object types,
instead, they also force us to set up a certain structure
for our classes.
And that's what we're taking advantage of here.
And that's what we'll also see in action
throughout this course.