Now to really conclude
this TypeScript introduction section now,
let's talk about configuring the TypeScript compiler.
You might recall that before when I executed
just npx typescript, I got this error here
that basically a TypeScript configuration file is missing
and that's why I had to target a specific TypeScript file
like this to then compile just this file.
Now, sometimes you want to compile all the TypeScript files
in your project in one go, and you also might want
to configure how the TypeScript compiler behaves.
And for this, you can add a TypeScript
compiler config file.
You can do this with npx tsc -- init.
What this does is it adds a tsconfig.json file,
though I will say, once we work with Angular,
we don't need to do that because the Angular project
get TypeScript configuration files out of the box,
and you should really only change them
if you know what you're doing.
But here we now got such a TypeScript compiler
configuration file.
And in there, we got lots of options, which we can set.
Now, one of the most important options
is the strict mode option here,
which by default is set to true.
When using strict mode, TypeScript,
as the name implies does very strict type checking.
And there are many things which it doesn't allow it,
like for example, values where it's not able
to infer the type.
You then have to explicitly set a type for those.
But that's just one example.
Now, in general, you can read through this config file
to understand these different settings.
And of course, I do talk about them
in way greater detail in my full TypeScript course.
As I said, with Angular projects,
we get a TypeScript file out of the box
and therefore, this is not really the focus here
because this default Angular TypeScript compiler file
will do the trick for us
and we don't really need to change them.
Nonetheless, this is how you can configure
the TypeScript compiler and feel free to dive
into these different options to play around with them.
But with that, we now got all those important
basics out of the way.
And now with that, you're definitely ready to dive
into Angular and TypeScript.